<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TaggedPDF-doc><x:xmpmeta xmlns:x="adobe:ns:meta/" x:xmptk="Adobe XMP Core 5.2-c001 63.139439, 2010/09/27-13:37:26        "><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"><rdf:Description rdf:about="" xmlns:pdfx="http://ns.adobe.com/pdfx/1.3/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xmp="http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/" xmlns:pdf="http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/"><pdfx:Format>xml</pdfx:Format>
<dc:creator><rdf:Bag><rdf:li>109502525</rdf:li>
</rdf:Bag>
</dc:creator>
<dc:title><rdf:Alt><rdf:li xml:lang="x-default">4_apple_1_72.pdf</rdf:li>
</rdf:Alt>
</dc:title>
<xmp:CreateDate>2023-03-14T13:28:13+08:00</xmp:CreateDate>
<xmp:ModifyDate>2023-03-14T13:28:13+08:00</xmp:ModifyDate>
<xmp:MetadataDate>2023-03-14T13:28:13+08:00</xmp:MetadataDate>
<pdf:Producer>Foxit PDF Editor - Foxit Software Inc.</pdf:Producer>
</rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
</x:xmpmeta>
<Part><Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_0.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Environmental</P>
<P>Social</P>
<P>Governance</P>
<P>Report</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report2</P>
<H1>Contents</H1>
<P>Introduction</P>
<L><LI>3Letter from Tim Cook</LI>
<LI>4Report highlights</LI>
<LI>6Our approach</LI>
<LI>8Our commitmentto transparency</LI>
<LI>9Advocating for change</LI>
<LI>10Our commitmentto human rights</LI>
</L>
<P>Environment</P>
<L><LI>13Our approach</LI>
<LI>13Climate change</LI>
<LI>18Resources</LI>
<LI>20Smarter chemistry</LI>
</L>
<P>Environmental</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<L><LI>23Our approach</LI>
<LI>23Inclusion and diversity</LI>
<LI>26Growth anddevelopment</LI>
<LI>27Benefits</LI>
<LI>28Compensation</LI>
<LI>29Engagement</LI>
<LI>30Workplace practicesand policies</LI>
<LI>33Health and safetyat Apple</LI>
</L>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<L><LI>37Our approach</LI>
<LI>40Labor and human rightsin the supply chain</LI>
<LI>43Health, safety,and wellness</LI>
<LI>44Responsible materialssourcing</LI>
<LI>45Education andprofessional development</LI>
<LI>46Environment</LI>
</L>
<P>Social</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<L><LI>48Our approach</LI>
<LI>48Privacy</LI>
<LI>50Accessibility</LI>
<LI>52Inclusive design</LI>
<LI>53Education</LI>
<LI>54Health</LI>
<LI>55Caring for customers</LI>
</L>
<P>Communities</P>
<L><LI>59Our approach</LI>
<LI>60Racial Equityand Justice Initiative</LI>
<LI>62Education</LI>
<LI>64Affordable housinginitiative</LI>
<LI>65Corporate donations</LI>
<LI>67Employee giving</LI>
<LI>68Job creation</LI>
</L>
<P>Governance</P>
<L><LI>70Corporate governance</LI>
<LI>71Ethics and compliance</LI>
<LI>72Tax payments</LI>
</L>
<P>Governance</P>
<P>Appendix</P>
<L><LI>74Awards and recognition</LI>
<LI>75United NationsSustainable DevelopmentGoals</LI>
<LI>77Stakeholder engagement</LI>
<LI>78ESG data summary</LI>
<LI>84About the report</LI>
<LI>85Endnotes</LI>
</L>
<P>ESG Index ↗︎</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report3</P>
<H1>At Apple, we believe the measure of any great innovation is thepositive impact it has on people’s lives. It’s why we work everyday to make our technology an even greater force for good.</H1>
<P>Today, our teams around the world infuse Apple’s deeply held values into everything we make. That work cantake many forms. But whether we’re protecting the right to privacy, designing technology that is accessible toall, or using more recycled material in our products than ever, we are always working to make a difference forthe people we serve and the planet we inhabit.</P>
<P>As a company, we know that our impact on people’s lives reaches beyond the technology we create. And weapply the same ethos of constant innovation and improvement to every aspect of our work — from building aninclusive company culture where everyone feels welcome to becoming carbon neutral across our global supplychain and the lifetime of our products by 2030.</P>
<P>At the heart of our efforts is a steadfast commitment to serving the communities we are a part of. We workwith teachers, advocates, and entrepreneurs from diverse backgrounds as part of our Racial Equity and JusticeInitiative. We help create opportunity in communities on the frontlines of climate change through the RestoreFund, which supports carbon removal and sustainable forestry. And we provide resources and training tothe next generation of innovators through the Apple Developer Academy and educational initiatives acrossthe globe.</P>
<P>In this report, we are pleased to share our progress, which is a product of collaboration with committedpartners worldwide. At Apple, we believe that the only way to effectively tackle global challenges is byworking together, and we are grateful to share this road with so many passionate leaders.</P>
<P>We’re engaged in this work because it’s right — and because we want to leave the world better than wefound it in everything we do. By leading with our values, we hope to be a ripple in the pond that inspiresa far greater change.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_2.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Tim Cook</P>
<P>CEO</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_1.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Tim Cook</P>
<P>CEO</P>
</Part>
<Part><Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_3.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_4.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_5.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H3>Introduction</H3>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report4</P>
<H1>Reporthighlights</H1>
<H2>At Apple, we’re demonstratingevery day that business can andshould be a force for good. Andwe’ve made important progressover the last year through ourEnvironmental, Social, andGovernance (ESG) initiatives.That would not be possiblewithout the innovation andcollaboration of teams acrossApple, and the people andorganizations we partner with.As we look ahead, we knowthere is more to be done. We’recommitted to continue to buildon our efforts and drive evengreater impact in the yearsto come.</H2>
<L><LI>*Pay equity at the intersections of race and ethnicity with genderwas achieved in 2022.</LI>
</L>
<P>**Leadership roles include managers at all levels of our company.</P>
<H2>Carbon neutral forcorporate emissions</H2>
<P>Since April 2020, we’ve achieved carbonneutrality for our corporate emissions bysourcing 100 percent renewable electricityfor Apple facilities, implementing energyefficiency initiatives, and securing carbonoffsets for remaining emissions.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 13</P>
<H2>Reduced overallemissions by 40%</H2>
<P>In fiscal year 2021, our environmentalinitiatives avoided over 23 million metrictons of emissions across all scopes, andwe reduced our carbon footprint by</P>
<P>40 percent compared with fiscal year2015. Efforts and initiatives that we’vebeen growing for years made this possible— like sourcing 100 percent renewableelectricity for our facilities, transitioningsuppliers to clean energy, and usinglow-carbon materials in products.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 13</P>
<H2>More than doubledrenewable energy inour supply chain</H2>
<P>As of March 2022, 213 suppliers havecommitted to renewable electricity forApple production, representing the majorityof Apple’s direct supplier spend. In fiscalyear 2021, Apple and its suppliers broughtonline over 10 megawatts of renewableenergy in our supply chain, doubling theamount from the prior year.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 16</P>
<H2>Continued tomaintain pay equity</H2>
<P>Since 2017, Apple has achieved andmaintained gender pay equity for ouremployees worldwide. In the U.S., we’vealso achieved pay equity with respect torace and ethnicity — as well as pay equityat the intersections of race and ethnicitywith gender.*</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 28</P>
<H2>Increased representationin leadership</H2>
<P>In calendar year 2021, 47% of openleadership** roles were filled by womenglobally, an increase of 10 percentagepoints since 2020, and we’ve had an 87%increase in women in leadership since2014. And in 2021, we hired more Black andHispanic/Latinx team members in the U.S.than ever before, with 13% open leadershiproles filled by Black candidates and 12%filled by Hispanic/Latinx candidates. Since2014, we’ve had an 84% increase in thenumber of Black employees and a 90%increase in the number of Hispanic/Latinxemployees in leadership in the U.S.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 24</P>
<H2>Protected privacy with AppTracking Transparency</H2>
<P>With iOS 14.5 in April 2021, we releasedApp Tracking Transparency for iPad andiPhone, requiring developers to obtaina user’s permission to track them acrossapps or websites owned by othercompanies for advertising purposes.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 49</P>
</Part>
<Part><Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_6.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_7.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report5</P>
<H1>Upholding thehighest standardsin our supply chain</H1>
<P>We hold ourselves and our suppliers tothe highest standards of labor and humanrights, health and safety, and environmentalstewardship. In fiscal year 2021, weconducted 1177 assessments, including291 smelter and refiner assessments,to verify that suppliers are meeting ourstrict requirements.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 38</P>
<H1>Responsibly sourcedprimary materials andsupported local communities</H1>
<P>We continue to source primary materialsresponsibly. 100 percent of the identifiedtin, tungsten, tantalum, and gold (3TG),cobalt, and lithium smelters and refinersin our supply chain have participated inindependent, third-party audits to assessand identify social, environmental, humanrights, and governance risks.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 44</P>
<H1>Expanded our investment ineducational opportunitiesthrough our Supplier EmployeeDevelopment Fund</H1>
<P>We announced our Supplier EmployeeDevelopment Fund, which will expand ourbest-in-class labor programs in our supplychain and establish a global Education Hubto scale the expansion of the technical andprofessional skills necessary for the jobs oftoday and tomorrow in our supply chain andsurrounding communities.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 45</P>
<H1>Committed an additional$55M to our Racial Justiceand Equity Initiative</H1>
<P>Building on our initial $100 millioncommitment in 2020, we announcedan additional $30 million commitmentin August 2021. The funding supportsefforts including the Global HSI EquityInnovation Hub, expanded learningopportunities for HBCUs, the first AppleEntrepreneur Camp for Hispanic/LatinxFounders and Developers, and funding fororganizations driving criminal justice reformand environmental justice. And in May2022, we committed $25 million to expandaccess to capital for community financialinstitutions supporting communities ofcolor in historically underserved marketsacross the U.S.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 60</P>
<H1>Expanded new featuresto support accessibility</H1>
<P>To celebrate Global Accessibility AwarenessDay 2022, we previewed upcoming softwarefeatures to offer users with disabilities newtools for navigation, health, communication,and more. Apple’s announcement includedDoor Detection, a cutting-edge navigationfeature for users who are blind or lowvision, Live Captions for the Deaf and hardof hearing community, and Apple WatchMirroring, which helps people with physicaland motor disabilities control Apple Watchremotely from their paired iPhone.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 52</P>
<H1>Further supportedinclusive design</H1>
<P>Across Apple we’ve continued our sustainedcommitment to making products moreinclusive. For example, we released newdiverse voices for Siri, and we’re taking stepsto advance equity in our cameras’ personrecognition features. We’ve also developedHuman Interface Guidelines to supportdevelopers in building inclusive apps.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 52</P>
<H1>Improved access toeducation for our schoolsand communities</H1>
<P>Our Community Education Initiativecontinued to grow, supporting andpartnering with 147 education institutionsand nonprofit organizations — including47 HBCUs — in over 500 different locationsacross 36 states in the U.S. and fourlocations across the UK since its launchin 2019.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 62</P>
<P>We launched Apple Learning Coach, afree professional learning program thattrains instructional coaches, digital learningspecialists, and other coaching educatorsto help teachers effectively use Appletechnology in the classroom.</P>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 54</P>
<H1>Marked 10 years of ourEmployee Giving program</H1>
<P>In 2021, Apple’s Employee Giving programcelebrated its 10th anniversary, havingraised nearly $725 million for 39,000organizations worldwide — with over$120 million distributed to organizationsaround the globe in 2021 alone. The fundsraised through Apple’s Employee Givingprogram include the work of 68,000employees who have logged almost</P>
<L><LI>2 million volunteer hours.</LI>
</L>
<P>-––&gt;Continue reading on page 67</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report6</P>
<H1>Our approach</H1>
<H3>Our values flow through the technology we make, the waywe make it, and how we care for people and the planet weshare. These values — accessibility, education, environment,inclusion and diversity, privacy, and supplier responsibility— are central to our ESG approach. And we go further toaddress a comprehensive set of critical issues that matterto our company and to our stakeholders.</H3>
<P>From our commitment to human rights to our 2030 environmental goals, ESGtopics are deeply interconnected. We can make the biggest impact only whenwe understand how these issues relate to one another.</P>
<P>ESG priorities are managed across Apple, and our senior leaders play an importantrole in integrating ESG into functions across the company. We listen to stakeholders— including our people, suppliers, communities, shareholders, and other externalgroups — to understand the issues they care about. And we measure our ESGprogress across our business so that we can work toward being more transparentwith each year.</P>
<P>Above all, we’re always working to leave the world better than we found it,and to create powerful tools that empower others to do the same.</P>
<H2>Environment</H2>
<P>We’ve been carbon neutral for our ownoperations since 2020, including business traveland employee commute, and are progressingtoward an urgent goal to be carbon neutralacross our entire business — including the fulllife cycle of our products — by 2030. We’reon an ambitious journey to one day make ourproducts using only recycled or renewablematerials. We design our products to be safe foranyone who assembles, uses, or recycles them— and to be better for the environment. At thesame time, we’re partnering with communitiesand local leaders and working to make sure ourenvironmental efforts are also a force for equityand justice.</P>
<P>Climate change</P>
<P>Resources</P>
<P>Smarter chemistry</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_8.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Since 2018, Apple sources all of the electricity for its facilities from100 percent renewable energy. The Montague Wind Farm in Oregonis one of Apple’s largest projects at 200 megawatts and powersApple’s Prineville data center.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report7</P>
<H1>Social</H1>
<H1>Governance</H1>
<P>At Apple, we work every day to put peoplefirst — by empowering them with accessibletechnology, being a force for equity andopportunity, creating an inclusive anddiverse work environment, and respectingthe human rights of everyone whose liveswe touch.</P>
<P>Human rights</P>
<H2>Our People</H2>
<P>We’re committed to inclusion and diversityfor our team and in our world. And we haveprograms and benefits to support thedevelopment of our team members. Wecontinue to prioritize the health and safetyof our teams, customers, supplieremployees, and communities.</P>
<P>Inclusion and diversityGrowth and developmentEngagementBenefits and compensationWorkplace practices and policiesHealth and safety</P>
<H2>Suppliers</H2>
<P>We hold ourselves and our suppliers to thehighest standards of labor and human rights,health and safety, environmental protections,and ethics. We’re working every day tosupport more people in our supply chainand surrounding communities. And we’recollaborating with others to promote bestpractices and scale innovative solutions.</P>
<P>Labor and human rights in the supply chain</P>
<P>Health, safety, and wellness</P>
<P>Responsible materials sourcing</P>
<P>Education and professional development</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<H2>Customers</H2>
<P>We’re focused on infusing our values into ourproducts — engineering privacy and securityinto everything we make and designing ourproducts and services to be accessible toand inclusive of the widest range of users.We also find innovative ways to supportpeople’s education, health, and a range ofhuman rights topics, with a specific focus oncommunities too often denied opportunities.</P>
<P>Privacy</P>
<P>Accessibility</P>
<P>Inclusive design</P>
<P>Education</P>
<P>Health</P>
<P>Caring for customers</P>
<H2>Communities</H2>
<P>We’re accelerating social change bysupporting communities and organizationsthat are addressing society’s toughestproblems, including a focus on communitiesof color. Some of our key initiatives includethe Racial Equity and Justice Initiative (REJI),Community Education Initiative, DeveloperAcademies, Entrepreneur Camp, andaffordable housing initiative. Our corporatedonations support nonprofits and otherorganizations with which we partner, andwe empower employees to contribute tothe causes they care about through ourEmployee Giving program.</P>
<P>Racial Equity and Justice InitiativeEducation</P>
<P>Affordable housingCorporate donationsEmployee givingJob creation</P>
<P>We embed transparency and accountability atevery level of our company. Apple’s board andgovernance structure helps foster principledactions, informed and effective decision-making, and appropriate monitoring of ourcompliance and performance. We’re committedto conducting business ethically, honestly, and incompliance with applicable laws and regulations.</P>
<P>Corporate governance</P>
<P>Ethics and compliance</P>
<P>Tax payments</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_9.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple has over 165,000 team members who work in corporateoffices and Apple Stores around the world.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report8</P>
<H1>Our commitment to transparency</H1>
<H3>In addition to this report,we’ve been reporting on ESGtopics for many years. Seeour topic-specific reports andwebsites for more informationon each issue.</H3>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_15.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>Environment</H2>
<P>Environmental</P>
<P>Progress</P>
<P>Report</P>
<P>Covering fiscal year 2021</P>
<P>Environmental Progress Report (24.5Mb PDF)Environment website</P>
<P>CDP</P>
<H2>Our people, customers,and communities</H2>
<P>Inclusion &amp; Diversity websiteBenefits website</P>
<P>Privacy website</P>
<P>Transparency ReportAccessibility websiteEducation website</P>
<P>Racial Equity and Justice website</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_10.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_11.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_12.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_13.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_14.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>Suppliers</H2>
<P>People andEnvironment inOur Supply Chain</P>
<P>2022 Annual Progress Report</P>
<P>People and Environment inOur Supply Chain (22.5Mb PDF)Supplier Responsibility websiteEfforts to Combat Human Traffickingand Slavery</P>
<P>Conflict Minerals Report</P>
<H2>Governance</H2>
<P>Human Rights Policy</P>
<P>2022 Proxy StatementForm 10-K</P>
<P>Ethics &amp; Compliance website</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_16.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Our ESG Indexdemonstrates how all of ourreports and public disclosures map to leadingframeworks, including the SustainabilityAccounting Standards Board (SASB), GlobalReporting Initiative (GRI), and Task Force onClimate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD).</P>
<P>Apple’sNewsroomalso provides the latestupdates regarding our programs, initiatives,and offerings mentioned throughout this report.</P>
<P>ESG Index</P>
<P>ESG Index (2.6Mb PDF)</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report9</P>
<H1>Advocating for change</H1>
<P>We’re committed to helpingaddress shared global challenges.That’s why we engage with publicpolicy and the legal system whenwe identify an opportunity tosupport the rights and well-beingof our people, customers,communities, and planet.</P>
<H2>Advocating for strong climate policies</H2>
<P>Apple’s climate policy advocacy centers onseveral principles, each of which governApple’s public policy positions on climate:Set strong targets based on science; disclosecomprehensive emissions; create sector-specific policies; and support a greeneconomy for all.</P>
<P>In April 2021, we made a public statementcalling for mandatory disclosures of globalgreenhouse gases across all emissions scopes.The statement also focused the discussionwithin industry and government towardgreater transparency and increased attentionby regulators.</P>
<P>In May 2021, Apple also became one of the firstcompanies to voice support for the enactmentof the Clean Energy Standard (CES) that woulddecarbonize the power grid by 2035. And atthe 26th UN Climate Change Conference ofthe Parties (COP26) in Glasgow, Scotland,in 2021, Apple called for bold governmentaction on climate change, joining several newinitiatives, including the First Movers Coalition,the Forest Investor Club, and the Clean EnergyDemand Initiative.</P>
<P>We also advocate for country-specific measuresthat motivate climate action. For example,we’ve called for enhanced climate ambitionand renewable energy deployment in Japan’sBasic Energy Plan and Nationally DeterminedContribution (Japan’s plan to reduce emissionsin furtherance of the Paris Agreement), and for</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_17.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple’s Vice President of Environment, Policy and Social Initiatives, Lisa Jackson, alongside President Joe Bidenand other leaders from around the world at the 2021 United Nations Climate Change Conference. Photo credit:World Economic Forum.</P>
<P>decarbonization policies to prioritize supportfor new technologies that can fully account forreducing emissions across their life cycle.</P>
<H2>Speaking out for rights</H2>
<P>We believe that every person should be treatedwith dignity and respect, and we speak outpublicly in ways that reflect our values. Asjust one recent example, we’ve continuedour public support for LGBTQ+ equality byworking with The Human Rights Campaignand other organizations to support LGBTQ+equality protections and oppose discriminatoryproposals. This includes legislative advocacyat the federal and state levels, and workingwith coalitions of businesses to stand againstwhat we believe to be harmful and divisivelegislation that threatens individuals, families,and communities. Most recently, that includedsending a letter to Texas leadership opposinglaws that discriminate against the LGBTQ+community.Read morehere.</P>
<H2>Protecting our customers</H2>
<P>In the U.S., the legal system is one avenuethrough which Apple can take action to supportour values. For example, in January 2022,Apple, along with other leading companies,filed anamicus briefin support of the EPA’sauthority to regulate greenhouse gas emissionsbecause that authority “is critical to combattingclimate change.”</P>
<P>In November 2021, Apple filed a lawsuit againstNSO Group and its parent company to hold itaccountable for the surveillance and targetingof Apple users. The complaint provides newinformation on how NSO Group infected victims’devices with its Pegasus spyware. To preventfurther abuse and harm to its users, Apple isseeking a permanent injunction to ban NSOGroup from using any Apple software, services,or devices.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report10</P>
<H1>Our commitment to human rights</H1>
<P>Our commitment begins withtreating everyone with dignityand respect. But it doesn’t endthere. We believe in the powerof technology to empower andconnect people around the world— and that business can andshould be a force for good.</P>
<H2>Apple’s Human Rights Policy</H2>
<P>OurHuman Rights Policygoverns how we treateveryone, including our customers, employees,business partners, and people across oursupply chain. We’re deeply committed torespecting internationally recognized humanrights in our business operations, as set outin the United Nations (UN) International Bill ofHuman Rights and the International LabourOrganization’s (ILO) Declaration on FundamentalPrinciples and Rights at Work. Our approach isbased on the UN Guiding Principles on Businessand Human Rights (UNGPs).</P>
<P>We conduct human rights due diligence toidentify risks and work to mitigate them. Wealso seek to remedy adverse impacts, trackand measure our progress, and report ourfindings. Our board of directors adopted thepolicy and is responsible for overseeing andperiodically reviewing it. Apple’s Senior VicePresident and General Counsel is responsiblefor its implementation, and reports to theBoard and its committees on our progress andsignificant issues.</P>
<H2>Embedding respect for human rights</H2>
<P>We’ve worked to embed respect for humanrights across our company — in the technologywe make, the way we make it, and how we treatpeople. A number of teams are responsiblefor carrying out human rights due diligence,including the Privacy, Corporate, andCompliance teams within Apple’s Legal andGlobal Security organization, as well as Apple’sEnvironment and Supply Chain Innovation (ESCI)team within Worldwide Operations.</P>
<H2>Our commitment to civil rights</H2>
<P>We are deeply committed to building a morejust and inclusive world and are moving forwardwith plans to conduct a civil rights audit.</P>
<H2>Identifying and managingsalient human rights risks</H2>
<P>Identifying human rights risks is the first stepto addressing those risks through improvementsto our policies and management systems. Wework to align our efforts with the business andhuman rights due diligence process set forthin the UNGPs to identify, mitigate, prevent,and remedy human rights risks.</P>
<P>We identify salient human rights risks throughinternal risk assessments and external industry-level third-party audits, as well as through thechannels we maintain with rights holders andother stakeholders, including investors, humanrights and labor experts, governments, andinternational bodies such as the UN.</P>
<P>In addition to our own internal monitoring,we consider reports identifying potential risksfrom external sources, including internationalorganizations, policy makers, shareholders, civilsociety organizations, news outlets, customers,individuals in the supply chain or supply chaincommunities, whistleblower mechanisms,and third-party hotlines. Reports also comethrough the reporting mechanisms we makeavailable directly to all supplier employees,Apple employees, and the general public. Thesereports can come to us in any language andcan be anonymous.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>CommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur People</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report11</P>
<P>Based on this due diligence, examplesof human rights issues of particular focusat Apple include:</P>
<L><LI>•Privacy, freedom of expression, and accessto information risks</LI>
<LI>•Discrimination risks in workforce managementand in product and services development</LI>
<LI>•Labor and human rights risks in thesupply chain</LI>
</L>
<P>Across Apple, teams such as ESCI, EPSI,People, Privacy, and others work to avoid,prevent, mitigate — and where appropriate,remediate — human rights issues and impactsacross Apple’s business, including through ourcommitments to:</P>
<L><LI>•Respecting the rights to privacy, freedomof expression, and access to information</LI>
<LI>•Promoting diversity, equity, and inclusion,including in our workforce, leadership,product and services development, andour industry</LI>
<LI>•Respecting labor and human rights in oursupply chain by working closely with suppliersso that people in our supply chain are treatedwith dignity and respect</LI>
</L>
<P>•Respecting human rights through our effortsto protect the planet in how we design,build, and recycle our products, and throughresponsible sourcing and use of materialsand natural resources</P>
<H1>Tracking progress</H1>
<P>We’re committed to continually assessing ourprogress and incorporating what we learn</P>
<P>into our work. We track and measure ourperformance across a range of areas, and applythe lessons we learn to continually improve.We publicly report detailed information on ourapproach and our performance in the reports,websites, and other disclosures listed onpage 8, as well as within this ESG Report:</P>
<P>Inclusion anddiversity</P>
<P>Workplacepractices</P>
<P>Health andsafetyLabor and humanrightsin the supplychain</P>
<P>PrivacyAccessibilityInclusivedesign</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_18.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>The rainbow arches at Apple Park in Cupertino, California are a nod to Apple’s originallogo and an expression of our inclusive values.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOur PeopleIntroductionEnvironment</P>
<H1>A planet-size plan.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report12</P>
<H2>Environment</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Our approachClimate changeResourcesSmarter chemistry</P>
<P>13</P>
<P>13</P>
<P>18</P>
<P>20</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report13</P>
<P>At Apple, we’re acting with urgency to protect our planet’s limited resources and to bea leader in the fight against climate change. Since 2020, we’ve been carbon neutral forour worldwide operations, and by 2030, we plan to expand that progress to our entiresupply chain and the lifetime use of our products. And today, nearly 20 percent of thematerials in our products were made from recycled content — a number we’re workingto increase.</P>
<P>Across our environmental work, we’re also committed to being a force for equity. We’reworking with communities on the frontlines of climate change and the next generationof diverse entrepreneurs to create shared opportunity and to build a more just world.</P>
<H1>Our approach</H1>
<P>The environmental challenges we face todayare significant, and we’re responding withurgency and dedication. We approach our workby focusing on fundamental questions. Whatmatters most? And where can we make thegreatest impact? These questions guide ourwork across our strategic focus areas of climatechange, resources, and smarter chemistry</P>
<P>— and inform our goals in how we can bestachieve change.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_19.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Our2022 Environmental Progress Reportprovides a detailed overview of our work andhow we’re progressing toward our goals.</P>
<P>We know we’re not alone in working to reduceour environmental footprint. So we’re engagingwith others to support our efforts and findopportunities to lift local communities alongthe way.</P>
<P>Setting ambitious goals is essential to ourapproach — to drive the innovation andcollaboration that makes change possibleand to be transparent and accountable toour progress.</P>
<P>Our work is led by Lisa Jackson, Apple’s VicePresident of Environment, Policy and SocialInitiatives, reporting directly to CEO TimCook. The Environment, Policy and SocialInitiatives team works with other teams acrossApple to set strategy, engage stakeholders,and communicate progress. Our integratedapproach means that decisions about theenvironment are reviewed and supportedat the highest levels of the company.</P>
<H1>Climate change</H1>
<P>As a global business, we believe it is ourresponsibility to take strong, decisive, andinclusive steps to mitigate our climate impact.We’ve committed to achieving carbon neutrality— reducing emissions 75 percent comparedwith fiscal year 2015 and balancing the residualemissions with carbon removal — across thelife cycle of all of our products by 2030.1Andthe Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi) hasvalidated an emissions reduction target for Applederived from this goal.2It’s an ambitious plan withplenty of challenges ahead. But we’re alreadywell on our way, having cut carbon emissionsacross our value chain by 40 percent sincefiscal year 2015.</P>
<P>Our work began years ago, making the transitionto sourcing 100 percent renewable electricityat our offices, retail stores, and data centers,</P>
<P>which we achieved in 2018. And in 2020, wereached the milestone of being carbon neutralfor our corporate operations, including directemissions as well as business travel andemployee commute.</P>
<P>Our 10-year Climate Roadmap is addressingApple’s carbon footprint through five pillars:</P>
<P>Low-carbon design:We will design productsand manufacturing processes to be lesscarbon-intensive through thoughtful materialselection, increased material efficiency, andgreater product energy efficiency.</P>
<P>Energy efficiency:We will increase energyefficiency at our facilities and in our supplychain by finding opportunities, such asretrofitting, to reduce energy use.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report14</P>
<H1>40%</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_20.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<TOC><TOCI>decrease in emissions across ourentire value chain since 2015</TOCI>
</TOC>
<H1>100%</H1>
<P>renewable energy sourced for allApple facilities</P>
<H1>213</H1>
<P>suppliers committed to</P>
<P>100 percent renewable electricityfor Apple production</P>
<H1>$4.7B</H1>
<P>issued in green bonds to model howbusinesses can drive investmentsto reduce global emissions. In ourlatestGreen Bond Impact Report,we share progress on the projectsfunded in fiscal year 2021.</P>
<P>Renewable electricity:We will continue tosource 100 percent renewable electricity forour facilities, and transition our entire supplychain to 100 percent clean, renewable sourcesof electricity.</P>
<P>Direct emissions abatement:We willreduce direct greenhouse gas emissions inour facilities and our supply chain throughprocess innovation, emissions abatement, andthe use of non-fossil-based low-carbon fuels.</P>
<P>Carbon removal:Working in parallel withour emissions reduction efforts, we will scaleup investments in carbon removal projects,including nature-based solutions that protectand restore ecosystems around the world.</P>
<H2>Low-carbon design</H2>
<P>To reduce the carbon footprint of our products,we’re increasing efficiency and transitioningto materials from recycled sources and thosemade using low-carbon energy. In 2021, wecontinued to improve the carbon efficiency ofthe integrated circuits we use in our products— components we’ve prioritized because theyare carbon-intensive. For example, switchingto the Apple M1 chip for the 13-inch MacBookPro reduced the energy needed to manufactureand use the device, driving down the product’scarbon footprint by over 8 percent.</P>
<P>We’ve continued to expand our use of</P>
<P>100 percent recycled aluminum in the enclosuresof a number of products. All iPad models in ourlineup now use 100 percent recycled aluminumin their enclosures — joining Apple WatchSeries 7, Apple Watch SE, MacBook Air, Macmini, and the 14-inch and 16-inch MacBook Prodevices. For products released in 2021 that hadenclosures made with primary aluminum, we</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_21.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>To minimize the carbon footprint of our products, we seek to create less waste in the processing of materials,reduce machining time and the associated energy used, more efficiently transform material into the shapeswe need, and maximize recovery and reprocessing of manufacturing scrap.</P>
<P>prioritized the use of aluminum smelted usinglow-carbon sources of electricity rather thanfossil fuels — for a lower carbon impact. Thesechanges alone have decreased the carbonemissions associated with our use of aluminumby 68 percent since 2015.</P>
<P>Product energy use accounts for 22 percentof our gross carbon footprint — and has animpact on the individual energy use of eachof our customers. By addressing this in theearliest phases of design, we’ve cut the productenergy use across all major product lines bymore than 70 percent since 2008 throughenergy efficiency improvements.3In fiscalyear 2021, over 99 percent of Apple’s eligibleproducts, by revenue, received an ENERGYSTAR rating for superior energy efficiency.4And over 99 percent of Apple’s eligibleproducts, by revenue, met the requirementsfor EPEAT registration.5</P>
<H2>Energy efficiency</H2>
<P>We’re focused on using less energy acrossour operations, beginning with how we design,operate, and maintain our facilities. And wecontinue these same efforts into our supplychain, which benefits the communities whereour suppliers operate. Drawing less energy fromelectrical grids — many of which still rely heavilyon fossil fuels — helps reduce local air pollutionand improve air quality for nearby communities.</P>
<P>The emissions from manufacturing our productsaccount for about 70 percent of Apple’s grosscarbon footprint. We launched our Supplier EnergyEfficiency Program in 2015 with the goal of helpingsuppliers optimize their facilities and operationsto use as little energy as possible. We provideguidance designed to help suppliers uncoveropportunities for energy efficiency. Suppliers inour Supplier Energy Efficiency Program avoidedmore than 1,150,000 annualized metric tons ofsupply chain carbon emissions in fiscal year 2021.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report15</P>
<H1>Apple’scomprehensivecarbon footprint</H1>
<P>This past year we intensified our efforts to reduce Apple’semissions. In fiscal year 2021, we avoided over 23 millionmetric tons of emissions across all scopes. Initiatives thatwe’ve been growing for years — like sourcing 100 percentrenewable electricity for our facilities, transitioning suppliersto clean energy, and using low-carbon materials in products— yielded indisputable results.</P>
<P>Thanks to this work, we’ve begun to decouple businessgrowth from emissions: While our revenue grew 33 percent,our emissions grew by less than 5 percent. To mitigate thisincrease in emissions, we applied an additional 0.6 milliontons of renewable energy credits (RECs) and 0.5 millionmetric tons of carbon offsets to proportionally coverelectricity use and direct emissions, respectively, across ourvalue chain. This represents a short-term bridging solutionas we grow our carbon reduction programs to meet thescale of the challenge.</P>
<P>Corporate footprint</P>
<P>Product footprint</P>
<L><LI>22.5 million metric tons</LI>
</L>
<H2>net carbon emissions**</H2>
<P>FY21RECpurchase:FY21RECpurchase:</P>
<P>0.4 million metric tons avoided</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_22.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Supplierenergyefficiency:Supplierenergyefficiency:</P>
<P>1.1 million metric tons avoided</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_23.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Gross emissions</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_24.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_25.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Avoided emissions</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_26.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Emissions offset</P>
<P>Low-carbonmaterials*:Low-carbonmaterials*:</P>
<P>7.3 million metric tons avoided</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_27.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Suppliercleanenergy:Suppliercleanenergy:</P>
<P>13.9 million metric tons avoided</P>
<P>UseofrenewableUseofrenewableelectricity:electricity:</P>
<P>1.0 million metrictons avoided</P>
<P>FY21RECpurchase:FY21RECpurchase:</P>
<P>0.2 million metric tons avoided</P>
<P>Productenergyefficiency:Productenergyefficiency:</P>
<P>0.2 million metric tons avoided</P>
<P>LoadreductionandLoadreductionandmodeswitching:modeswitching:</P>
<P>0.2 million metrictonsavoidedtonsavoided</P>
<P>Gross emissions</P>
<P>CorporateenergyCorporateenergyefficiency:efficiency:</P>
<P>0.06 million metrictons avoided</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_28.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_29.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Offsets</P>
<P>Emissions categories(% of gross emissions)</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_30.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_31.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_32.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_33.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>0.02%</P>
<TOC><TOCI>Direct emissions(Scope 1)</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>0%</P>
<TOC><TOCI>Electricity(Scope 2)</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>0.5%</P>
<P>Business traveland commute(Scope 3)</P>
<P>70%</P>
<P>Productmanufacturing(Scope 3)</P>
<P>22%</P>
<TOC><TOCI>Product use(Scope 3)</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>8%</P>
<TOC><TOCI>Product transport(Scope 3)</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>0.3%</P>
<P>End-of-life productprocessing(Scope 3)</P>
<L><LI>*Low-carbon materials represents emissions savings from transitioning to recycled materials in our products, or use of low-carbon aluminum, as described onpage18.</LI>
</L>
<P>**Net carbon emissions represents our total gross footprint minus carbon offsets applied to each category. Percentages shown for each emissions category represent the share of Apple’s gross footprint. Totals add up to more than 100 percent, due to rounding.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report16</P>
<H1>Providing access to clean energy in South Africa</H1>
<P>Even a few years ago, not everyone in one community in South Africa had electricityat home. Many people had been using battery-powered lanterns because upfront costsand other challenges put connecting to the grid out of reach. As we worked with ourpartners to identify new renewable energy projects for our Power for Impact program,we saw exciting potential in this community.</P>
<P>Our partner on the ground, DC GO, a solar energy provider based in Johannesburg,got to work meeting members of the community and learning more about their needs.Ultimately, DC GO developed a pay-as-you-go model that brought solar energy to 3500homes that previously lacked access. This was possible only because of the way theybuilt relationships with community members and worked with Apple to price the solutionin line with what people were already spending on batteries for their lanterns.</P>
<P>In addition, DC GO hired and trained local people for jobs in sales, maintenance,and other roles that not only created local jobs but also helped to make sure the project— and the community’s access to electricity — would be sustainable over time.</P>
<P>This is just one example of how the Power for Impact program is working to benefitcommunities, our company, and the environment at the same time. Learn moreon pages 22 and 27 of ourEnvironmental Progress Report.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_34.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>With access to electricity in their homes, kids can now do homeworkat night and families can cook meals indoors.</P>
<H1>Renewable electricity</H1>
<P>Our retail stores, data centers, and officesaround the world currently source 100 percentrenewable electricity. We’ve focused ourefforts to source renewables around severalkey pillars: creating new renewable energyprojects, undertaking projects that deliver clearbenefits to local communities, and supportingrenewable energy innovations. About 1.5gigawatts of Apple-created renewableelectricity projects account for over 90 percentof the renewable electricity our facilities use.</P>
<P>We continue to experience tremendousprogress toward our goal of transitioning ourmanufacturing supply chain to 100 percentrenewable electricity by 2030. As of March2022, 213 manufacturing partners in 25countries have committed to 100 percentrenewable energy for Apple production.</P>
<P>Over 70 percent of companies on Apple’sSupplier List — those suppliers that makeup 98 percent of Apple’s direct spend formaterials, manufacturing, and assembly ofour products worldwide — have committed to100 percent renewable electricity. In addition,many other smaller suppliers have also madethese commitments.</P>
<H1>Direct emissions abatement</H1>
<P>To address the non-electricity emissionsassociated with our materials andmanufacturing processes, we seektechnological solutions through emissionsabatement or switching to low-carbon fueloptions. For example, we partnered withaluminum companies and the governmentsof Canada and Quebec to help fund researchand development for ELYSIS, a technology thateliminates direct greenhouse gas emissionsfrom aluminum smelting.</P>
<P>Many components essential to products likeours, including integrated circuit chips anddisplay panels, currently rely on manufacturingprocesses that use fluorinated gases, whichhave high global warming potential. We’repartnering closely with key manufacturersto prevent these gases from being</P>
<P>released into the atmosphere by optimizingmanufacturing processes and deployingabatement technologies.</P>
<P>To address emissions from shipping productsto our customers, we’re shifting wheneverpossible toward less carbon-intensive shippingmodes, such as rail and ocean. And we’reseeking out technical innovations, includingalternative fuels and electric vehicles. In fiscalyear 2021, Apple avoided 180,000 metric tonsof CO2e by shifting the mode of transport and</P>
<P>reducing product weight through the removalof the power adapter from the box ofiPhone devices.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report17</P>
<H1>Climate scenario analysis</H1>
<P>In 2020, we conducted a climate scenario analysis to help us better understand the potential physical andtransition effects of climate change. To align with the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures(TCFD) recommendations, we considered a range of future scenarios, including a scenario below 2°C.And we assessed geographies around the world to capture both corporate and supplier activities. Theanalysis highlighted how our renewable energy program and carbon neutrality goals could contribute to ourcorporate resiliency. It also provided environmental data that we considered in developing business strategies,including considerations around supply chain diversification, as well as safeguarding our global assets.</P>
<P>We’re committed to managing regulatory, reputational, and market risks related to climate change.For more information on these climate-related risks and Apple’s governance of these risks, read our2021 CDP submission (PDF).</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_35.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>Carbon removal</H1>
<P>To address the emissions we can’t yet avoid,we’re are investing in carbon removal projects.In addition to removing carbon, nature-basedcarbon removal projects also offer importantecological and social benefits, such as preservingbiodiversity and enhancing the resilience ofecosystems, while often providing economicdevelopment opportunities for local communities.</P>
<P>We partnered with Conservation Internationaland Goldman Sachs to launch the innovativeRestore Fund, which seeks to blend responsibleforestry practices with carbon removal: We’reworking with forestry managers to createsustainably managed forests that optimize forboth carbon and wood production, creatingrevenue from timber, and generating high-quality carbon credits. Apple will invest up to$200 million in projects that aim to removecarbon from the atmosphere and store it, allwhile meeting clear social and environmentalimpact criteria and offering a financial return.In its pilot phase, the Restore Fund has a goalof removing at least 1 million metric tons ofcarbon dioxide per year.</P>
<P>As the projects in the Restore Fund comeonline, we’re also working to address difficult-to-avoid emissions in the short term. In fiscalyear 2021, 167,000 metric tons of carboncredits were retired from theChyulu Hillsproject in Kenya to maintain carbon neutralityfor our corporate emissions in fiscal year2021. And we purchased carbon credits fromtwo additional projects to offset a total of500,000 metric tons of direct emissions acrossour value chain:a REDD+ coastal conservationproject in Guatemalaanda reforestation projectin Guizhou Province of China. These projectsare all certified to the VCS and CCB standards.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_36.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_37.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>For more information on our efforts to combatclimate change and reach our 2030 carbonneutral goal, read our2022 EnvironmentalProgress Report.</P>
<P>As the Restore Fund projects come online, we’ve partnered with Conservation International todevelop and invest in nature-based carbon removal projects. This includes a project to protectand restore 27,000 acres of mangrove forests in Colombia.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report18</P>
<H3>Welcoming the first class of the Impact Accelerator</H3>
<P>Last year, we welcomed the first class to our Impact Accelerator, a program for Black-,Hispanic/Latinx-, and Indigenous-owned businesses headquartered in the United Statesthat share our focus on innovation and our commitment to the environment. Part of Apple’sRacial Equity and Justice Initiative (seepage 60), the Accelerator aims to help combatsystemic barriers to opportunity, while also advancing innovative solutions for communitiesmost impacted by climate change.</P>
<P>We selected our first class of 15 businesses on the cutting edge of green technology andclean energy to begin the program in August 2021. The three-month program included livevirtual sessions, online courses on supply chain management, supplier diversity, financialand legal subjects, as well as one-on-one mentorship with an Apple expert on topics fromrenewable energy to responsible sourcing.</P>
<P>The goal of the Impact Accelerator is to better position the participating companies forgrowth, to improve their abilities to take on larger contracts, and to expand their customerbase — all while fostering their environmental commitment. For example, last October weannounced that we will be working with the Oceti Sakowin Power Authority, formed by sixSioux tribes to jointly develop tribal renewable energy resources, on a project to createa wind power development in the Midwest. And following the success of this year’s class,our efforts continue. This spring, applications opened for the next class to join ourImpact Accelerator.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_38.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>For Apple’s inaugural Impact Accelerator, leaders from 15 companies participatedin a three-month virtual program with customized training and access to Appleexpert mentors.</P>
<H2>Resources</H2>
<P>Natural resources make our work possible —and we take responsibility for how we source,use, and recycle the materials we rely on tocreate our products. As a starting point, thismeans sourcing responsibly, minimizing ourfreshwater use, and eliminating waste acrossour operations and those of our suppliers.And we’re also seeking to redefine the overallresource footprint of our products. Our goal isto one day make products using only responsiblysourced recycled and renewable materials.</P>
<P>Within resources, we focus on three mainareas of impact:</P>
<P>•Materials:Transitioning to only recycledor renewable materials in our productsand packaging, and maximizing materialefficiency, product longevity, and recovery.</P>
<P>•Water:Reducing water impacts in themanufacturing of our products, use of ourservices, and operation of our facilities.At the same time, transitioning to alternativesources, improving the quality of waterwe discharge, and protecting sharedwater resources.</P>
<P>•Zero waste:Minimizing overall wastegenerated and eliminating waste sent tolandfill from our manufacturing supply chainas well as corporate offices, data centers,and retail stores.</P>
<H3>Materials</H3>
<P>We aim to make the best use of the materials werely on to make our products. That’s why we’refocusing on three different levers to reduceour footprint and achieve circularity: sourcingand efficiency; product longevity; and productend-of-life.</P>
<P>Sourcing and efficiency</P>
<P>Last year, we made progress across materials —from expanding our use of recycled rare earthelements to designing cameras with recycledgold. In September, we introduced iPhone 13,with more certified recycled materials than anyprevious version of iPhone. We also introduced100 percent recycled aluminum enclosures onevery single model in the iPad lineup.</P>
<H1>20%</H1>
<P>In fiscal year 2021, nearly 20 percent ofthe material we shipped in products camefrom recycled and renewable sources</P>
<H1>2x</H1>
<P>In fiscal year 2021, we more than doubledour use of recycled tungsten, rare earthelements, and cobalt — and introducedcertified recycled gold for the first timein an Apple product</P>
<H1>75%</H1>
<TOC><TOCI>We’ve reduced the plastic in our packagingby 75 percent compared with 2015,progressing toward our goal to eliminateall plastic from our packaging by 2025</TOCI>
</TOC>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report19</P>
<P>Across our business, we released eightproducts with more than 20 percent recycledcontent.6The MacBook Air with M1 chip(2020) had the highest total — made with</P>
<P>44 percent recycled content device-wide,including 100 percent recycled aluminum in theenclosure. These and other innovations helpedus increase our use of recycled or renewablecontent to 18 percent of all the material shippedin products in fiscal year 2021.7</P>
<P>Product longevity</P>
<P>We want to make the most of the materials weuse through designing long-lasting products.We are designing durable hardware, leveragingsoftware updates to extend functionality,expanding access to repair services,refurbishing devices for their next user, andreusing parts that still have more to give. Readmore on caring for customers onpage56.</P>
<H1>Innovating packaging to reduce our footprint</H1>
<P>We’ve made significant progress toward eliminating all plastics from our packaging by 2025.This past year, plastics accounted for only 4 percent of our packaging. Since 2015, we’vededicated our efforts to replacing large plastic trays, wraps, and foam cushioning with fiberalternatives that have higher recovery rates and reduced environmental footprints.</P>
<P>This year, the iPhone 13 and iPhone 13 Pro were the first iPhone models to be shippedwithout any plastic packaging components.8And we replaced plastic foam with a fiberalternative to protect the 24-inch iMac during shipping.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_39.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>For the 24-inch iMac, using corrugated fiber rather than foam for shock absorptionallowed us to reduce plastic by 72 percent.</P>
<P>Product end-of-life</P>
<P>By effectively recovering the materials in ourproducts, we enable the circular supply chainsthat make the best use of finite resources.Through our work in this area, we’re reducingthe need to mine new materials and theamount of energy needed to manufacture newproducts, ultimately driving down emissionsand conserving resources.</P>
<P>In 99 percent of the countries where we</P>
<P>sell products, we continue to provide andparticipate in product take-back and recyclingcollection programs. With the help ofcustomer and employee participation acrossrecycling programs, we directed more than38,000 metric tons of e-waste to recyclingglobally in fiscal year 2021.</P>
<P>We’ve also continued to innovate ondisassembly technologies. Daisy, the robot wedesigned to disassemble iPhone devices, hasnow been joined by Dave, which dismantlesTaptic Engines from iPhone to enable therecovery of materials like rare earth elements,tungsten, and steel, and Taz, designed torecycle modules containing rare earth magnets.At our Material Recovery Lab we’re workingon developing better, more efficient means ofdisassembling products that maximize materialrecovery, while minimizing waste.</P>
<H1>Water stewardship</H1>
<P>We’re committed to managing the resourceswe share with the communities where we andour suppliers operate. Our efforts to addressthe water footprint of our corporate sites andof our suppliers’ sites focus on:</P>
<L><LI>•Using water efficiently</LI>
<LI>•Expanding the use of alternative watersources, including onsite reuse</LI>
<LI>•Discharging water responsibly</LI>
<LI>•Enhancing our water stewardship to keepwatersheds healthy for all who rely on them</LI>
</L>
<P>In fiscal year 2021, our facilities used about1.4 billion gallons of water. We saved 133 milliongallons of freshwater this fiscal year due toefficiency projects implemented since 2017.9Last year, alternative water sources accountedfor 10 percent of our total corporate water usage— primarily from recycled water sources.10</P>
<P>Our supply chain accounts for 99 percent ofour total water footprint, based on our detailedwater inventory. That’s why we partner closelywith our suppliers through our Clean WaterProgram. The more than 195 participatingsupplier sites increased their average reuserate to 41 percent and saved our suppliers12.3 billion gallons of freshwater in fiscal year2021 — for a total of 50.3 billion gallons ofwater savings since the program’s launchin 2013.11</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report20</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_42.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple works with the Alliance for Water Stewardship and others to promote water stewardship that protectsthe health of water basins, including the Kunshan watershed in China.</P>
<H3>Zero waste</H3>
<P>Across our corporate operations, we’re reducingthe amount of waste we generate and directingmore toward recycling programs. In fiscalyear 2021, recycling and composting effortsallowed us to achieve a waste diversion rate of68 percent, limiting landfill waste from our globaloperations to about 15,000 metric tons.12Ouroverall waste generated also remained low, inpart due to COVID-related temporary closureof facilities. Last year, our Mesa, Arizona, datacenter became the second Apple facility toreceive TRUE certification for zero waste,following the Prineville data center in 2020.13</P>
<P>We’ve partnered with our suppliers, recyclers,and waste solution providers to eliminate wastefrom our manufacturing processes. At the closeof fiscal year 2021, more than 100 facilitieshad been zero waste verified — nearly half ofthe supplier facilities that are part of our ZeroWaste Program.14All participating facilitiesacross 12 countries can access resourcesincluding guidance on how to reduce waste andthen reuse, recycle, or compost the waste theydo create. And we’re seeing results: In fiscalyear 2021, suppliers redirected 491,000 metrictons of waste from landfills, bringing the total toover 2 million metric tons since the program’sinception — the equivalent of eliminating morethan 2.5 million square meters of landfill space.</P>
<H1>100+</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_41.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple supplier facilitiesare zero waste verified</P>
<H1>2M+</H1>
<P>metric tons of waste redirected fromlandfill by supplier facilities as part ofApple’s Zero Waste Program</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_40.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Read more about our efforts to conserveresources in our2022 Environmental</P>
<P>Progress Report</P>
<H2>Smarter chemistry</H2>
<P>The well-being of our employees, customers,people in our supply chain, and the planetis a priority for Apple, which is why we’recommitted to using safer materials to createsafer products. This commitment requiresdiligent work — to build a comprehensivepicture of chemicals across our supply chain,to insist on rigorous chemical managementprocesses, to promote adoption of saferchemical alternatives, and to innovate throughdesign smarter approaches to making ourproducts. Using safer chemistry in ourproducts also enables recycling and materialrecovery, so that our products can be the rawmaterials for the next generation.</P>
<P>The pillars of our smarter chemistrystrategy are:</P>
<P>Mapping and engagement:Engage oursupply chain partners to comprehensivelyidentify the chemicals in the materials usedto make our products, allowing us to drivechange that goes beyond what is requiredfor regulatory compliance.</P>
<P>Assessment and management:Assess thepotential human health and environmental risksof chemicals to evaluate compliance with ourrequirements and inform product design.</P>
<P>Innovation:Drive the development and useof innovative materials that enable the creationof groundbreaking products and also supportindustrywide change.</P>
<H3>Mapping and engagement</H3>
<P>Our Full Material Disclosure (FMD) programmaps the chemicals used in our products —an effort that includes tens of thousands ofparts and assemblies. Then we look at howour products are manufactured. Our ChemicalSafety Disclosure (CSD) program engages withsupply chain partners to get the most recentinformation on which materials are in use.This information includes the volume ofmaterials being consumed and how they’rebeing applied, stored, and handled — as wellas the steps being taken to protect employees.</P>
<P>More than 1000 supplier facilities have sharedtheir chemical inventories as well as storage andsafety protocols as part of our CSD program.Through this process, we’ve identified morethan 17,000 chemicals and applications. Theseefforts contribute to a safer work environmentfor people across our supply chain.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Our PeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report21</P>
<H1>Assessment and management</H1>
<P>The data we collect on chemicals and materials</P>
<P>forms the foundation for key decisions that</P>
<P>have an impact on our product designs,</P>
<P>manufacturing processes, and approach to</P>
<P>recycling and reuse. This data enables us</P>
<P>to establish requirements for our suppliers,</P>
<P>including those set out in ourRegulated</P>
<P>Substances Specification (RSS)and the</P>
<P>Restricted Chemicals for Prolonged SkinContact Materials list. These requirements</P>
<P>provide clear guidelines on potentially harmful</P>
<P>materials, including those that are restricted.</P>
<P>Our assessment system helps to ensure</P>
<P>that only materials that meet our stringentrequirements are used in Apple products. At ourEnvironmental Testing Lab, we evaluate thesafety of our products and materials throughchemical analyses. Our chemists test materialsfor safety and monitor compliance with ourspecifications. In fiscal year 2021, we performedtoxicological assessments on 1000 new materialsto proactively evaluate and eliminate potentiallyharmful substances from our products.</P>
<P>Both the data we gather on chemicals andour rigorous assessments allow us to makeinformed decisions and manage chemicals,for the safety of those who use, make, andrecycle our products.</P>
<H1>Innovation</H1>
<P>The work we do in mapping, assessing, andmanaging the chemicals within our supplychain underpins our innovations. We rely ondetailed information on the material properties,including toxicological data and environmentalperformance characteristics. We also look</P>
<P>at how these materials are used at each</P>
<P>point in the product life cycle, from design, tomanufacturing, to end-of-life. This allows us toseek out and support the development of saferchemistries that have an impact on each phase— and contribute to continually improving theoverall safety of our products and processes.</P>
<P>Since the late 1990s, we have diligentlyidentified and removed potentially harmfulchemicals from our products, such asbrominated flame retardants, beryllium,mercury, and lead. We’re also driving theuse of safer process chemicals in our supplychain: Since 2018, all our final assembly siteshave used only safer alternative cleaners anddegreasers. As we work toward minimizingpotentially harmful chemistries in our productsand processes, we’re making the transition tosafer alternatives accessible to others throughindustry initiatives, partnerships, and standardswith the hope of driving chemical safety acrossthe industry.</P>
<H1>Comprehensive chemical mapping</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_43.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>MappingchemicalsMappingchemicalsthroughoutproductthroughoutproductdevelopmentleadstodevelopmentleadstobetter,better,saferproductssaferproducts</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_44.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Understanding chemicalingredientsleads to bettermaterials for Apple products</P>
<P>Through our Full Material Disclosure (FMD)program, manufacturers share chemicalingredients used to make materials with Apple.</P>
<P>With FMD data, Apple evaluates the chemicalsin materials against restrictions.</P>
<P>Data helps Apple suppliersmanage chemicalswhenmaking Apple products</P>
<P>Information on how chemicals are used, howthey’re stored, and how employees are protectedis shared with Apple by suppliers through ourChemical Safety Disclosure (CSD) program.</P>
<P>CSD data informs and prioritizes supplierengagement, helping to ensure rigorouschemical management practices and adoptionof safer alternatives.</P>
<P>Applecustomers benefitfrom use of products madewith safer ingredients</P>
<P>The FMD and CSD programs help supportcreation of best-in-class products in aresponsible manner for our customers.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_45.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_46.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Read more about our commitment to usingsafer materials to create safer products inour2022 Environmental Progress Report</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersEnvironmentIntroductionOurPeople</P>
<H1>The heart ofwho we are.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report22</P>
<H2>Our People</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Our approach</P>
<P>Inclusion and diversityGrowth and developmentBenefits</P>
<P>CompensationEngagement</P>
<P>Workplace practices and policiesHealth and safety at Apple</P>
<P>23</P>
<P>23</P>
<P>26</P>
<P>27</P>
<P>28</P>
<P>29</P>
<P>30</P>
<P>33</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report23</P>
<H1>At Apple, we work every day to create an inclusive, safe, and supportiveenvironment for all our team members. We’re always finding new waysto invest in our teams’ development and to encourage collaborationand creativity. And we provide strong and comprehensive benefits andcompetitive compensation. We believe we’re a better and more innovativecompany when people have support and the opportunity to be theirbest selves.</H1>
<H1>Our approach</H1>
<P>With over 165,000 team members* around theworld, our people are at the heart of everythingwe do. From their first day, Apple team membershave the resources and opportunities to buildnew skill sets, pursue new passions, and feelsupported and cared for at work and beyond.</P>
<P>Our People team supports our overall employeeexperience — from hiring to retaining ourtalented team members — through our inclusiveculture, learning opportunities, compensation,and benefits. The team is led by Deirdre O’Brien,Senior Vice President of Retail + People,reporting to CEO Tim Cook. Deirdre works withthe People team to help Apple connect with,develop, and care for team members — and tohelp everyone do the best work of their lives.</P>
<P>A safe environment is also integral to unlockingthe potential of all of our team members. And ourcommitment to environment, health, and safety(EHS) extends to contractors, customers, andcommunities as well. We’re working hard to makesure our people are safe no matter where theyare when they’re conducting business for Apple.We have procedures in place to identify andmitigate possible hazards, and we’re prepared torespond to any crises that may arise. Our SeniorVice President and Chief Financial Officer (CFO)Luca Maestri oversees Apple’s EHS program,which is driven by an expert leadership team.</P>
<P>We have robust workplace policies andpractices, including our Business ConductPolicy, Human Rights Policy, and EHS Policy,that articulate our strong commitment to ourpeople and to creating an environment wherethey can do their best work.</P>
<H1>Inclusion and diversity</H1>
<P>At Apple, we remain committed to building amore equitable and inclusive world by increasingdiverse representation at every level, fosteringan inclusive culture that brings everybody in,and ensuring equitable pay and access toopportunity for all.</P>
<P>Inclusive representation in leadership is apowerful driver of progress. At Apple, leadersof all backgrounds are working to growand develop our next generation of leadersfrom within. We’re committed to increasing thenumber of managers from underrepresentedcommunities, because differences in ourbackgrounds, our identities, and the waywe think ultimately make our teams strongerand more innovative.</P>
<P>Accountability measures across thecompany allow us to track progress andbuild a foundation for lasting and durablechange. We’re listening to employee feedback,amplifying underrepresented voices, andtaking action to meet our teams’ needs.</P>
<P>From hiring to development and engagement,we’re making sure every part of Apple isincreasing inclusion and representation. Seniorleaders now have access to data that helpsthem assess how well they’re driving diversitywithin their teams and organizations. We’rebuilding inclusion and diversity measuresinto our annual review process to create</P>
<P>consistency in how we drive and track progress.In the last year, we completed comprehensivedata reviews with executive leadership andorganizational action plans within every lineof business.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report24</P>
<H2>More inclusive leadership</H2>
<P>Compared to the previous year, open leadership* roles filled by women globally increased by 10percentage points overall, and by 8 percentage points in R&amp;D. And in the U.S., open leadership rolesfilled by people from underrepresented communities (URCs)** increased by 16 percentage pointsoverall, and by 9 percentage points in R&amp;D.</P>
<H1>47%</H1>
<P>Open leadership roles filledby women globally</P>
<H1>59%</H1>
<P>Open leadership roles filled bypeople from URCs in the U.S</P>
<H2>Progress in retail</H2>
<H1>58%</H1>
<P>Open retail leadership rolesglobally filled by women</P>
<H1>34%</H1>
<P>Open R&amp;D leadership roles filledby women globally</P>
<H1>38%</H1>
<P>Open R&amp;D leadership roles filledby people from URCs in the U.S</P>
<H1>76%</H1>
<P>Open retail leadership roles inthe U.S. filled by people from URCs</P>
<P>*Leadership roles include managers at all levels of our company.</P>
<P>**URCs: Groups whose representation in tech has been historically low — Female, Black, Hispanic/Latinx, Multiracial,and Indigenous peoples.</P>
<P>Data is for the 2021 calendar year.</P>
<H2>Inclusive representation</H2>
<P>To create products for everyone in the world,we need a workforce with diverse backgroundsand experiences. We’re making continuousprogress in building an Apple community that</P>
<P>represents the diverse and ever-changingworld we live in. And we’re committedto far more.</P>
<P>We’re making progress in increasingrepresentation, and currently 50 percent ofour workforce in the U.S. is made up of peoplefrom underrepresented communities. Withmore than 165,000 employees globally, evena 1 percent improvement impacts a substantialnumber of people, and increasing overallrepresentation requires focus to drive progress.</P>
<TOC><TOCI>Please see the Appendix onpage 81formore data on representation across ourworkforce. Additionally, more than half of ourBoard identify as women and/or membersof Asian, Black, Hispanic/Latinx, LGBTQ+,and veterans communities. And women holdhalf of our Board and committee leadershippositions. Read more on page 6 of our2022</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>ProxyStatement.</P>
<P>need to develop inclusive interviewing skills.All of our hiring managers and recruitersreceive training in inclusive hiring practices.Our recruiters also receive training on how tocontinuously drive meaningful conversationswith hiring managers to help implement thesehiring practices with every role. These trainingshelp mitigate inherent biases and create moreconsistent hiring experiences for all.</P>
<P>We’re working to accelerate progress throughour diversity recruiting and hiring efforts acrossApple, with a focus on technical, engineering,and leadership roles. We’re expanding ourdiversity outreach efforts, including our tieswith Historically Black Colleges and Universities(HBCUs), Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs),and other organizations that serve and engagetalent from underrepresented communities.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_47.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_48.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Beyond our own operations, we’re partneringto challenge systemic bias through initiativeslike REJI (page 60), Entrepreneur Camp (page64), Impact Accelerator (page 18), AppleDeveloper Academy (page 63), work withHistorically Black Colleges and Universities(HBCUs) and HSIs (page 60), as well as ourresponsible procurement work (page 45).</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_49.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>Continuing to increase Black and Hispanic/Latinx team members</H2>
<P>Over the past year, we hired more Black and Hispanic/Latinx team members in the U.S. than ever before.Additionally, in the open positions we filled during this time period, representation of these communitieswas the highest ever in corporate and retail roles filled in the U.S.</P>
<H1>13%</H1>
<P>Open U.S. leadership roles filledby Black candidates</P>
<H1>23%</H1>
<P>Open U.S. retail leadership rolesfilled by Black candidates</P>
<P>Data is for the 2021 calendar year.</P>
<H1>12%</H1>
<P>Open U.S. leadership roles</P>
<P>filled by Hispanic/Latinx candidates</P>
<H1>18%</H1>
<P>Open U.S. retail leadership rolesfilled by Hispanic/Latinx candidates</P>
<H2>Inclusive hiring</H2>
<P>We’ve built inclusion and diversity measuresinto our candidate assessment framework. Andwe continue to make progress toward our goalof having more diverse interview panels andcandidates so that diversity is reflected at everystage of the hiring process. We’re making sureeveryone involved in the hiring process hasaccess to the information and resources they</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report25</P>
<H1>185,000</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_51.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>hours of inclusion and diversitytraining in calendar year 2021*</P>
<L><LI>*In addition to training and embedded materialprovided through Apple University below.</LI>
</L>
<H1>80,000</H1>
<P>hours of management educationincluding focus on mitigating biasand creating inclusive environmentsthrough Apple University in FY2021</P>
<P>Nearly</P>
<H1>10,000</H1>
<P>coaching hours provided to managersand individuals in support of inclusionthrough Apple University in FY2021</P>
<H1>4000</H1>
<P>hours for optional in-depth coursesexploring race and justice in the U.S.,gender in the workforce, and buildinginclusive products through AppleUniversity in FY2021</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_50.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>55K</H1>
<P>employee members of DNAcommunities worldwide</P>
<H1>1000+</H1>
<P>community events and heritagecelebrations worldwide in the last year</P>
<H2>Training and resources</H2>
<P>Apple team members have access to careerdevelopment programs, ongoing inclusionand diversity education, and supportthroughout their career journey. From new-hireorientation, to specialized classes for individualcontributors and managers, to talent planningand mentorship, we’re always finding new waysto help team members continue to learn, thrive,and advance in their careers in</P>
<P>an inclusive environment.</P>
<P>All of our employees complete unconsciousbias and inclusion training, and can accessexpert-led courses on race, gender, justice,allyship, and more. Equitable, inclusiveexperiences for all employees begin withequipping our leaders with the resources theyneed. Apple’s more than 15,000 managersare trained in unconscious bias andinclusive leadership.</P>
<P>In addition, in fiscal year 2021, we reached90 percent of all managers with new materialon creating inclusive environments andmitigating bias within their teams. This offeringwill now be available to all new managers.</P>
<P>We also work to ensure equitable accessacross all of our growth and developmentprograms (seepage26).</P>
<H2>Supporting accessibilityfor our employees</H2>
<P>Accessibility is one of our values and afundamental human right. To make sure thatall of our team members have the supportthey need, Apple’s own best-in-classaccessibility features are in use across thecompany by team members with disabilitiesto remove barriers and enable them to bemore productive and successful. We offeron-demand sign language interpretationin the U.S., Canada, the UK, and France tosupport in-person conversations, or to reachout to employee services. We have multipleaccessibility-focused trainings available toteam members, managers, and recruiters.We have a dedicated global accessibilityand accommodations team to support teammembers throughout their career journeys.And we have a directory of all of theseaccessibility resources available that teammembers can access and search.</P>
<H2>Community is the core of our culture</H2>
<P>For more than 35 years, Apple employeeshave found community and connection inApple’s Diversity Network Associations (DNAs).These employee-led groups foster a cultureof belonging through education, leadershipdevelopment, networking, and volunteering— while also encouraging the kind of opendialogue that leads to stronger allyshipacross Apple.</P>
<P>In the last year, we’ve grown our global DNAcommunities more than 50 percent, includingexpansions in Apple Store locations and acrossall regions. More than 55,000 Apple employeesbelong to groups like Accessibility@Apple,AsianPacific@Apple, Beacon@Apple,Black@Apple, Familia@Apple,Indigenous@Apple, Pride@Apple, SouthAsian@Apple, Veterans@Apple, Women@Apple,and more.</P>
<P>Many of our community-led initiatives andvolunteer engagements drive progress withinthe business as well as outside Apple inlocal communities.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_52.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Supporting our team members to find community and build connections is central to our culture.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report26</P>
<H2>Growth and development</H2>
<P>We want everyone to flourish in their time atApple, whether in their current role or their nextcareer opportunity. We offer many differentpaths to career fulfillment, and we continue totake new steps to ensure that everyone at Applehas the opportunity to find support to growand develop.</P>
<P>Across Apple, our managers and leadershelp our team members progress, creatingdevelopment pathways that enableindividuals to learn, improve, and empowertheir colleagues to do the best work of theirlives. We provide a growth and developmentframework and tools — including planningworksheets, manager toolkits, and a dedicatedinternal web page — that team members canuse to create individual plans to shape theircareers and identify their goals.</P>
<P>We encourage our team members to discovernew opportunities and roles listed on ourinternal career site, and for many roles andlines of business, we provide detailed profilesof the skills required to be successful.We help ensure an end-to-end selectionprocess that is clear and equitable for all,and we encourage regular discussions withmanagers about team members’ growth anddevelopment goals at Apple.</P>
<H1>175,000</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_53.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>training hours in Apple Universityin FY2021</P>
<P>In addition to our company-wide programsand initiatives, a significant amount of learninghappens within teams because of our uniquefunctional structure. Our leaders are expertsin their fields and thus guide their teamsof experts to further deepen very specificknowledge and skill sets.</P>
<P>We also support team members throughformal education and career developmentinitiatives, including:</P>
<P>Apple University:Apple University beganin 2010 with a simple mission — to fosterunderstanding and critical thinking aboutApple’s culture, organization, and values.Apple University offers original classes,tools, and resources across a distinctive rangeof topics to help employees learn to lead andexplore important topics like fairness andjustice. All employees have access to AppleUniversity, and to date, more than 95 percentof executives and managers and nearly</P>
<P>60 percent of individual contributors haveparticipated in classes. In fiscal year 2021,team members spent more than 175,000hours participating in all Apple Universitycourses combined.</P>
<P>Educational Assistance Program:OurEducational Assistance Program offers tuitionreimbursement for team members to continuetheir education.</P>
<P>Apple Mentorship Program:Our newmentorship program creates opportunities forApple employees of all backgrounds to learnfrom one another and grow their careers atApple. After successful pilot programs in the</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_54.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Across Apple, our managers and leaders help our team members to learn, improve,and do the best work of their lives.</P>
<P>U.S. and the UK, we’re continuing to expand theprogram globally, pairing a greater number ofexperienced Apple mentors with future leadersfrom across the company.</P>
<P>Retail-specific training:Through onboardingtraining, new Apple Retail employees learnthe fundamental knowledge and skills thatwill support their success at Apple. Ongoingtraining opportunities cover Apple cultureand values, products and services, systems,processes, and customer engagement skills.</P>
<P>Career Experience:Career Experiencesenable temporary, hands-on developmentopportunities for Apple Store, service, andsupport team members by creating short-term rotations in technical, operations, andcorporate functions across Apple. Participantsbuild new skills, explore an aspirational roleup close, and gain in-role experience, whilehost teams benefit from the unique customer-facing perspectives, talents, and passions ofparticipants. The program is currently availablein 11 locations in every geographic region, withmore countries being added each year, and96% of Apple’s lines of business participate.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report27</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_55.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Every year, our performance review process helps team members have meaningfulconversations with their managers.</P>
<P>Rotational programs:We also have a numberof programs for new graduates to learn througha combination of training and on-the-jobwork experience. Over a two-year period,participants rotate through multiple teams togain a breadth of experience and exposure tovarious projects to help discover their strengthsand passion. Upon successful completion ofthe program, participants will often transitioninto a non-rotating role within Apple. OurServices, Finance, Operations, and AI/MLfunctions all offer these types of programs.</P>
<H2>Performance reviews</H2>
<P>Our annual performance review processoffers team members the opportunity to</P>
<P>have meaningful conversations with theirmanagers about their performance, growth, anddevelopment. Across Apple, employees receivean annual performance review, and retail teammembers are supported by monthly performanceconversations to align on their progress.</P>
<P>Performance reviews focus on three categories:teamwork, innovation, and results, and theyinclude a self-assessment and feedback frompeers and the team member’s manager. Theperformance review is also a chance to reflecton the contribution each person makes toApple’s long-standing commitment to inclusionand diversity.</P>
<H1>Benefits</H1>
<P>We recognize that our people thrive whenthey have the resources to meet their needsand the time and support to succeed in theirprofessional and personal lives. We providea host of benefits for corporate and retailemployees to help our teams live healthier, morefulfilled, and happier lives at work and beyond.15</P>
<P>We regularly review and update the benefits thatwe offer in order to respond to our employees’changing needs. For example, we recentlyexpanded family care services and mental healthbenefits, including 15 free counseling sessionsthrough our Employee Assistance Program, tohelp employees care for themselves and theirloved ones through the pandemic. And in theU.S., we now offer part-time team membersnew vacation and sick leave days, New ParentLeave, Gradual Return to Work, Paid FamilyCare, and Emergency Backup Care, and in 2022,we enhanced sick leave benefits and a newaccelerated vacation accrual schedule for full-timeemployees in our U.S. Apple Store locations.</P>
<H2>Physical and mental well-being</H2>
<P>Apple provides employees with a wide varietyof health-related benefits, including:</P>
<L><LI>•Physical and mental health coverage that alsoextends to spouses and domestic partners</LI>
<LI>•Virtual and onsite wellness visits for employeesand eligible dependents</LI>
<LI>•Free, confidential counseling for employeesand their dependents16</LI>
<LI>•Comprehensive reproductive health services17</LI>
<LI>•Expert second opinion resources to helpemployees and their family members makeinformed healthcare decisions</LI>
</L>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report28</P>
<P>•A comprehensive mental health andwell-being hub where employees can findevents, apps, and other resources</P>
<L><LI>•Month-long wellness events for teammembers across Apple to support oneanother and build healthier habits</LI>
</L>
<P>Our health plans are designed to supportthe various life stages of our employees andtheir families. They are transgender inclusive,where legally and plan allowed, and supportroutine care, therapies, and other medicallynecessary surgeries.</P>
<H2>Life and family</H2>
<P>Apple also provides a number of benefits tosupport our employees in their personal andfamily life, including:</P>
<L><LI>•Retirement programs to help employees withtheir future financial needs, such as 401(k)matching contributions in the U.S. and localretirement plans for employees outside ofthe U.S.</LI>
<LI>•Referrals and resources for childcare, whichincludes backup care in the U.S., as wellas before- and after-school programs,programs for children with special needs,and more</LI>
</L>
<P>•Consultations and referrals to supportemployees caring for an elderlyfamily member</P>
<L><LI>•Adoption, surrogacy, and fertility services</LI>
<LI>•Financial coaching services</LI>
<LI>•Tuition reimbursement</LI>
<LI>•Legal services for adoption, child support,housing, wills, identity theft, and more</LI>
</L>
<P>Coming back to work after the arrival of a childcan be a big adjustment for employees, so to</P>
<P>smooth the transition period following the arrivalof a new family member, our gradual return-to-work program allows employees to chooseto return half-time at full pay for four weeks —whether they’re welcoming a child through birth,adoption, or other covered means.</P>
<H2>Time away</H2>
<P>Taking the time to recharge is an important partof employee health and well-being. We providea wide variety of time-away options for ouremployees, including:</P>
<L><LI>•Vacation</LI>
<LI>•Paid sick time and medical leave for serioushealth conditions18</LI>
<LI>•Pregnancy leave and New Parent Leave19</LI>
<LI>•Leave for bereavement or to care for a sickfamily member</LI>
<LI>•Time off for voting, jury duty, and othercivil obligations</LI>
<LI>•Company holidays throughout the year</LI>
</L>
<H2>Product discounts</H2>
<P>Apple’s Employee Purchase Plan offers specialpricing on most Apple products. We offersubstantial discounts on hardware, software,and accessories for employees, families, andfriends — as well as an additional credit that canbe used to purchase a Mac, iPad, or unlockediPhone once every two years.</P>
<H1>Compensation</H1>
<P>We believe that our compensation should notonly be highly competitive across all types ofroles, levels, and talent markets; it should be</P>
<P>equitable and enable all team members to sharein the company’s success as shareholdersof Apple.</P>
<P>We’re committed to being a leader in payequity, providing all employees with annualopportunities for stock ownership in thecompany, and offering highly competitivepay that’s in the top tier of each local market.And we hold our leaders accountable byincorporating Apple values and key communityinitiatives into our executive short-termincentive plan.</P>
<H2>Competitive pay</H2>
<P>Apple is committed to remaining a marketleader in compensation through our highlycompetitive and equitable programs. Inaddition to our stock program and wide rangeof benefits we provide, we regularly review ourcompetitive position to establish our leadingstarting pay rates in each local market.</P>
<H2>Apple stock ownership</H2>
<P>In 2015, we introduced our Stock OwnershipProgram, which was designed to reachemployees who were not previously eligible forrestricted stock unit (RSU) awards, includingall of our retail and AppleCare teams. By theend of 2022, over $1.1 billion of RSU grants willhave been awarded under this program, andthe shares underlying the RSUs today wouldhave an estimated value of over $3 billion(based on a share price of $130.06 as of June16, 2022). Apple is one of the few companiesin the S&amp;P 500, and the largest technologycompany, in which employees at all levels areeligible for RSU grants on an annual basis. In2021, 150,000 employees were eligible forRSU grants and our Compensation Committeeapproved grants for 99% of those eligible.</P>
<P>In most countries, employees also get discountswhen purchasing Apple stock by participatingin the Employee Stock Purchase Plan (ESPP).Currently, 81 percent of eligible employeesparticipate in the ESPP.</P>
<H2>ESG Modifier</H2>
<P>Beginning in 2021, the CompensationCommittee incorporated the ESG Modifierinto the Executive annual cash incentiveprogram. The ESG Modifier is based on aholistic evaluation by the CompensationCommittee of key accomplishments andactions taken during the year to advanceour Apple values: accessibility, education,environment, inclusion and diversity, privacy,and supplier responsibility, and key communityinitiatives which were chosen because theyrepresent long-standing, business-relevantenvironmental, social, and governanceprinciples that reflect Apple’s commitment topromoting values-driven leadership.</P>
<H2>Pay equity</H2>
<P>Since 2017, Apple has achieved and maintainedgender pay equity for our employees worldwide.In the U.S., we’ve also achieved pay equity withrespect to race and ethnicity — as well as payequity at the intersections of race and ethnicitywith gender.*</P>
<P>In addition to our pay equity commitment,our Inclusion and Diversity program (seepage 23) supports growth, development,and engagement for team members ofall backgrounds.</P>
<P>We have a number of practices in placeto support our commitment to payequity, including:</P>
<L><LI>*Pay equity at the intersections of race and ethnicitywith gender was achieved in 2022.</LI>
</L>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report29</P>
<P>Annual pay equity review:To maintain payequity, we engage an independent third-partyexpert to build and run statistical models toassess and resolve any differences in totalcompensation on the basis of gender and, inthe U.S., on the basis of race and ethnicity andat the intersections with gender.</P>
<P>Job assessments:Apple’s dedicatedcompensation team regularly conductscomprehensive job title reviews to ensure thatemployees are in the correct job title, which isan important factor in determining pay. We alsocontinuously analyze market data to ensurethat compensation guidelines for all rolesremain competitive.</P>
<H3>Pay equity at Apple</H3>
<P>Our pay equity review is global and covers100 percent of our employees. We considertotal compensation, including base salary,bonus, and stock.</P>
<H1>1:1</H1>
<P>gender pay equity globally</P>
<H1>1:1</H1>
<P>pay equity in the U.S. by raceand ethnicity</P>
<H1>1:1</H1>
<P>gender pay equity in every country</P>
<H1>1:1</H1>
<P>pay equity in the U.S. atthe intersections of raceand ethnicity and gender</P>
<P>Annual compensation planning:During ourannual compensation planning process, thePeople team uses analytics to assess promotionrates, performance ratings distribution, and paymetrics for women compared to men and, in theU.S., for underrepresented groups comparedto non-underrepresented groups.</P>
<P>Global compensation history policy:Wedon’t ask candidates for salary history duringthe recruiting process, which has been ourpolicy globally since 2019. Our recruitersdevelop offers of employment based on thecompensation of current Apple employees insimilar roles using a tool developed specificallyfor this purpose.</P>
<H2>Engagement</H2>
<P>At Apple, we believe that open and honestcommunication among team members,managers, and leaders helps create an open,collaborative work environment where everyonecan contribute, grow, and succeed.</P>
<P>Across all our teams, we’re always building onour long-standing commitment to creating anenvironment where people at every level of thecompany feel connected and supported. Ourgoal is to listen and learn — and to use thoselessons to build an even better workplace for all.</P>
<P>If team members have questions, feedback,or concerns, they’re encouraged to sharethem with their manager. If a team member isever uncomfortable raising a particular issuewith their manager, they can discuss it withany manager at Apple, their People BusinessPartner, People Support, or they can contactthe Business Conduct team.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_57.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>We encourage open and honest communication among team members, managers, and leadership as we seek tobuild a better work environment for all.</P>
<P>Another way team members can let us knowhow Apple is doing is to participate in surveysthat we conduct regularly. These survey resultsare a great way for us to learn about what’sgoing well and how we can do better in areaslike career development, manager performance,and inclusivity, and teams are encouraged tocreate action plans based on the survey results.</P>
<P>We conduct annual surveys for all Apple Storeand AppleCare team members to listen to theirviews on topics like leadership, management,career development, performance, values,culture, and work environment. And leadersfrom each organization use the survey insightsto take steps to better support team memberswhere they need it.</P>
<P>Over the last two years in particular, we focusedon listening to Apple Store and AppleCareemployees as they were interacting mostdirectly with customers during the pandemicand experiencing rapid change in how theyworked to support those customers. For ourearly 2022 surveys, 76 percent of Apple Storeteam members and 73 percent of AppleCareteam members participated.</P>
<P>Apple has a no-retaliation policy. Retaliationagainst anyone who comes forward with aconcern or participates in an investigation isgrounds for termination. We respect each teammember’s right to form or join (or refrain fromjoining) organizations of their choice in a lawfulmanner without discrimination, retaliation,or harassment.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_56.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H3>Empowering employeesto support the causes theycare about</H3>
<P>Our Employee Giving program providesopportunities for employees to contributeto the causes they care deeply about withthe support of Apple. From volunteering todonations to smaller individual actions, Appleis committed to giving, hand in hand with ourteam members. Read more onpage 67.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report30</P>
<H2>Reporting a concern</H2>
<P>At Apple we believe strongly in a culture of open communication, mutual respect, and highethical standards — and we strive to do the right thing. It can be stressful if something at Applehas a negative effect on well-being, violates an Apple policy, or interferes with someone’sability to do their best work. There are several ways team members can report a concern:</P>
<P>Managers:Talking to a manager is a good place to start. A large part of their responsibilityis to support their team members. If a team member is not comfortable bringing a concernto their manager, they can discuss it with any manager at Apple.</P>
<P>People Support:This dedicated team specializes in supporting Apple team members withwork-related topics. They can answer questions, clarify a policy, or suggest resources oroptions to help resolve a problem.</P>
<P>Business Conduct:Team members can contact the Business Conduct team via phone,email, or a third party. They will review the concern and share it with the appropriate internalpartners. Read more on page 72.</P>
<P>People Business Partner:Team members can discuss the issue with their PeopleBusiness Partner (PBP), particularly if it’s related to your team or organization.</P>
<P>Team members are encouraged to raise their concerns in the way they feel mostcomfortable, internally or externally. In addition to the options above, they may also contactany of the government agencies or other external organizations that address employee andworkplace concerns.</P>
<H1>Workplace practicesand policies</H1>
<P>Apple’s culture is built on treating everyone withdignity and respect, and this focus shapes howour colleagues engage with one another andwith our customers and partners around theworld. We’re also committed to respecting ourteam members’ rights as set out in our HumanRightsPolicy.</P>
<H2>Equal employment opportunity</H2>
<P>Apple is an equal opportunity employercommitted to inclusion and diversity.</P>
<P>We take steps to provide equal opportunityfor all applicants and employees, withoutregard to race, color, ancestry, national origin,caste, religion, creed, age (over 40), mentaland physical disability, sex, gender (includingpregnancy, childbirth, breastfeeding, or relatedmedical conditions), sexual orientation, genderidentity or expression, medical condition,genetic information, marital status, militaryor protected Veteran status, an employee’sreproductive health decisions or those oftheir dependents, or on any other basisprotected by law. We provide reasonableaccommodations to applicants and employeeswith physical and mental disabilities.</P>
<H2>Harassment and discrimination</H2>
<P>Wearecommitted to providing a workplacefreeofharassmentordiscriminationbasedonrace,color,ancestry,nationalorigin,caste,sex,gender(includingpregnancy,childbirth,breastfeeding,orrelatedmedicalconditions),sexualorientation,genderidentityorexpression,religion,creed,age(over 40), mental and physical disability, medicalcondition,geneticinformation,maritalstatus,ormilitary or protected Veteran status, or on anyother basis protectedby law. Wedo not toleratediscriminationorharassmentofouremployeesorthosewithwhomwehaveabusiness,service,orprofessionalrelationship(includingcustomers),nor do wetolerate workplace violence of any kind.Retaliationagainstanyoneforcomplainingaboutharassmentordiscrimination,orforparticipatingin theinvestigation of a complaint of harassmentordiscrimination,isagainstApplepolicyandwillnot betolerated at Apple.</P>
<H2>Voluntary decision review</H2>
<P>Apple’s voluntary decision review enablesemployeestohaveanemploymentdecisionreevaluated. This is designed to promotefairness and impartiality, in line with our valuesand policies. The reviewer will consider anynewinformationthatindicatesthedecisionmay not have been in accordance with ourpoliciesandguidelines.</P>
<H2>Non-employeesandtemporary workers</H2>
<P>In addition to our full-time employees,temporaryworkersandvendorservicesplayanimportant role on our team. Our temporaryworkersgenerallyperformsimilarworkasourfull-time employees, as they are intended toaugmenttheAppleemployeeworkforceunderashorttomid-termassignment.Approximately</P>
<P>6 percent of our U.S. corporate workforcewere temporary workers as of October 2021.Temporary workers have the same opportunityto be considered as all other applicants to anyApple job posting whether that opportunity isa conversion of their current role or a role theyfound on our job site. And in our retail business,we have a strong record of hiring temporaryworkers as full- and part-time employees.</P>
<P>Our outsourced services with workers providedvia vendors generally perform work that can bedifferent from that performed by our permanentemployees. This workforce is intended tosupport business needs where specific skillsare required and the vendors have the abilityto scale with our varied business needs.</P>
<P>Pay and benefits:For vendor services, payrates are managed by the vendor. Variousbenefits, including but not limited to healthcare,are offered to these workers through theiremployer or staffing agencies. Vendors arealso accountable to Apple’s Supplier Codeof Conduct, which requires that our staffingagencies are compliant with all current localand national legislation and employment laws,including wage and benefits requirements, fortheir employees (seepage 37orPeople andEnvironment in Our SupplyChain).</P>
<P>Raising concerns:In many cases there aremultiple avenues for non-Apple workers toreport problems anonymously, including internalprocesses with their employer and the AppleBusiness Conduct Helpline (seepage72).</P>
<P>Performance:Vendor performance isreviewed and evaluated by the vendormanagement based on feedback sometimesreceived from Apple managers, Procurement,and/or Supplier Responsibility.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report31</P>
<H1>Apple’sCOVID-19response</H1>
<H2>Protecting each other’s health</H2>
<P>At every stage of the pandemic, our firstpriority has always been the health of ourteams, customers, and communities. Thatmeant being one of the first companies toclose our offices and retail stores, and findinginnovative ways to connect with colleagues andcustomers virtually.</P>
<P>Since 2020, we’ve continued our efforts andprograms to support our people. We adoptedCDC recommendations around up-to-datevaccinations, including booster doses. Applealso continued to pay our teams duringtemporary store and office closures, expandedour paid leave policies, and enhanced ourpolicies and procedures for a safe workenvironment — both in the office and in-store.</P>
<P>To keep our teams informed, we deployedcomprehensive resources with up-to-dateCOVID-19 information, including a dedicatedplatform for teams returning to the office.COVID-19 case support, implemented forall team members, included return-to-workguidance and contact tracing, with the utmostregard for employee privacy. We continue tooffer special sick leave for employees withpossible COVID-19 symptoms, as well ascomprehensive health coverage.</P>
<P>To continue to manage our response goingforward, we created a dedicated pandemicresponse team in 2022 in addition to thecross-functional team that has been supportingand guiding our COVID response. The newresponse team will support future pandemicplanning and response.</P>
<H2>Innovating to support our customers</H2>
<P>Despite all of the pandemic’s challenges, webrought our hardware, software, and servicesinto customers’ hands, helping them stayinformed, connected, and entertained.</P>
<P>We also tailored our services to promote easyaccess to trusted information on COVID-19:launching a dedicated section on Apple News;prioritizing visibility of essential serviceslocations — including COVID-19 testing andvaccination locations — on Apple Maps;offering a curated collection of telehealth appson the App Store; and leveraging Siri to providethe latest COVID-19 guidance.</P>
<P>To meet the extraordinary challenges ofvirtual education, we delivered new contentand services for students, parents, andteachers to foster creativity and learning</P>
<P>in a digital environment. We worked withmobile carriers and school administratorsto deliver iPad devices with cellular supportfor students in need. With our Apple CardCustomer Assistance Program, we also offeredcustomers the option to skip their monthlypayments without incurring interest.</P>
<P>Across many of our Apple Store locations,we were able to serve our customers’</P>
<P>needs through contactless pickup, expressstorefronts, and new online support. Ourresponse to COVID-19 is still ongoing, andwe’re committed to implementing healthprotocols and adjusting store operations asrequired based on available data and guidancefrom health officials.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_58.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>The health of our teams, customers, and communities continues to be our first priority.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report32</P>
<H1>Supporting people in our supply chain</H1>
<P>We are continuing to work together with oursuppliers to help them ensure that everynecessary precaution is taken to keep peoplesafe at work. In 2020, we introduced anenhancement to our Code and Standardsspecifically addressing Infectious DiseasePreparedness and Response (IDPR). IDPRcontains a set of new requirements resultingfrom our learnings during the pandemic, whichwill help our suppliers better prepare for andbe ready to respond to an infectious diseaseoutbreak at their facility. As part of the rolloutof IDPR in fiscal year 2021, we conductedmore than 200 onsite and remote specializedassessments to verify suppliers’ compliancewith COVID-19 control protocols in order todrive improvement when necessary.</P>
<P>We also continue to assess any existing gapsat supplier facilities, and identify opportunitiesto work with those in higher-risk areas tohelp make their facilities safer. This includesworking with third-party suppliers to redesignand reconfigure factory floor plans where</P>
<P>necessary, implementing flexible working hoursto maximize interpersonal space, implementingenhanced deep cleaning protocols, anddeploying masks and sanitizers. In fiscal year2021, we also encouraged our suppliers’employees to get vaccinated and boostedwhere available.</P>
<P>We also partnered with NGOs to help furthersupport supplier employees, as well as thoseworking deeper in our supply chain, particularlythose from vulnerable groups. We worked withthe International Organization for Migration(IOM) — the world’s leading organizationproviding services to migrant workers — toprovide support to migrant workers impacted</P>
<P>by the pandemic. With support from Apple,our long-time partner Pact, an internationaldevelopment organization, prepared andcoordinated activities to prevent the spread ofCOVID-19 in several mining communities in theDemocratic Republic of the Congo (DRC). Theinitiative has reached more than 50,000 peoplethrough individual and group dialogues onCOVID-19 prevention since the program beganin December 2020.</P>
<H1>Giving back to our communities</H1>
<P>Apple’s company-wide response to theCOVID-19 pandemic involved teams acrossthe business, including product design,engineering, operations, packaging teams,suppliers, and more. At the beginning of thepandemic, when personal protective equipmentwas in short supply, we sourced through oursupply chain and donated more than 30 millionmasks for healthcare workers worldwide.We also launched a company-wide effort toproduce and ship over 10 million face shields.These face shields were delivered to sitesaround the world, from New York PresbyterianHospital in the U.S. to the Ministry of Healthin Zambia.</P>
<P>Additionally, we have also donated over</P>
<P>$10 million to the World Health Organization’sCOVID-19 Solidarity Response Fund. We alsomatched employee donations two-to-one tosupport COVID-19 response efforts worldwide.</P>
<P>We awarded $10 million from our AdvancedManufacturing Fund to COPAN diagnostics,a market leader in sample collection kits,that rapidly accelerated their ability to supplysample collection kits to hospitals in the U.S.for COVID-19 testing. And our partnershipwith Product (RED) also supported COVID-19response (seepage65).</P>
<P>In partnership with the White HouseCoronavirus Task Force and the CDC, wereleased an app and a website that guidedAmericans through a series of questions abouttheir health and exposure to determine if theyshould seek care for COVID-19 symptoms,providing CDC recommendations on nextsteps, including guidance on social distancingand self-isolating, how to closely monitor</P>
<P>symptoms, recommendations on testing,and when to contact a medical provider.And we collaborated with Google to create anew exposure notification system for globalgovernments and health agencies, with userprivacy and security central to its design, tohelp fight the pandemic.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_59.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Collaboration with our suppliers helps them make sure they’re taking every necessaryprecaution to keep people safe at work.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report33</P>
<H1>Health and safety at Apple</H1>
<P>We’re dedicated to protecting our teammembers and our customers everywherewe operate — a responsibility COVID-19 hasbrought into even greater focus. At everystage of the pandemic, we’ve made decisionsbased on the latest local data and public healthguidance, and we share lessons across ourEnvironment, Health, and Safety (EHS) teamsglobally so we can continuously improve oursafety programs.</P>
<H2>Protecting our people</H2>
<P>We’re always working hard to make sure ourworkers are safe no matter where they arewhen they’re conducting business for Apple.We abide by EHS requirements in every countrywhere we operate and are dedicated to doingeverything we can to support the safety andwell-being of our global teams.</P>
<P>Managing work-related hazards and risks</P>
<P>To help ensure the safety of our workers andcustomers, we put procedures in place toidentify workplace risks and mitigate possiblehazards. We support and protect employeesin lower hazard spaces, and we put risk-specific programs in place for those workingin higher hazard environments, including safesystems of work, chemical management,laser safety, equipment and machinery safety,hazardous materials management, andelectrical safety. Employees can request tohave their workspaces individually inspectedto review hazards and controls, includingergonomics evaluations.</P>
<P>Apple implements a hierarchy of controlfor significant risks, which centers onelimination, substitution, engineering controls,administrative controls, and personal protectiveequipment (PPE).</P>
<P>As one example, Apple EHS regularly assesseshazards at our research labs based on theirchemical, equipment, laser, and other hazards.Approximately 9 percent of our labs areconsidered “complex,” meaning that theycontain high-hazard processes and equipment.These assessments help teams understandwhich EHS programs and controls must beput in place to mitigate risks. In 2021, Applecompleted hazard assessments in over 2500research labs globally.</P>
<P>Our EHS teams identify and provide teammembers with appropriate PPE for specifichazards. This PPE is provided at no cost andwith training on correct use. For example,our hearing conservation programs includeevaluation and control of occupationalexposures to noise, and hearing protection isavailable for processes, areas, and tasks withpotential high noise exposures. Additionally,EHS conducts mandatory health checks foremployees where they’re needed.</P>
<P>We invest in new technologies as we continueto manage potential risks across our operations,including our Apple-owned manufacturingsites. Our standards, programs, trainings,procedures, and other safeguards are managedby trained EHS professionals, and whererequired, we also translate EHS procedures intolocal languages for our team members.</P>
<P>Risks identified from incidents, injuries, andnon-routine events are addressed expeditiouslyto identify and implement appropriatecorrective and preventative actions, and weintegrate our learnings into future programdevelopment and training. Lessons learnedare routinely communicated across Apple’sEHS team and potentially affected operations,and they are used to inform updates to existingpolicies and procedures.</P>
<P>Employees and managers can report incidents,near-misses, and observations — includingnewly identified hazards and risks—throughan internal iOS app. Incident responses areaddressed by Apple’s EHS team through aconsistent process that connects employeeswith care and support, while identifyingcorrective actions where appropriate to preventfuture occurrences.</P>
<P>Waste management</P>
<P>Apple is committed to minimizing resourceuse and the associated generation of non-hazardous or hazardous waste. Wherepossible, Apple implements a waste hierarchyof prevention, waste reduction at the source,reuse of materials, recycling, energy recovery,and landfilling as a last resort.</P>
<P>We maintain our commitment to the safe andresponsible management of hazardous waste,both onsite and offsite. Any facility that doesnot meet our requirements is replaced byanother approved waste management facility.</P>
<P>We made progress in 2021 at sites aroundthe world:</P>
<P>U.S.:Thirteen of the Treatment, Storage, andDisposal Facilities (TSDFs) we utilize in the U.S.were audited in 2021 to confirm that the wasteis treated, recycled, or incinerated within thegoverning safety standards for health and theenvironment. Eight disposal facility reviewswere completed by vendors under Applemanagement, and we reviewed five other sitesvia third-party audit reports. At one of our majorresearch labs in Santa Clara Valley, the emptycontainer management program resulted in a3 percent reduction of lab debris for hazardouswaste streams.</P>
<P>United Kingdom:Through an internal initiativeto further strengthen waste management,product site-specific waste initiativesachieved a 97 percent diversion from landfilland a 0.4 tonnes of waste/1002, bothexceeding requirements.</P>
<P>Ireland:The Cork Campus is ECVP 2799 ZeroWaste to Landfill Certified annually and has hadno material landfilled in the past five years.</P>
<P>Ergonomics</P>
<P>In 2021, we continued to support our globalteam members working from home office,Apple office, and non-office settings.</P>
<P>The Apple ergonomics program is heavilyfocused on preventative measures to reducethe risk of work-related musculoskeletaldisorders (WMSDs). This includes ergonomicstraining sessions for our team members andproviding input into the purchase or designof work equipment, systems, and facilities toensure that they meet ergonomic standards toprovide the best levels of efficiency, comfort,health, and safety for anyone using them. Our</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report34</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_60.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>We’re always working hard to make sure our workers are safe no matter where they are whenthey’re conducting business for Apple.</P>
<P>ergonomics trainings and self-assessmentsupport are aimed at creating an awarenessof ergonomic risk factors for WMSDs, how toprevent them, and how to proactively requestfor adjustments to workstations.</P>
<P>We completed over 10,000 individual supportrequests for our team members working fromhome, along with those who returned to Appleoffices and Apple Store locations. Supportincluded tailored guidance and feedback,equipment recommendations, and 1:1 virtualor in-person assessments. In addition, over3000 employees participated in varioustraining sessions.</P>
<P>Our industrial, warehouse, and other non-office operations teams were supported withapproximately 400 ergonomic risk assessmentsand 76 lab screenings. The assessmentsevaluated risk factors such as repetition,force, posture, and duration, while reviewingthe interaction of the team member withnew machines, equipment, work processes,and workspaces.</P>
<P>Emergency preparedness and response</P>
<P>Beyond COVID-19, we supported the responseto dozens of crisis events in 2021, includingfires, severe weather, and civil unrest. Ourresponses focused on the safety of ouremployees and business continuity. Weactivated 31 crisis management teams (CMTs)to manage the most severe events, and 120additional incidents were supported withoutfull CMTs.</P>
<P>All team members can sign up for Apple’sEmergency Alert system, enabling them to benotified of local emergencies and to indicatewhether they are safe or need help. Disastersupplies are available at our facilities. All Applecampuses with over 1000 employees haveFacility Response and Recovery Plans, whichprovide a comprehensive approach to the safetyand support of our employees while minimizingbusiness interruption. Site-specific EmergencyResponse Plans have been implementedglobally. These plans are communicated to allemployees, and trainings and drills are held atleast annually. And our employees are trainedin emergency response, allowing them to reactquickly while supporting the safety of our teammembers and customers.</P>
<P>In 2021, we completed over 200 emergencyresponse drills, which were supported by2700 trained Emergency Response Team(ERT) members. We expect to increase thefrequency of these drills, depending onCOVID-19 restrictions.</P>
<P>With the care and support of our employeesand customers in mind, we deployed AutomaticExternal Defibrillator (AED) stations acrossour global retail stores in 2021. And to ensurethat our team members could effectively usethis new tool, we provided AED training for ourteam members.</P>
<P>All campuses and key sites have disaster suppliesto match localized risks. As Apple’s footprintgrows, sites are evaluated and supplies areadded as needed. As one example, in 2021, welaunched earthquake preparedness campaignsfor employees across the western United Statesand Japan. We conducted outreach to provideemployees with information, tools, and resources,and we held drills in some offices.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>Our People</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report35</P>
<H1>EHS management systems</H1>
<P>To provide a safe and sustainable environmentfor our teams, our EHS programs are built toshare information about risks, requirements,and expectations for all workers.</P>
<P>Our EHS policy outlines our commitmentto workplace safety and environmentalstewardship, and it establishes the principlesthat integrate effective EHS practices into allaspects of our business. The EHS policy iscommunicated through mandatory trainingfor all new employees and through ourinternal EHS website.</P>
<P>Apple’s EHS leadership team, including Apple’sEHS director, is responsible for establishingpriorities, determining annual work plans, andassigning resources to implement high-qualityservices in all geographies where we operate.</P>
<P>Certifications</P>
<P>Our operations in Cork, Ireland, are certifiedto ISO14001, an international standard forenvironmental management systems. AndApple’s Taiwan Technology Center is certifiedto ISO45001 for occupational health and safetymanagement systems, and working towardISO14001 certifications in 2022.</P>
<P>Inspections</P>
<P>Our EHS inspections serve to both identifypotential safety hazards and ensure that we’refollowing our internal processes to mitigatethem. To support this work, Apple formalizedour existing inspections program by launchingenterprise-wide software, which allows usersto create mobile inspections and then carry outinspections and safety compliance audits. Thetool also captures observations, findings, andcorrective actions.</P>
<P>Our inspections tool was deployed globallyto 1050 users across various retail andcorporate locations, including Apple Storelocations, general office spaces, R&amp;D labs,kitchens and cafés, data centers, constructionsites, and laser labs.</P>
<P>Training</P>
<P>In 2021, Apple employees completed 68,249hours of safety training. Apple currentlyoffers 304 safety courses or trainings toour employees.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_61.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Our EHS management systems are designed to provide a safe environment for teamsacross Apple.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironmentIntroduction</P>
<H1>Values thatlead the way.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report36</P>
<H2>Suppliers</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Our approach</P>
<P>37</P>
<P>Labor and human rights in the supply chain40</P>
<P>Health, safety, and wellnessResponsible materials sourcingEducation and professional developmentEnvironment</P>
<P>43</P>
<P>44</P>
<P>45</P>
<P>46</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report37</P>
<H1>People are at the center of everything we do and every decision we make. While thepandemic has changed some of the ways we do our work, our values remain the same.The partnerships we have cultivated over the years throughout our supply chain haveallowed us to continue to make significant progress in upholding the highest standardsof labor and human rights and worker health and safety, and make unprecedentedachievements in climate action and the stewardship of natural resources. Yet, as proudas we are of our progress, we know each year and each achievement is just a steppingstone in our continuous pursuit of “better.”</H1>
<H1>Our approach</H1>
<P>Our commitment to people and the planetextends across our supply chain — frommanufacturing to services, and to the manyplaces where our suppliers operate. We workclosely with our suppliers to uphold the higheststandards so that the people in our supplychain are safe and treated with respect, andthe environment is protected everywhere thatApple products are made.</P>
<P>Apple’s work in this space is led by Applesenior management. Sabih Khan is Apple’sSenior Vice President of Operations, reportingto COO Jeff Williams. Sabih is in charge ofApple’s global supply chain, product quality,and overseeing planning, procurement,manufacturing, logistics, and product fulfillmentfunctions — the programs that support Apple’sEnvironment and Supply Chain Innovation work.</P>
<P>The Operations team also supports Apple’s</P>
<P>environmental initiatives by partnering with</P>
<P>suppliers to propel green manufacturing, help</P>
<P>conserve resources, and protect the planet.</P>
<H2>Holding ourselves and our suppliers</H2>
<H2>to the highest standards</H2>
<P>As described onpage 10, ourHuman Rights</P>
<P>Policyoutlines how we treat everyone, includingour customers, employees, business partners,</P>
<P>and people at every level of our supply chain.</P>
<P>We take a very broad view of our supply</P>
<P>chain (see diagram onpage 38) — and the</P>
<P>responsibility that comes with it. We consider</P>
<P>our supply chain to include everything that</P>
<P>goes into designing, building, delivering,</P>
<P>supporting, and recycling of Apple products,</P>
<P>as well as our retail stores and all of the services</P>
<P>and operations that are part of our supply</P>
<P>chain ecosystem.</P>
<P>The AppleSupplier Code of ConductandSupplier Responsibility Standardsoutline ourrequirements for our suppliers in the areasof labor and human rights, health and safety,environment, ethics, and management systems.Since 2005, the Code and Standards havebeen updated annually, are published on ourwebsite in 15 languages, and communicated toour suppliers.</P>
<P>The requirements in our Supplier Code ofConduct and Supplier Responsibility Standardsand the due diligence we conduct acrossour supply chain align with internationallyrecognized labor and human rights standards,including those of the International LabourOrganization (ILO), the United Nations GuidingPrinciples on Business and Human Rights(UNGPs), the Organisation for Economic</P>
<P>Co-operation and Development (OECD),as well as industry-leading health andsafety organizations.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_62.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_63.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>Learn more about SupplierResponsibility at Apple</H2>
<P>We publicly share our progress througha number of reports, available on ourSupplier Responsibility site:</P>
<L><LI>2022 Annual People and Environmentin Our Supply Chain Progress Report</LI>
</L>
<P>How We Work with SuppliersConflict Minerals ReportSupplier List</P>
<P>Smelter and Refiner List</P>
<L><LI>2021 Efforts to Combat HumanTrafficking and Slavery</LI>
</L>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report38</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_65.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>The Apple Supply Chain</H2>
<P>A global network of people andbusinesses working together tobuild the best products in the world.</P>
<P>Recycling</P>
<P>Design &amp; engineering</P>
<P>Primary materials</P>
<L><LI>3 million+</LI>
</L>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_64.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>people</P>
<P>52</P>
<P>Thousands</P>
<P>of businesses and facilities</P>
<P>countries</P>
<P>Services</P>
<P>Services</P>
<P>Retail stores</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_66.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Final assembly</P>
<P>Smelter&amp; refiner</P>
<P>Components</P>
<P>Logistics</P>
<P>We also extend our support to help prospectivesuppliers correct compliance issues foundduring the procurement process — even whenthe supplier is not awarded Apple’s business— at no cost to the participating companies.Since 2020, 68 percent of companies that werenot awarded Apple business elected to join thisvoluntary program, helping to protect people andthe planet beyond the reach of our business andsupply chain.</P>
<P>OurPeople and Environment in Our SupplyChain Report(page 99) provides a detailedoverview of progress in our supply chain,including efforts to identify, mitigate, prevent,and remedy human rights risks as outlined bythe Business and Human Rights Due Diligenceprocess set forth in the UNGPs.</P>
<P>We work closely with many experts acrossApple — from product and services designersto facility managers — to evaluate andupdate our Code and Standards annually toaddress emerging risks, incorporate new legalrequirements and industry best practices, andreflect the needs of supplier employees in adynamic operating environment. We engage</P>
<P>with a range of stakeholders, including rights-holders, civil society organizations, academicexperts, and program partners, to ensure</P>
<P>that our Code and Standards reflect currentinternationally recognized labor, human rights,health and safety, and environmental standards.</P>
<H3>Upholding our values from the start</H3>
<P>We work across our business to implement ourstandards from the earliest stages of productdesign and development — from the supplierswe choose to work with, to the materials in ourproducts, to the processes and equipment weuse to make them. We take a comprehensiveapproach to identifying and mitigating risks early</P>
<P>in the procurement and product developmentcycles. Since fiscal year 2020, 9 percent ofprospective suppliers evaluated for Code-related risks have been prevented from enteringour supply chain for being unable or unwilling tomeet our Code and Standards.</P>
<P>Once new suppliers are awarded Applebusiness, we begin the process of helping themquickly get up to speed on our requirementsthrough our supplier onboarding process.In 2021, we expanded our onboarding processto engage new suppliers at an even earlierstage in their working relationship with Apple.</P>
<H3>Supplier engagementand accountability</H3>
<P>We take a broad, comprehensive approachto engaging with our suppliers to confirm thatour standards are met. One of the tools thatwe employ are assessments. Assessments,also known as audits, are one of severalmethods we use to measure compliance</P>
<P>with our requirements. These independent,third-party assessments, which take placeonsite at supplier facilities, provide a snapshotof a supplier’s performance. However, whencombined with regular engagement withsupplier teams, mandated reporting, andlistening directly to hundreds of thousandsof supplier employees about their workplaceexperiences, our rigorous supplier assessmentsprovide a clear measure of their performance inupholding our Code and Standards.</P>
<P>In the 2021 reporting period, 1177 assessmentswere conducted in 52 countries. This included886 Code of Conduct assessments and 291smelter and refiner assessments.20Since 2007,Apple-managed assessments have covered94 percent of our direct manufacturing spend.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report39</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_68.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>How we stay engaged with suppliers</H1>
<P>Code of conductassessments</P>
<P>Earlyengagement</P>
<P>Specializedassessments</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_67.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Ongoingtraining</P>
<P>Investigations</P>
<P>Capability building</P>
<P>been taken to prevent a reoccurrence. Weprohibit retaliation of any kind against supplieremployees who participate in our assessments.</P>
<P>Our goal is to work together with suppliers tohelp them improve their management systems,rather than to simply remove them from oursupply chain without helping them correct theissues we have discovered. In the event that asupplier is unwilling or unable to improve theiroperations to meet our requirements, they riskremoval from our supply chain. Since 2009, wehave directed the removal of 24 manufacturingsupplier facilities and 170 smelters and refinersfrom our supply chain for being unwilling orunable to sufficiently improve their operationsto meet our requirements.</P>
<P>Results of our assessments are detailed in ourPeople and Environment in Our Supply ChainReportbeginning on page 91.</P>
<H2>A responsibility thatgrows with our business</H2>
<P>As Apple’s business continues to grow andexpand to new areas, we adapt our supplierengagement model accordingly. This includescontinuing to expand our scope to conductindependent, third-party assessments of agrowing number of suppliers that supportour business outside of manufacturing. Lastyear, we increased our engagement andexpanded the application of our Code andStandards to suppliers supporting newer areasof Apple’s business, including those that workwith our content services like Apple TV+ andApple Fitness+.</P>
<P>These assessments also include unannouncedassessments and unannounced visitsin response to workers’ grievances andallegations, or to verify risks at supplier facilitiesbased on predictive analytics. In fiscal year2021, 211 unannounced assessments andinvestigations were conducted where thesupplier facility was provided no advance noticeof our arrival. This is nearly double the numberconducted in 2020.</P>
<P>In addition to third-party Code of Conductassessments, we require many of our suppliersto also undergo the Responsible BusinessAlliance’s (RBA) Validated Assessment Program(VAP), a facility-wide, third-party assessment</P>
<P>widely used by the industry. A total of 99 RBAVAP assessments were completed in fiscal year2021 at Apple supplier sites.</P>
<P>If we uncover non-compliance in the courseof any assessment or engagement, we takeprompt action so that suppliers not only correctand remedy the issue, but make meaningful,long-term changes to their systems andprocesses. We do this through a CorrectiveAction Plan (CAP), during which 30-, 60-, and90-day check-ins with Apple are required.We then conduct our Corrective ActionVerification (CAV) process to verify that allcorrective actions have been successfullyimplemented, and necessary steps have</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_69.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Supplier employees at Final Assembly in the U.S.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report40</P>
<H2>Partnerships that accelerate progress</H2>
<P>We are collaborating with industry associations,</P>
<P>civil society organizations, and multi-</P>
<P>stakeholder initiatives around the world to</P>
<P>promote best practices, to listen to and learn</P>
<P>from others’ perspectives and experiences, and</P>
<P>to scale innovative solutions, helping everyone</P>
<P>to achieve progress at a more rapid pace. See</P>
<P>page 32 of thePeople and Environment in Our</P>
<P>Supply Chain Reportfor more detail on theorganizations we work with.</P>
<H1>Labor and human rightsin the supply chain</H1>
<P>People come first in everything we do. Ourcommitment to protecting the people in oursupply chain has been unwavering, anchoredby a simple set of beliefs: People deserve to betreated with dignity and to know their rights.They should be able to speak up if those rightsare not being respected — and to know andexpect that when they do, we will listen and act.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_70.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>We are committed to respecting the rights ofevery individual in our supply chain — just likewe do for our team members, customers, andother partners — and more broadly, to workingwith others to share our tools and the lessonswe’ve learned, and to empowering everyone toachieve progress more rapidly.</P>
<H2>Listening to workers</H2>
<P>Effective grievance channels, ongoing workermanagement communications, and supplieremployee feedback are essential to ensuringrespect for worker rights and maintainingsafe and healthy workplaces. Whetherthrough social dialogue and formal employeerepresentation, workplace satisfactionsurveys, anonymous hotlines, focus groups,or interviews during annual assessments, thefeedback we receive directly from supplieremployees helps us ensure labor and humanrights are respected throughout our globalsupply chain. We also use this feedbackto address emerging risks, improve rightstraining for supplier employees and suppliermanagement, and to continually strengthen ourCode and Standards.</P>
<L><LI>•Rights awareness:We believe thatprotection starts with rights awareness,and since 2008, more than 23.6 millionsupplier employees have been trained ontheir workplace rights. Under our Code andStandards, suppliers are required to provideemployees with training on their workplacerights. This training is generally conductedduring new employee orientation, andcovers international labor standards, locallabor laws, environmental health and safety,and the protections required by our Codeand Standards</LI>
</L>
<P>•Feedback channels:Supplier employeeinterviews are an important part of everyassessment conducted. Each year, weinterview tens of thousands of supplieremployees in their local language andwithout their managers present, to determinewhether or not their experience on the jobaligns with auditors’ observations duringassessments. In fiscal year 2021, despitethe ongoing challenges presented bythe COVID-19 pandemic, we interviewed87,626 workers in our supply chain — over35,000 more than were interviewed in theprevious fiscal year.</P>
<P>Our Code and Standards require effectiveworker feedback channels, includinggrievance mechanisms, at all supplier sites.We also provide third-party anonymoushotlines, which are also available to ouremployees (seepage 72), and the ability tocontact the Apple Environment and SupplyChain Innovation (ESCI) team directly at anytime and in any language. When an issue israised, we require supplier management toimmediately investigate and to resolve theissue in a timely manner.</P>
<P>In 2021, we launched a grievance hotlineawareness campaign, and its initial rolloutresulted in a 22 percent increase in utilizationof these third-party hotlines. The reportswe received from supplier employees viahotlines in 2021 included issues related towages and benefits, employee relations,amenities at supplier facilities, workforcestability, and health and safety. In each case,we investigated and worked directly with thesuppliers to drive improvement and correctany compliance issues found. Suppliersimplemented a number of actions as a resultof supplier employee feedback through these</P>
<P>We’re committed to respecting the rights of every individual in our supply chain.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report41</P>
<P>channels, including improvements to workinghours, resignation processes, timing ofbonuses, and the use of personal protectiveequipment (PPE).</P>
<L><LI>•Workplace satisfaction:In addition tointerviews and grievance channels, we</LI>
</L>
<P>also engage with supplier employeesto understand their overall workplacesatisfaction. In 2021, we anonymouslysurveyed 264,963 supplier employees in191 facilities across Greater China, India,Ireland, Malaysia, Philippines, Singapore,UK, U.S., and Vietnam about their workplaceexperiences — nearly double the number ofsupplier employees surveyed last fiscal year.As a result, suppliers took 3944 actions,including better commute options, increasingwages and bonuses, offering better foodvariety, and skill development opportunitiesfor entry-level managers.</P>
<H2>Responsible labor recruitment</H2>
<P>Our Code and Standards, and the protectionsthey provide, apply equally to all workers,regardless of a person’s job, geographiclocation, or how they enter our supply chain— and this commitment begins even beforea worker ever enters our supply chain. Thisincludes zero tolerance for forced labor.</P>
<P>We implement strict policies and procedureswith our suppliers to protect workers in oursupply chain from forced labor. This includesselecting suppliers for assessments basedon factors, such as their geographic location,which may put them at higher risk of forcedlabor violations, as well as their previousperformance and/or history of violations orallegations. Suppliers may also receive additionalspecialized assessments based on the natureof their business or employee population, suchas those that employ Foreign Contract Workers,and those located in higher risk migrationcorridors. Our Code and Standards also requirethat all supplier employees have an effectivemechanism to report grievances. In addition,we provide third-party anonymous hotlines andthe ability to contact the Apple Environment andSupply Chain Innovation (ESCI) team directly atany time and in any language. When an issueis raised, supplier management is required topromptly investigate and to resolve the issue in atimely manner.</P>
<P>We strictly prohibit any form of involuntary laborthroughout our worldwide supply chain and lookfor evidence of it in every supplier assessmentwe conduct, including unannouncedassessments. Last year, we conducted morethan 1100 assessments, and found no instanceswhere anyone was forced to work in oursupply chain.</P>
<P>We did discover two cases in Taiwan in whichpeople paid recruitment fees to secure theirjob, which is a violation of our Code. Werequired the supplier to directly repay theiremployees in full, and verified repaymentthrough a third-party auditor. The payment ofrecruitment fees, withholding an employee’spassport or personal identity documents,or restricting an employee’s freedom ofmovement are Core Violations of our Codeand Standards — the most serious level ofCode violations. If we discover workers havepaid recruitment fees at any point on theiremployment journey to an Apple supplier, werequire supplier management to take promptaction to provide remedy to those affectedby directly repaying their workers for any andall fees, even if the supplier was unawarethat their employees had paid recruitmentfees. From 2008 through fiscal year 2021,our suppliers have repaid $33.2 million inrecruitment fees directly to 37,322 workers.</P>
<P>Finally, in collaboration with the InternationalOrganization for Migration (IOM) and theResponsible Business Alliance (RBA), weexpanded our Responsible Labor RecruitmentToolkit to more than 39 additional supplierfacilities in 10 countries, reaching nearly 77,000workers globally, with 66 percent of thoseworking on Apple production lines.</P>
<H1>23.6M</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_71.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<TOC><TOCI>supplier employees trained on theirrights since 2008</TOCI>
</TOC>
<H1>352,589</H1>
<P>supplier employees directly engaged abouttheir workplace experiences, throughinterviews and satisfaction surveys</P>
<H1>220,000</H1>
<P>supplier employees reached by grievancehotline awareness campaign</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<H4>Suppliers</H4>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report42</P>
<H1>How wework toprevent forcedlabor in oursupply chain</H1>
<H2>Apple has zero tolerance for forcedlabor. In the more than 50 countriesand regions where our suppliersoperate, we have teams of experts,including independent third parties,who monitor our suppliers and put inplace industry-leading proceduresto help ensure that no one is forcedto work. Our comprehensive policiesstart before we even sign a contractwith suppliers, and we are consistentlyraising the bar.</H2>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_72.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_73.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>1</H4>
<H3>We set the highest standards.</H3>
<H4>Eliminating forced labor begins with settingand maintaining the highest standards. Ourstandards often go above and beyond legalrequirements to protect people from forcedlabor risks.</H4>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_74.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>Aligning with international frameworks.</H4>
<P>Apple policies and our supplier requirements align withinternational labor and human rights standards, including thoseof the International Labour Organization, the United NationsGuiding Principles on Business and Human Rights (UNGPs), andthe Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_75.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>The Apple Human Rights Policy</H4>
<P>Our Human Rights Policy outlines how we treat everyone,including our customers, employees, business partners,and the people across every level of our supply chain.</P>
<P>Read the Apple Human Rights Policy</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_76.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>The Apple Supplier Code of Conduct and SupplierResponsibility Standards</H4>
<P>Our supplier requirements contain strict standards forresponsible labor recruitment, and apply to all suppliers,protecting workers globally. We go above and beyond legalrequirements in many places by strictly prohibiting laborrecruitment in regions where we cannot conduct adequatedue diligence and by maintaining a zero recruitment fees policy,because we believe no one should pay to secure a job.</P>
<P>Read the Apple Supplier Code of Conductand Supplier Responsibility Standards</P>
<H3>2We engage early.</H3>
<H4>To address forced labor risks at its roots,we know that our work has to begin beforepeople enter our supply chain.</H4>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_77.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_78.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<L><LI>Thorough mapping informs our strategy.</LI>
</L>
<P>An effective strategy requires deep understanding of oursupply chain. To date, we have mapped over 1000 laborrecruitment agencies that work with our suppliers across32 countries.</P>
<H4>A leading strategy requires leading tools.</H4>
<P>The Apple Responsible Labor Recruitment Toolkit, developedin partnership with the International Organization forMigration, provides suppliers and their labor agencies witheasy-to-use tools that help them effectively manage andreport data, mitigating forced labor risks before people evenenter our supply chain. In addition to providing hands-ontraining, we are making these tools openly available for othersto use.</P>
<H4>Awareness is power.</H4>
<P>We require our suppliers to provide their employees withtraining on their workplace rights on their first day on thejob. This helps to ensure that every person is aware of</P>
<P>their rights and what to do if they’re not being respected,which includes the ability to anonymously contact Appledirectly. Foreign Contract Workers, who make up a verysmall percentage of people in our supply chain, also receivetraining prior to leaving their home country, as well as uponarriving in their destination country. To date, our suppliershave provided workplace rights training to over 23.6 millionpeople. In addition, last year we directly engaged with over350,000 people in our supply chain to learn more about theirworkplace experience.</P>
<H4>Investing in consistent improvement.</H4>
<P>Through our new Supplier Employee Development Fund,we’re investing $50M to expand programs designedto continue to improve the rights training experience,worker voice platforms, and supplier employee educationopportunities.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_79.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_80.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_81.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H3>3We hold suppliers accountable.</H3>
<H4>Once we’ve implemented thoroughpreventative measures, independent,third-party assessments verify that oursuppliers are meeting our standards.Looking for evidence of forced labor is partof every supplier assessment. If we find anyviolations of our Code and Standards, wetake swift action to remedy the issue andimprove their operations.</H4>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_82.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>A close look.</H4>
<P>We regularly conduct independent, third-party assessments,including surprise assessments, of our suppliers, verifyingcompliance with over 500 points across our standards. Thisincludes an extensive document review to be sure all hiringand personnel records are in place and accurate. In additionto specialized forced labor assessments for at-risk suppliers,we also require many suppliers to participate in facility-wideassessments, such as the Validated Assessment Program,to verify performance across the supplier’s entire business.In the event that we find gaps in a supplier’s complianceor capabilities, we require them to implement a CorrectiveAction Plan. To date, our assessments have covered 94percent of our direct manufacturing spend.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_83.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<L><LI>We investigate every report.</LI>
</L>
<P>In addition to thoroughly assessing our suppliers’ performancein upholding our standards, we also receive reports from thepress, governments, civil society, and people in our supplychain, and we encourage the public to report concerns viahttps://www.apple.com/uk/supplier-responsibility/.Weinvestigate every report, and frequently have Apple teamsonsite within 24 hours.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_84.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>Swift action and steep penalties.</H4>
<P>Forced labor in any form is a Core Violation (the most serious</P>
<P>violation level) of our requirements. If a Core Violation is</P>
<P>discovered, the supplier’s CEO is notified and the supplier</P>
<P>is immediately placed on probation, pending the successful</P>
<P>completion of a Corrective Action Plan. Probation can include</P>
<P>no new projects, no new business, and termination of existing</P>
<P>business. In addition to commercial penalties, if a supplier is</P>
<P>unable or unwilling to meet our standards, they risk removal</P>
<P>from our supply chain. Since 2009, we have directed the</P>
<P>removal of 24 manufacturing supplier facilities and 170</P>
<P>smelters and refiners for failure to meet our requirements.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_85.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>Action this year.</H4>
<P>In FY21, across more than 1100 assessments, we foundno instances where anyone was forced to work in our</P>
<P>supply chain. We did find two cases where employees ofthe same supplier in Taiwan paid recruitment fees. Per ourrequirements, the supplier directly repaid their employees forthose fees. To date, our suppliers have directly repaid $33.2Min recruitment fees to 37,322 of their employees.</P>
<P>4We track progress</P>
<P>and report transparently.</P>
<H4>Consistent improvement requirestransparency and accountability. Since2007, we have been publishing reportson our efforts across all of our workto transparently share our progressand challenges.</H4>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_86.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_87.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_88.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_89.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>People and Environment in Our SupplyChain Annual Progress Report</H4>
<P>Published annually since 2007 (formerly known as theSupplier Responsibility Progress Report), this report containsa detailed accounting of our progress, challenges, and future</P>
<P>plans across all areas of our supplier requirements.Read our Annual Progress Report</P>
<H4>Efforts to Combat Human Traffickingand Slavery Disclosure</H4>
<P>This disclosure is a specialized filing that focuses specificallyon our efforts to prevent and address forced labor risksthroughout our supply chain, and includes our due diligenceprocess for our entire business, including manufacturing,materials and goods sourcing, and services. This reportalso demonstrates our alignment with the UNGPs and meets</P>
<P>regulatory requirements in the UK, Australia, and California.Read our disclosure</P>
<H4>Consistently raising the bar.</H4>
<P>We revisit all of our supplier requirements every year,consistently raising the bar that suppliers must meet in orderto continue doing business with us, and publish the updatespublicly.</P>
<P>Read the Apple Supplier Code of Conduct and SupplierResponsibility Standards</P>
<H4>Take a closer look.</H4>
<P>We publish additional reports that provide a transparent lookat our supply chain. Our Conflict Minerals Report describesour work to responsibly source materials. Our Smelter andRefiner List publishes a list of all identified tin, tungsten,tantalum, gold (3TG), cobalt, and lithium smelters and refinersacross our global supply chain, and the Apple Supplier Listshares the companies and their locations that comprise at</P>
<P>least 98 percent of our direct manufacturing spend.Read our disclosures</P>
<P>5We regularly engage and</P>
<P>partner with stakeholders.</P>
<H4>Engagement with stakeholders and rightsholders is critical to accountability, ensuringwe’re taking action where it’s needed, and toachieving rapid progress.</H4>
<L><LI>The International Labour Organization (ILO)</LI>
</L>
<P>We work closely with the ILO on a number of projects,including those related to rights and advancing workervoice. Apple is a member of the ILO Global BusinessNetwork on Forced Labor, and serves on the steeringcommittee.</P>
<L><LI>The International Organization for Migration (IOM)</LI>
</L>
<P>Apple partners with the IOM on multiple initiatives,including the development of our Responsible LaborRecruitment Toolkit and training our suppliers onthe Toolkit.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_90.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>Responsible Business Alliance (RBA)</H4>
<P>Apple collaborates with the RBA and its membercompanies frequently throughout the year on initiativesspanning the entirety of our program. As a full member,we serve in several leadership capacities, includingserving on the board of directors, being a founding andsteering committee member of the Responsible LaborInitiative, and serving on the steering committee of theResponsible Minerals Initiative.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_91.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_92.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H4>Responsible Labor Initiative (RLI)</H4>
<P>Apple is a founding member and serves on the steeringcommittee of RLI, which was established by the RBA asa multi-industry, multi-stakeholder initiative focused onensuring that the rights of workers vulnerable to forcedlabor in global supply chains are consistently respectedand promoted.</P>
<H4>Fund for Global Human Rights</H4>
<P>Apple partners with the Fund to support grassrootsactivists, as well as human rights and environmentaldefenders, which empowers local voices.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report43</P>
<H2>Health, safety, andwellness</H2>
<P>Everyone has the right to a safe and healthyworkplace. We work from the earliest stagesof product design to ensure that the materials,machines, and processes used in themanufacturing of our products prioritize thehealth and safety of the people working in oursupply chain.</P>
<H3>Building a culture of safety</H3>
<P>Among many topics, our Code and Standardscover the safe handling of chemicals,emergency preparedness, health and safetypermits, living and working conditions, andincident management. Health and safety isalso an important part of every assessment weconduct. Any instances of noncompliance withour Code and Standards during an assessmentare addressed through customized CorrectiveAction Plans, online training materials, andcapability building with EHS experts in orderto improve their future performance. In 2021,we began development of a safety cultureguide to help suppliers cultivate a deeper, moresustainable culture of safety in their facilities.</P>
<H3>Health and wellness</H3>
<P>Beyond keeping people in our supply chainsafe, we’re committed to creating workplaceswhere people can thrive. This means giving oursupplier employees the tools and resources toimprove their physical and mental health andwell-being.</P>
<P>Since 2017, we’ve helped make healtheducation and resources available to more than2.95 million supplier employees on topics such</P>
<P>as reproductive health, disease prevention,and nutrition. In 2021, we conducted a needsassessment to give supplier employees anopportunity to share their feedback, and weare updating our resources with those resultsin mind.</P>
<H3>Safeguarding healththrough safer chemistry</H3>
<P>Our commitment starts with setting andupholding strict material safety standardsthat often go beyond regulatory requirementsin order to protect human health and theenvironment. These are outlined in our Codeand Standards and our Regulated SubstancesSpecification (RSS), and are derived frominternational laws or directives, regulatoryagencies, eco-label requirements, andenvironmental standards. We then go further,by intentionally designing our productsand manufacturing processes to use safermaterials, as well as verifying that the correcthealth and safety protocols are being usedacross our supply chain. And we’re making animpact beyond our supply chain by workingwith others to help make the use of safermaterials the industry norm.</P>
<P>We received the U.S. Environmental ProtectionAgency’s (EPA) Safer Choice Partner of theYear Award for the second year in a row,in recognition of our leadership in saferchemistry. We’re also a founding signatoryof the Clean Electronics Production Network’s(CEPN) Toward Zero Exposure program,a public platform for companies across theelectronics industry to commit to and reporton their efforts to eliminate workers’ exposureto hazardous chemicals in manufacturing.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_96.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>We work from the earliest stages of product design to ensure that the materials, machines, and processes usedin the manufacturing of our products prioritize the health and safety of the people working in our supply chain.</P>
<H1>1000+</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_95.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>supplier facilities disclosed chemicaland safety data, representing themajority of Apple’s direct spend</P>
<H1>2nd Year</H1>
<P>receiving U.S. EPA Safer ChoicePartner of the Year Award</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_93.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_94.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>See more about our approach to smarterchemistry onpage 20and on page 54 of thePeople and Environment in Our SupplyChain Report</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report44</P>
<H2>Responsiblematerials sourcing</H2>
<P>From mapping our supply chain and assessingrisk, to conducting independent, third-partyaudits, engaging with civil society and industry,and investing heavily in innovation, upholdingstandards in the sourcing of materials isa responsibility that requires a strategic,comprehensive approach.</P>
<P>As we make progress toward our goal to useonly recycled and renewable minerals andmaterials in our products and packaging,we continue to source primary materials —including tin, tantalum, tungsten, and gold(3TG), and other minerals, such as cobalt— responsibly, while working to improveconditions in and around mining communities.</P>
<P>Our Responsible Sourcing of MaterialsStandard, part of our Code and Standards,covers all primary and recycled materials,including advanced and bio-based materials.Our standard aligns with leading internationalstandards, including the United Nations GuidingPrinciples on Business and Human Rights andthe Organisation for Economic Co-operationand Development’s Due Diligence Guidancefor Responsible Supply Chains of Minerals fromConflict-Affected and High-Risk Areas (OECDDue Diligence Guidance).</P>
<P>Every year, as part of our commitment totransparency, we publish a list of identified 3TG,cobalt, and — for the second year — lithiumsmelters and refiners in our supply chain.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_99.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>A placer miner holds gold sourced from Alaska and the Yukon as part of the Salmon Gold Project.Learn more on page 70 ofPeople and Environment in Our Supply Chain Report.</P>
<Div><Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_98.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H3>The first battery with100% responsiblysourced key minerals</H3>
<P>We also achieved an industry first</P>
<P>— a battery containing 100 percentresponsibly sourced key minerals,whether primary or recycled. In 2021,all identified cobalt and lithium refiners— key materials used to make batteriesfor all Apple products — participated inOECD-aligned independent, third-partyaudits covering labor, human rights,and environmental policies, as well asmanagement systems. We continue toconduct additional due diligence andcarry out OECD-aligned independent,third-party audits on other batterymaterials such as graphite, nickel,and copper.</P>
</Div>
<H1>100%</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_97.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>of identified 3TG, cobalt and lithiumsmelters and refiners participated inindependent, third-party audits</P>
<P>We also map other minerals in our productssuch as mica, copper, graphite, and nickel,and assess new materials for compliance withour requirements prior to production. In fiscalyear 2021, we conducted due diligence on 26recycled or bio-based materials to verify thattheir sourcing pathways met Apple’s standardsand expectations.</P>
<P>Also in fiscal year 2021, 100 percent of theidentified 3TG, cobalt, and lithium smelters andrefiners in our supply chain have participated inindependent, third-party audits to assess andidentify a broad range of risks, including social,environmental, human rights, and governancerisks. This marks seven consecutive yearsof 100 percent compliance for 3TG, sixconsecutive years for cobalt, and twoconsecutive years for lithium.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_101.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_100.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Read more on page 69 of ourPeople andEnvironment in Our Supply Chain Reportand in ourConflict Minerals Report</P>
<P>In the event that a smelter or refiner is unableor unwilling to meet our requirements, weremove them from our supply chain. Since2009, we have directed the removal of 163 3TGand 7 cobalt smelters and refiners from oursupply chain.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report45</P>
<H2>Using our purchasing power for good</H2>
<P>For Apple, our work to make our company more inclusive extends to how wechoose the businesses we work with. When contracting with suppliers, we use ourpurchasing power to increase diversity in our supply chain and change outdatednorms that hurt those who are underrepresented in their field or industry.</P>
<P>Apple’s award-winning Supplier Diversity program, established in 1993, activelyengages suppliers from historically underrepresented communities.</P>
<P>We have policies and procedures that require diverse supplier participation duringearly-stage sourcing, key performance indicators to measure company success,and diversity awareness trainings for our global sourcing team members and relatedApple business units.</P>
<P>In 2016, Apple was the first Silicon Valley–based company to be invitedinto the Billion Dollar Roundtable (BDR) in recognition of our long-standingcommitment to promoting diversity within our supplier base. BDR celebratescorporations that achieved spending of at least $1 billion with minority- andwoman-owned businesses.</P>
<P>In calendar year 2021, Apple spent over $7.1 billion with diverse suppliers around theworld. Our Supplier Diversity program offers support to participating suppliers andseeks active engagement in industry diversity leadership activities. For example,supplier development has been a long-standing commitment within Apple’s supplychain, which is facilitated internally and externally. Externally, we partner with majoruniversities to provide executive development and capacity building to key diversesuppliers. And we’re proud to have supported Michigan State University andHoward University on creating their first programs for diverse supplier development.</P>
<P>A highlight of 2021 was that for the first time we engaged diverse suppliersin North America in manufacturing accessories for some of Apple’s most well-known products.</P>
<P>We’re also promoting diversity in the companies with which we do business.For example, our agreements with our primary construction suppliers requirethe reporting of their efforts to include diverse subcontractors on all Apple-related projects.</P>
<P>As a result of our efforts, we were chosen as Corporation of the Year by the NationalMinority Supplier Development Council (NMSDC) in October 2021. This award isNMSDC’s highest honor to a major corporation for the utilization of ethnic minority-owned suppliers, specifically those with Asian-Indian, Asian-Pacific, Black,Hispanic/Latinx, and Indigenous owners.</P>
<H1>Education andprofessional development</H1>
<P>Through our global supply chain, we createopportunities for people around the world,including by helping to close skills gaps inmanufacturing, and by helping to prepareworkers across our supply chain for the jobsof today and tomorrow.</P>
<H2>Supplier Employee DevelopmentFund and Apple Education Hub</H2>
<P>In March 2022, we announced a $50 millionSupplier Employee Development Fund toamplify worker voice and expand access tolearning and skill development opportunitiesto more people in our supply chain and</P>
<P>surrounding communities. Part of thiscommitment will support new and expandedlabor programs reaching more than 3.5 millionsupplier employees in over 40 countries,aided by our strategic partners, including theInternational Labour Organization (ILO) and theInternational Organization for Migration (IOM).</P>
<P>As part of this fund, we also launched theApple Education Hub, informed by our previoussupplier employee learning and developmentprograms, which 5 million supplier employeeshave taken advantage of since 2008. Inpartnership with local educational institutionsand NGOs, the Apple Education Hub willprovide a scalable solution through virtual-first learning, to promote and develop theskills necessary for the future of work in oursupply chain and surrounding communities.With initial programming to begin in the</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_102.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple’s $50 million Supplier Employee Development Fund will expand access to learning opportunities and skillsdevelopment for people across its supply chain.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>AppendixGovernanceCommunities</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report46</P>
<P>U.S., China, India, and Vietnam, more than100,000 supplier employees will participatein new learning opportunities by 2023 — fromleadership training and technical certifications,to classes on coding, robotics, and advancedmanufacturing fundamentals.</P>
<H2>Internal leadershipand technical programs</H2>
<P>We work consistently to provide meaningfuleducational opportunities that enrich supplieremployees’ workplace experiences and provideopportunities to improve career paths. Over thepast five years, more than 5000 students haveparticipated in our Line Leader, AutomationTechnician, and general apprenticeshipprograms. These programs give participantsthe skills they need to pursue opportunities inhighly technical roles. In 2021, 5883 supplieremployees at 18 supplier sites participatedin technical training, including programs onrobotics, Computer Numerical Control (CNC)machines, and mobile device repair.</P>
<H2>Coding</H2>
<P>Since 2017, we’ve offered training to supplieremployees on Apple’s Swift coding language— a skill that is in high demand. In 2021, wecontinued to build on feedback from studentsand suppliers to refine our curriculum by addingmore opportunities for virtual learning whilemaintaining the quality and consistency ofthe programs.</P>
<H1>Environment</H1>
<P>Human rights and environmental protectionare inextricably linked. And we’re taking actionaccordingly. As we build products that enrichthe lives of people around the world, we havea profound responsibility to do so in a way thatminimizes our resource use while protecting thelocal environments and communities where weand our suppliers operate.</P>
<P>We work with our suppliers to help us addressour environmental commitments, including ourgoal to become carbon neutral by 2030 acrossour entire product footprint. Our Supplier EnergyEfficiency Program and Supplier Clean EnergyProgram both address direct and indirectemissions in our supply chain, while our SupplierClean Water and Zero Waste programs help toreduce resource usage.</P>
<P>In addition, our Code contains strictenvironmental protections, which require oursuppliers to understand and take active stepsto reduce their environmental impact while alsobecoming better stewards of the resourceswe all share and the communities in whichwe operate. Specifically, our Code addressesthe management of regulated substances,stormwater, wastewater, air emissions, waste,and noise, as well as pollution prevention,resource reduction, and obtaining necessaryenvironmental permits.</P>
<P>More detail about our environment work in thesupply chain is covered onpage 13, as well asinPeople and Environment in Our Supply ChainReportand theEnvironmental ProgressReport.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_103.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H2>Apple helps suppliers rapidly accelerate renewableenergy use around the world</H2>
<P>In April 2022, Apple announced that its suppliers more than doubled their useof clean power over the last year, with over 10 gigawatts operational today outof nearly 16 gigawatts in total commitments in the coming years. In 2021, theserenewable projects avoided 13.9 million metric tons of carbon emissions. Theprojects online today will support greenhouse gas reductions equivalent toremoving 3 million cars from the road for one year.</P>
<P>Apple is constantly working with its global supply chain to accelerate andsupport its transition to clean energy. As of March 2022, 213 of the company’smajor manufacturing partners have pledged to power all Apple production withrenewable electricity across 25 countries. The dozens of new commitmentsannounced this year will accelerate progress toward Apple’s 2030 goal tobecome carbon neutral across its entire supply chain.</P>
<P>Apple has invested in the 2300-acre IP Radian Solar project in Brown County, Texas.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironmentIntroduction</P>
<H1>Design thatempowers.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report47</P>
<H2>Customers</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Our approachPrivacyAccessibilityInclusive designEducationHealth</P>
<P>Caring for customers</P>
<P>48</P>
<P>48</P>
<P>50</P>
<P>52</P>
<P>53</P>
<P>54</P>
<P>55</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report48</P>
<P>At Apple, our North Star is creating technology that empowers people and enrichestheir lives. Teams across Apple are always innovating to make technology that’seven better for our users — that protects their right to privacy, that’s durable andresilient, and that’s inclusive and accessible for everyone. And wherever we meetour customers — online, over the phone, or in person — we’re committed to treatingeveryone with dignity and respect.</P>
<H1>We believe that technology should be a force for good in the world. It’s why wepartner with students and educators using technology to teach and learn in newways, and collaborate with doctors and researchers to uncover new insights that helppeople live healthier lives. Every day, we work to infuse the technology we make withthe values that define us.</H1>
<H1>Our approach</H1>
<P>Delivering exceptional products that enrichthe lives of our customers is core to Apple’sbusiness. We have enormous potential to helppeople use technology to overcome barriersto their goals, innovate to solve problems, andexpand access to critical needs like health andeducation. With our products and services,we’re uniquely positioned to both empowerour customers to take action as well as to drivepositive impact on some of the biggest issuesin our society today, including those addressedby the UN Sustainable Development Goals(seepage75).</P>
<P>Equally important, we have a responsibilityto manage the environmental footprint ofour products and services (seepage 13) andunderstand their impacts on customers’ rightsas set out in our Human Rights Policy. Acrossour products and services, we consider howwe respect human rights, including privacy,freedom of expression, non-discrimination,accessibility, health, education, a cleanenvironment, and safety. Our human rightsdue diligence (seepage 10) helps us identifyand manage salient human rights risks acrossour current portfolio, as well as look ahead tofast-evolving areas like machine learning andartificial intelligence (AI).</P>
<P>Responsibility for integrating privacy,accessibility, inclusion, education, and healthinto our products and services cuts acrossmany teams, including Hardware Engineering,Software Engineering, Hardware Technologies,Machine Learning and AI, and Environment,Policy and Social Initiatives.</P>
<P>Because we care about our customers, wealso have programs in place to understand andsupport their needs. We work to provide positivecustomer experiences as well as products</P>
<P>that are durable and can be used for years tocome. And when we design our products, we’refocused on making them safe for anyone whoassembles, uses, or recycles them.</P>
<H1>Privacy</H1>
<P>Privacy is a fundamental human right, andwe’re constantly innovating to give users moretransparency and control over their data. It’swhy we set the industry standard for minimizingdata collection and processing a user’s</P>
<P>data on-device, and build industry-leadingtransparency and controls into our technology.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report49</P>
<P>Hand in hand with the privacy of our users areour commitments to free expression and accessto information. Our products and services helpour customers learn, express their creativity,exercise their ingenuity, communicate privatelyand securely, and share information globally,whether by text message, audio, or signlanguage over FaceTime video.</P>
<H1>Designed for privacy</H1>
<P>Our products and services are built withinnovative privacy technologies and techniquesdesigned to minimize how much of your dataApple — or anyone else — can access. Theycontain features designed and implementedover decades to protect customers’ privacyand give them control over their information.</P>
<H1>Privacy and securityon the App Store</H1>
<P>To meet the highest standards for privacy,security, and content, all the apps in our AppStore agree to comply with our App StoreReview Guidelines.</P>
<P>These provide developers with clear andtransparent guidance on safety, performance,business, design, and legal issues, includingappeal rights. The guidelines help ensure thatthe apps offered on the App Store are safe,provide a good user experience, adhere toour rules on user privacy, and secure devicesfrom malware and threats.</P>
<P>Safari was the first browser to block third-party cookies by default as far back as 2003,and in 2017, Safari added Intelligent TrackingPrevention to further limit tracking whilestill enabling websites to function normally.</P>
<P>Random identifiers ensure that routescustomers take and the places they searchin Maps are not associated with their AppleID, and Messages and FaceTime are end-to-end encrypted, so Apple can’t eavesdrop onuser communications. Siri was designed fromthe very beginning in 2011 to not associatethe things that users say to Siri with theirApple ID, but instead uses a random identifiergenerated when a user first enables Siri. Thathas remained the same since then, and in2021, with newly introduced on-device speechrecognition, the audio of users’ Siri requestsis processed right on their iPhone or iPadby default.</P>
<P>Throughout the App Store ecosystem, wecontinue to add innovative new features thatadvance user privacy even further. PrivacyNutrition Labels require developers, includingApple, to report their data collection andprivacy practices in a standardized format. AndApp Tracking Transparency requires developersto obtain a user’s permission to track theirdata across apps or websites owned by othercompanies for use in advertising or shared withdata brokers.</P>
<P>Apple’s Privacy Policy ensures that privacyremains a top priority in all that we do. Oursuppliers are also obligated to apply our privacyprinciples via our contractual terms. We respectusers’ ability to know, access, change, transfer,restrict, and delete personal data, and westrive to collect the minimum amount of datanecessary to power our products and services.</P>
<P>Customers control what information is shared,where it’s shared, and when it’s backed up.We do not provide user information to anythird parties without a clear legal basis, andwe publish aTransparency Reportdetailinggovernment requests for customer data andapp removal.</P>
<P>Users can exercise their privacy rights atour dedicated Data and Privacy page,privacy.apple.com, where they can receivea copy of the personal data that Apple holds onthem across all of their interactions with us andrequest deletion or temporary deactivation oftheir account if they wish.</P>
<P>Apple is committed to delivering advertising in away that respects user privacy. Apple-deliveredads may appear on the App Store, Apple News,and Stocks depending on the jurisdiction.The Apple advertising platform does not trackusers, nor does it buy or share user personalinformation with other companies.</P>
<P>To continue raising awareness and educatingpeople on how to protect their personalinformation, on Data Privacy Day in January2021 we shared a report that illustrates howcompanies track user data across websitesand apps. And in June 2021 we shared anotherreport exploring how Apple’s security layersand the App Review process protect users andkeep them in control of their data.</P>
<H1>Privacy governance</H1>
<P>To keep privacy at the center of our work, wemaintain rigorous privacy standards for bothcustomer and employee data. Our Chief PrivacyOfficer reports to Apple’s Senior Vice Presidentand General Counsel, who chairs Apple’sPrivacy Steering Committee. The Committee</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_104.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Privacy Nutrition Labels: Product pages on the AppStore feature a section that provides developers’self-reported summaries of some of their</P>
<P>privacy practices in a simple, easy-to-read label.Learn more.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report50</P>
<P>sets privacy standards for teams across Appleand addresses or escalates privacy complianceissues. Its members include Apple’s SeniorVice President of Machine Learning and AIStrategy and Senior Vice President of SoftwareEngineering, and a cross-functional group ofsenior representatives from across the business.These standards are in turn implemented andassessed by our Privacy Compliance team,which works to continue to deliver on ourprivacy commitments across all personal datacollections. We’ve created a dedicated structurewith executive sponsors in each functional area,supported by privacy champions embedded ineach functional area and taking direction fromthe Privacy Compliance team.</P>
<P>The Audit and Finance Committee of theBoard of Directors regularly reviews Apple’sprivacy and data security risks, and discussesthem with management. The Committeereviews reports on privacy and data securitymatters, including updates on Apple’s privacyprogram, cybersecurity risks, risk management,and relevant legislative, regulatory, andtechnical developments.</P>
<P>We maintain currentISO 27001 and ISO 27018certifications that set user security standards,for which we undergo yearly audits.</P>
<P>Privacy and security training</P>
<P>We communicate privacy and securityguidelines with employees and strictly enforcesafeguards across the company. All employeestake annual training on business conduct,of which privacy is an essential component.Employees with access to customer data andpersonal information are required to undergoadditional privacy and security training. Formore information, visitApple’s Ethics andCompliancewebsite.</P>
<P>Privacy Impact Assessments</P>
<P>As part of our General Data ProtectionRegulation (GDPR) and human rights work, weundertake Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs)of our major products and services. Theseassessments also consider decision-makingthat relies on algorithmic systems and theimpact such decisions have on individuals andtheir rights. PIAs take into consideration howlaws affect privacy and assess any associatedrisks in the relevant jurisdictions where weoperate. PIA reviewers are also trained toidentify and highlight potential impacts tofreedom of expression. Apple regularlyengages with a wide range of civil societyrepresentatives globally on various privacy andfreedom of expression issues, including privacyby design and encryption.</P>
<P>Privacy inquiries</P>
<P>Privacy questions, concerns, or complaints canbe raised online or by calling our Apple supportnumber. Our Data Protection Officer is availablefor questions regarding the Privacy Policy orgeneral privacy practices.</P>
<H2>Embedding security and privacy</H2>
<P>We’ve spoken out, time and again, for strongencryption without backdoors, recognizingthat security is the foundation of privacy. Webuild security into our hardware, software,and services, including at the design anddevelopment phase, to provide users withmaximum security and a transparent userexperience, serving the ultimate goal of keepingpersonal information safe. And we’ve designedthe Secure Enclave — a dedicated secure</P>
<P>subsystem integrated into Apple hardware— to keep sensitive user data, like biometricinformation, secure.</P>
<P>As part of our commitment, our Apple SecurityBounty rewards researchers who discoverand share with us critical issues in our latestoperating systems and the techniques usedto exploit them.</P>
<P>Apple also uses administrative, technical, andphysical safeguards to protect users’ data,taking into account the nature of that informationand the threats posed. Apple employees whohandle personal information are only permittedto use approved software and collaborationtools. Our employees handling personal dataare required to undergo dedicated privacytraining, which is updated on an ongoing basisto take into account new laws and privacydevelopments. All our employees can raiseany privacy issues and questions with our</P>
<P>Data Protection Officer, who is mandated toraise any issues of concern to Apple’s PrivacySteering Committee.</P>
<P>When we become aware of a potentialdata security incident, we conduct promptinvestigations and analysis, providenotifications in a timely manner whennecessary, and determine what stepsto take in response.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_105.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Learn moreabout privacy at AppleReview privacy features</P>
<P>Control what you share</P>
<P>See how apps from Apple handle your data</P>
<H1>Accessibility</H1>
<P>At Apple, we believe technology can play apowerful role in helping people to create, learn,be more collaborative and independent, fosterdignity, and live out their dreams. Accessibilityis a human right. Nowhere is that more evidentthan in our work in accessibility.</P>
<P>Our work to make technology customizable tothe diverse needs of all our users has becomewidely known. For example, the2021 WebAIMsurvey(from the Institute for Disability Research,Policy, and Practice, Utah State University),which analyzed responses from over 1,500 usersaround the world who have a vision disability anduse a screen reader, shows that 71.9% of surveyrespondents use iPhone or iPad with Apple’sVoiceOver as their primary mobile platform.</P>
<P>Apple has also been repeatedly honoredfor our accessibility work, including mostrecently receiving aFCC Chair’s Award forAdvancement in Accessibilityfor iOS 14, whichadded a suite of accessibility features thathave particular importance in the context ofthe COVID-19 pandemic. These features —People Detection, VoiceOver Recognition,sign language prominence in FaceTime, andSound Recognition — have helped users withdisabilities navigate day-to-day life during theCOVID-19 pandemic.</P>
<P>Our passion and commitment to inclusion ledApple to recently join the Valuable 500and bedesignated “Iconic Partner for inclusive design.”The Valuable 500’s mission includes tangibleaction for disability inclusion, starting at the CEOlevel to grow investments in company culture,standards, recruitment, representation, andresearch worldwide.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report51</P>
<P>Apple promotes authentic and positiveportrayals of disability in films and series onApple TV+, includingCODA,See,El Deafo,andLittle Voice. Apple Original contentincludes audio descriptions in Dolby Atmosin nine languages, and closed captions andsubtitles for the deaf and hard of hearing inover 40 languages in all 100+ countries whereApple TV+ is available.</P>
<H1>Vision</H1>
<P>Our features for blind and low-vision usersinclude VoiceOver, an industry-leading screenreader that describes exactly what’s happeningon your device, and Zoom, a screen magnifierthat lets you enlarge the content you see onyour device. Magnifier, Apple’s built-in appfor iPhone and iPad, turns the camera into adigital magnifying glass to increase the size ofany physical object you point it at. The PeopleDetection feature in Magnifier uses camera,LiDAR Scanner, and on-device machinelearning to help support health and safety forusers who are blind or have low vision and needto maintain social distancing.</P>
<H1>Hearing</H1>
<P>Tosupport customers who are deaf or hard ofhearing, Apple was the first to directly connecthearing aids or a cochlear implant to iPhoneand other iOS devices through the Made foriPhone (MFi) program. This enables customersto make phone calls and stream high-qualityaudio directly to their MFi hearing devices. Andin 2021, Apple added support for the latestgeneration of bidirectional hearing aids fromMade for iPhone partners that support hands-free phone and FaceTime conversations.Sound Recognition notifies users of externalenvironmental sounds like running water,</P>
<P>alarms, electrical appliances, breaking glass,and more, with the newly introduced optionto train your iPhone or iPad to listen for aspecific alarm or electrical appliance sound.Other features include Live Captions (beta),introduced in 2022, which helps users withhearing disabilities follow along with calls andmedia on iPhone, iPad, and Mac; sign languageprominence in FaceTime, which can detectwhen someone uses sign language in groupcalls; and Conversation Boost for AirPods Pro,which helps users better hear conversations incrowded or noisy environments.</P>
<H1>Mobility</H1>
<P>Users with limited mobility can use SwitchControl to navigate their device with a varietyof switches, including head-tracking, backtap, sound actions, and certified MFi switches.Voice Control helps a user control a devicewith voice commands across iPhone, iPad,and Mac. On Apple Watch, AssistiveTouchfor Apple Watch helps users with upper-bodylimb differences to enjoy the benefits of AppleWatch without having to touch the display. AndApple Watch Mirroring, introduced in 2022,supports users with quadriplegia or otherphysical and motor disabilities in controllingApple Watch via iPhone using assistive featuressuch as Switch Control and Voice Control.iPadOS supports third-party eye-trackingdevices, making it possible for people tocontrol iPad using just their eyes. With TouchAccommodations, customers can controlhow long they touch the screen before it’srecognized and whether repeat touches areignored, while Back Tap lets users double-tap or triple-tap the back of their iPhone toautomatically perform a range of custom tasks,from opening an app to taking a screenshot.</P>
<H1>Cognitive</H1>
<P>Our products are built with an array of featuresto support people who are neurodivergent orhave cognitive disabilities. Background soundshelp minimize distractions and support userswho want to focus, stay calm, or rest. WithSpeak Selection for iOS and macOS, audiocan be used to support reading or writingcomprehension, and Dictation and Siri helpanyone who finds speaking easier than typingor writing. Another feature, Guided Access,limits a device to a single app and lets userscontrol which features are available.</P>
<H1>Community support</H1>
<P>Apple offersextensive support documentation,engagingonline training content, andin-storesessionsto help anyone learn how to use ourbuilt-in accessibility features. Customerscan also call or chat with Apple Support staffdedicated to supporting accessibility, orshare</P>
<P>feedback about an accessibility feature on anAppleproduct.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_106.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>The People Detection feature in Magnifier uses the LiDAR camera in iPhone 12 Pro, iPhone 13 Pro, and iPad Pro tohelp support health and safety for users who are blind or have low vision and need to maintain social distancing.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report52</P>
<P>We offer world-class, on-demand signlanguage interpretation services with theSignTime service available in US, UK, France,and Canada, which helps Apple customersand team members request an interpreter andcommunicate using American Sign Language(ASL) in US and Canada, British Sign Language(BSL) in the UK, or French Sign Language (LSF)in France.</P>
<H2>External engagement</H2>
<P>Apple subscribes to the principle ofparticipation — “Nothing About Us WithoutUs” — used by disability organizations to callfor inclusion in work done for, by, and withpersons with disabilities. In addition to hiringpeople with disabilities to develop and informour accessibility features, we welcome all userstobeta test featuresand give feedback.</P>
<H2>A preview of innovative accessibility features combiningthe power of hardware, software, and machine learning</H2>
<P>In May 2022, we previewed software features coming later this year that offer userswith disabilities new tools for navigation, health, communication, and more. Usingadvancements across hardware, software, and machine learning, people who are blindor low vision can use their iPhone and iPad to navigate the last few feet to their destinationwith Door Detection; users with physical and motor disabilities who may rely on assistivefeatures like Voice Control and Switch Control can fully control Apple Watch from theiriPhone with Apple Watch Mirroring; and the Deaf and hard of hearing community canfollow Live Captions on iPhone, iPad, and Mac.Read morehere.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_107.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple’s innovative software features introduce new ways for users with disabilitiesto navigate, connect, and get the most out of Apple products.</P>
<P>We work with various nonprofit organizationsaround the globe to strategically align andsupport each other, and we maintain constantcontact with community organizations tohelp ensure that we are exceeding theirexpectations. We also work with internationalstandards organizations to expand equalaccess to information and functionality whileworking to protect and improve the rights,inclusion, and equity of people with disabilities.</P>
<P>Apple follows policy developments and sharesits best practices with regulators, governments,and organizations, including the World HealthOrganization (WHO) and the EuropeanDisability Forum (EDF).</P>
<P>Working with the World Federation of theDeaf, the American Council of the Blind, theCerebral Palsy Foundation, and the NationalAssociation of the Deaf, Apple proposed theadoption of accessibility-themed emoji tothe Unicode Consortium, the global body incharge of setting character standards across allcomputing platforms. In 2019, the consortiumadopted Apple’s recommendation for moreinclusive and representational emoji. And in2021, we expanded the accessibility options forMemoji to include cochlear implants, an oxygentube, and a soft helmet.</P>
<H1>Inclusive design</H1>
<P>Building on our accessibility work, we’vealways believed that in order to create the mostpersonal technology in the world, we mustconsider the full range of human experiences.All across Apple there is a sustainedcommitment to making products more inclusivefor a wide range of diverse groups. Apple</P>
<P>engineers work hand in hand with teams acrossthe business to help solve unique problemsothers seldom think about.</P>
<P>For example, with iOS 14.5, Siri no longer has adefault voice, allowing users to choose the voicethat speaks to them when they first set up theirdevice, and in English, users can now selectmore diverse voice options. We’re also takingsteps to ensure equity in our cameras’ automaticperson recognition features so that everyonecan have the same extraordinary experience,no matter the photographic subject’s skin color,age, or gender. As a result, the machine learningmodels used in camera technology must showsimilar performance across various age groups,genders, ethnicities, skin tones, and otherattributes. We’ve alsopublishedresearchon this workto help others learn from it.</P>
<P>Beyond our own products and services,</P>
<P>we’ve developedmachine learning researchandHuman Interface Guidelinesto supportdevelopers in building inclusive apps thatput people first by prioritizing respectfulcommunication and presenting content andfunctionality in ways that everyone can accessand understand. Some of the characteristicsto consider include age, gender and genderidentity, race and ethnicity, language and culture,and social and economic context, amongothers. We also providetools, documentation,sample code, and design best practicesto helpdevelopers make their apps more accessible.</P>
<P>We launched two videos during our WorldwideDevelopers Conference (WWDC) in June2021 on the process and practice of inclusivedesign that were among the most popular of theweek:The Process of Inclusive DesignandThePractice of InclusiveDesign.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report53</P>
<H1>Education</H1>
<P>For more than 40 years, we’ve workedalongside educators to inspire the nextgeneration of learners, supporting creativity,problem-solving, communication, andcollaboration. We believe that education canbe a great equalizing force, and our goal is toempower all educators and learners throughtechnology that protects student privacy and isaccessible for all learners.</P>
<P>We develop products, programs, tools, andcurricula for educators to create engaginglearning experiences, and we supporteducation leaders and administrators so theycan get the most out of the technology in theclassroom and beyond.</P>
<P>Coding is a universal language, and a greatway to help students think critically and expresstheir creativity. We’re always working to makeit easy and fun to learn to code, with supportiveresources like Swift Playgrounds and theEveryone Can Code curriculum. And we workhand in hand with communities — particularlycommunities of color and others that are under-resourced — to bring coding, creating, andentrepreneurship opportunities to learnersof all ages.</P>
<H2>Products for learning</H2>
<P>Knowing that everyone has their own wayof learning and expressing themselves, weoffer products that support students andeducators from kindergarten through highereducation. iPad provides apps and advancedtechnologies that help educators teach andstudents push the boundaries of their creativity.The Augmented Reality capabilities on iPad let</P>
<P>students bring digital objects into the real worldto spark curiosity and enhance understandingin new, exciting ways. And the powerful Macprocessors are equipped for the most intensivetasks, throughout university and far beyond.</P>
<P>We also developed Apple School Manager,a free web-based portal that helps ITadministrators in K–12 and higher educationinstitutions effortlessly configure, deploy,and manage iPad and Mac devices.</P>
<H2>Teaching tools</H2>
<P>Our teaching tools empower educators topersonalize the learning experience for eachstudent and manage the classroom to keepevery student on task. Our Classroom app servesas a powerful teaching assistant that makes iteasy to navigate lessons and share information,while the Schoolwork app aids the distributionand collection of assignments, tracks progress,and supports collaboration with students.</P>
<H2>Curricula and project guides</H2>
<P>Our programs help educators integratecreativity and coding into their lessons, evenif they’re new to teaching with technology:</P>
<P>Everyone Can Create:Gives educatorsfun and meaningful ways to bring creativeexpression into any lesson, topic, orassignment. The free guides teach studentsto develop and communicate ideas throughdrawing, photography, video, and music, whileteacher guides help educators integrate bothtechnology and creativity into every lesson.</P>
<P>Everyone Can Code:Guides students throughthe Swift Playgrounds app on iPad and Mac.This free curriculum and the app teach codingfor kids through a world of interactive puzzles</P>
<H2>Expanding horizons with Inclusive App Design</H2>
<P>Educators can also try Apple’s new one-hour Inclusive App Design activity to introducestudents to the world of coding and app development. During Europe Code Week inOctober 2021 and through Computer Science Education Week in December 2021, Appleencouraged educators and their students to participate in an introductory Inclusive AppDesign activity. This new lesson from Apple helps educators guide students through a one-hour session to turn their ideas into apps with inclusion and accessibility in mind. The appdesign process helps students identify problems they care about, and then plan, prototype,and code creative solutions. It helps students think critically about how to build apps thatare inclusive for all and prepares them to be the innovators of tomorrow.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_108.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>and playful characters, and introduce Swift,the same programming language used byprofessional app developers. Teacher guidessupport educators in teaching code, even ifthey have no experience.</P>
<P>Develop in Swift:Teaches students ages 14and over how to use Swift for designing anddeveloping apps through Apple’s integrateddevelopment environment, Xcode. In 2020, welaunched a free online course taught by Appleexperts that helps instructors learn to teachSwift and Xcode.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_109.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_110.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Learn moreabout how Apple empowerseducators and learners of all ages.</P>
<P>Read moreabout Apple’s communityeducation initiatives in Communities (page 62).</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report54</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_111.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Professional learning is a key piece of Apple’s education offerings.</P>
<H2>Apple Distinguished Educatorsand Apple Distinguished Schools</H2>
<P>Our community of nearly 3000 AppleDistinguished Educators in 45 countriesmodel, advise, advocate, and publish materialson ways to integrate Apple technology intoteaching and learning. These educators areactive leaders, helping to make learning deeplypersonal for every student.</P>
<P>Apple Distinguished Schools are centers ofleadership and educational excellence thatdemonstrate the impact of learning withApple technology. The nearly 700 schoolsacross 36 countries cultivate environmentswhere students are excited and curiousabout learning.</P>
<H2>Inspiration and support for teachers</H2>
<P>We help educators share experiences, ideas,and inspiration, so that they too can get moreout of the technology in their classrooms.</P>
<P>Apple Teacher is a free online, self-pacedprofessional learning program that helpsteachers build their skills and confidence inteaching with Apple technology and earn AppleTeacher recognition. Our Apple ProfessionalLearning Specialists are experts who provideone-on-one coaching sessions and groupprofessional learning workshops for educators,in addition to the support resources availableonline or via phone. The majority of oureducator tools are free, and we offer special</P>
<P>pricing on Mac, iPad, and other Apple hardwarefor education institutions, eligible collegestudents, and education faculty and staff.</P>
<P>In March 2022, we unveiled Apple LearningCoach, which is a free professional learningprogram that trains instructional coaches,digital learning specialists, and other coachingeducators to help teachers effectively useApple technology in the classroom. Through amix of self-paced lessons and virtual workshopsessions with Apple Professional LearningSpecialists, participants come away from theexperience with an actionable portfolio, acohort of peers, and the opportunity to applyfor continuing education credits from LamarUniversity through the Texas Education Agency.Each Apple Learning Coach gains a deeperunderstanding of how to support teacherswhere they are, as they integrate technologyinto learning.</P>
<H1>Health</H1>
<P>Apple empowers our users to take control oftheir health by making it easier to track andshare their health and wellness informationwhile always keeping their data secure. Thisallows for a more informed dialogue with lovedones and doctors, offering the ability to makebetter health choices on a daily basis.</P>
<P>Privacy is a fundamental aspect of our healthwork. The right place for health information toexist is with a user on their device, and whereor how that information is shared should becompletely up to the individual.</P>
<H2>Technology for better health</H2>
<P>Since launching Apple Watch in 2015, we’vebeen constantly inspired by the stories we hearfrom our users about how using Apple Watchfor health and fitness has changed their lives.These range from users who found closing theirActivity rings every day motivated them to be inthe best shape of their lives to those alerted toa potential irregular heart rhythm who soughtmedical care to confirm. Stories like thosecontinually drive us to do more for our users.</P>
<P>Building on innovative features for Apple Watchlike the ECG app, irregular rhythm notifications,and fall detection, Apple recently introduceda variety of services and features to helppeople on their health and fitness journeys.Apple Fitness+ is an award-winning fitnessand wellness service powered by Apple Watchand designed to be welcoming to all, whereverthey are in their journey. Fitness+ helps userstrain their body and mind with a personalizedand engaging experience that can be doneanytime, anywhere; intelligently incorporatesworkout metrics from Apple Watch right onthe screen; and motivates users from startto finish with music from today’s top artists.Features like Handwashing, Sleep, and BloodOxygen offer more insights into users’ overallwellness to make more informed decisions forthemselves. Apple Watch users can also viewa classification of their Cardio Fitness Level— a powerful predictor of overall health — inthe Health app, and receive a notification if itfalls within the “low” range. The breakthroughtechnology allows users to better understandtheir cardio fitness measurements taken rightfrom their own wrist.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report55</P>
<P>On iPhone, Walking Steadiness is an industryfirst, providing insight into fall risk by leveragingimportant mobility data as users walk with theiriPhone, directly within the Health app. TheHealth app provides a consolidated view ofusers’ health information — data from iPhone,third-party apps, and Apple Watch. And sinceintroducing the Health Records feature in2018, it is supported at over 800 healthcareinstitutions with over 12,500 care locationsacross three regions — the U.S., Canada,</P>
<H2>Investigator Support Program</H2>
<P>Inspired by the innovative ways the research,clinical, and developer communities leverageour products and platforms, we launched theInvestigator Support Program that providesresearchers with opportunities to receiveApple Watch to include in their research study.We have witnessed firsthand how researchersand clinicians are able to accomplish evenmore with the addition of Apple Watch to theirresearch and care programs, and through thisprogram we hope even more people can havethe same kind of success. Currently, studiesaround the globe are integrating Apple Watchinto their research across heart, mobility,activity, and other focus areas.See moreabout the program.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_112.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>and the UK. Additionally, users have the optionto securely share their health data with a lovedone, a caregiver, and, in the U.S., their doctorthrough the Health app.</P>
<H2>Health research</H2>
<P>Everything Apple does in health is basedin science. We have a history of enablingthe medical community through platformslike ResearchKit and CareKit, which helpresearchers produce medical insights anddiscoveries on conditions from epilepsyto Parkinson’s at a pace and scale neverseen before.</P>
<P>Apple technology is helping democratizemedical research by giving users the abilityto opt in to share data through theResearchappusing their iPhone or Apple Watch. Thereare currently three public landmark studiesin the Research app:</P>
<P>Apple Women’s Health Study:The HarvardT.H. Chan School of Public Health has teamedup with Apple and the National Institute ofEnvironmental Health Sciences to gain a deeperunderstanding of how certain demographicand lifestyle factors could have an impact onmenstrual cycles and gynecologic conditions,including infertility, menopause, and polycysticovary syndrome.See the latestupdates.</P>
<P>Apple Hearing Study:The Apple HearingStudy is a partnership between the Universityof Michigan and Apple to study soundexposure and its impact on hearing health.This groundbreaking study helps advanceour understanding of how hearing could beimpacted over time by exposure to sound at</P>
<P>certain levels. The study data is also beingshared with the World Health Organization as acontribution to its Make Listening Safe initiative.See the latestupdates.</P>
<P>Apple Heart and Movement Study:</P>
<P>Conducted in collaboration with the AmericanHeart Association and Brigham and Women’sHospital, the Apple Heart and MovementStudy explores factors that affect hearthealth and potentially cause deterioration inmobility or overall well-being, in an effort topromote healthy movement and improvedcardiovascular health. By collecting hearthealth, workout, mobility, and activity datafrom Apple Watch and iPhone users, as well assurvey data, this study will provide insights onheart health and potential early warning signsin ways that were not possible before.See the latestupdates.</P>
<H2>Partnering with the medical industry</H2>
<P>Our technology gives healthcare providersthe tools they need to work effectively withinhospitals and connect remotely with patients.Apps on iPad, iPhone, and Apple Watch canhelp medical professionals deliver personalizedcare. We have seen how our technology canalso empower clinicians to be more mobile,leading to time savings and more time spenttaking care of patients. Our devices aredesigned to protect patient data yet remainaccessible and easy to use across providers.The result is care that becomes more efficient,more personalized, and ultimately, morehuman.Learn more about how our productssupport medicalprofessionals.</P>
<H1>Caring for customers</H1>
<P>At Apple, we want to create products andservices that enrich people’s lives. To us, thatmeans making the best, not the most, and onlybuilding things that make us proud.</P>
<H2>A world-class experience</H2>
<P>We’re motivated by creating the best userexperience through our products and in everyinteraction with our customers. We focus onbreakthrough technologies and innovativefeatures that set us apart and keep peoplecoming back to Apple. Consumer surveys haveconsistently shown high satisfaction ratings forour revolutionary products, including iPhone(97 percent or higher), Mac (over 87 percent),iPad (93 percent or higher), and Apple Watch(90 percent or higher).21</P>
<H2>Support through retail</H2>
<P>Our focus on our customers extends to a retailexperience that puts the people we serveat the center of everything we do. Our retailteams inspire our customers to discover, learnabout, and choose Apple products, services,and accessories by delivering a personalizedexperience like no other. Apple Specialistsin our retail stores and contact centers helpcustomers find the right products with</P>
<P>one-on-one shopping and support sessions— in person, over the phone, or via chat. Todayat Apple and Online Personal sessions helpcustomers learn how to get the most from theirdevices and take their creativity further.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report56</P>
<P>Apple’s Education team works to ensure thatstudents, teachers, and parents have the bestlearning tools for the classroom. For businesscustomers, the dedicated teams in every AppleStore provide the advice, pricing, and supportsmall businesses need in our communities.</P>
<P>We work closely with Apple AuthorizedResellers, like carriers, and retailers to enhancethe customer shopping experience beyond ourown retail locations and the Apple website.</P>
<H1>Listening and improving</H1>
<P>To help ensure quality, we continually monitorcustomer feedback, assess key drivers, andleverage analytics to improve the customerexperience. Customer feedback is sharedwith team members as well as leaders, so thateveryone understands their impact and isfocused on making the customer experiencethe best it can possibly be. Throughout thepandemic, our retail teams continue to workdiligently to be flexible through ever-changingoperational challenges, as well as health andgovernment guidelines. All the while they keepthe focus on helping our customers, and as aresult our Store teams earned our highest-evercustomer satisfaction scores.</P>
<P>As we continue delivering exceptionalproducts, we remain committed to high-qualitystandards and transparent communicationwith customers. We maintain a System Statuspage to actively report on identified systemissues and offer service programs to addresshardware issues. We encourage our customersto contact us with questions, provide feedback,or request support. As just one example,learnmoreabout how we responded to customerfeedback on AirTag.</P>
<H1>Safety for children and families</H1>
<P>Families love iPhone, iPad, Mac, Apple Watch,and Apple TV because they are some of themost powerful tools ever made for learning,exploring, and staying in touch. We’re committedto providing tools that let caregivers know, andfeel good about, what kids are doing. A range offeatures offer flexibility to track app usage, setlimits on screen time and community, choosewhich apps children can use, and manage thecontent and websites they can access.</P>
<P>Features also help protect kids from what theysee and send. With the latest versions of iOS,iPadOS, and macOS, families can set up kids’devices to show warnings when receiving orsending images containing nudity. The imageis blurred, and the child gets an alert along with</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_113.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Messages can warn children when receiving orsending photos that contain nudity.</P>
<P>helpful resources and the option to messagesomeone they trust for help. End-to-endencryption is maintained, and Apple doesn’tget access to your messages.</P>
<P>Apple has also expanded guidance in Siri,Spotlight, and Safari Search by providingadditional resources to help children andfamilies stay safe online and get help withunsafe situations. For example, users who askSiri how they can report child exploitation willbe pointed to resources for where and howto file a report.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_116.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>The App Store:A safe place for kids</H1>
<P>The Made for Kids section on the App Storeis carefully curated to be a great space forchildren. And we review apps to help makesure they do what they say they do. In ContentRestrictions, you can also tap an age rangeand, just like that, your kids can buy ordownload only apps appropriate for them.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_115.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_114.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Visit ourFamilies siteandChild Safety siteto learn more</P>
<H1>Product longevity</H1>
<P>We believe long-lasting products are best forthe environment. We also believe products thatminimize the need for repair or replacementencourage our customers to come back toApple. We design our products with this goalin mind.</P>
<P>Building durability and repairabilityinto our designs</P>
<P>Designing and building durable hardware iscore to delivering this customer experience.We assess our designs against our strictdurability standards through testing methodsthat mimic realistic conditions in which ourcustomers use their products. Every aspectof our products is thoroughly assessed byengineers in our Reliability Testing Lab whomeasure the performance of materials,components, and fully assembled products.</P>
<P>We continue to design our products withfeatures that enhance repairability anddurability. For instance, we’ve continuedto increase the number of repairable moduleson iPhone while also adding durability featureslike water resistance.</P>
<P>Making repairs more convenient</P>
<P>If a repair is needed, we believe our customersshould have convenient access to qualityrepair services to get their product back upand running as quickly as possible.</P>
<P>Over the past three years, we’ve nearly doubledthe number of service locations with accessto genuine Apple parts, tools, and training,offering more ways for consumers to getrepairs. These repair options include AppleStore locations, Apple Authorized ServiceProviders (AASP), participating IndependentRepair Providers, mail-in repair centers, oronsite service and, starting in 2022, SelfService Repair. Our repair network has grownto over 5000 AASP locations and over 3000Independent Repair Providers around the world— in addition to our 500 Apple retail locations.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>Environment</P>
<P>OurPeople</P>
<P>Suppliers</P>
<P>Customers</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report57</P>
<H1>Now available: Self Service Repair</H1>
<P>Self Service Repair became available in April2022, providing repair manuals and genuineApple parts and tools through theApple SelfService Repair Store. Self Service Repair isavailable in the U.S. and will expand to additionalcountries, beginning in Europe, later in 2022.The new online store offers more than 200individual parts and tools, enabling customerswho are experienced with the complexities ofrepairing electronic devices to complete repairson the iPhone 12 and iPhone 13 lineups andiPhone SE (3rd generation).</P>
<P>We also released “Expanding Access to Safe,Reliable, and Secure Service and Repair,”which details Apple’s approach to designinglong-lasting products and increasing accessto repairs.</P>
<P>Keeping our products currentwith software updates</P>
<P>Apple provides free software upgrades toimprove our customers’ experience and helpour products last longer. Our customers cancount on the latest software features andsecurity updates to their existing devices foryears. We continually improve the operatingsystems that power our products and engineereach software release to run seamlessly on allsupported devices.</P>
<P>Extending the life of products and partsthrough refurbishment and reuse</P>
<P>We can lower the impact each device has onthe environment — including carbon intensityper year of life — by finding ways to refurbishand reuse these products. And by building ourproducts to serve more than one owner andencouraging customers to exchange devicesfor an upgrade, we extend the life</P>
<P>of our products.</P>
<P>We collect devices for refurbishing and reusethrough several programs, including AppleTrade In, the iPhone Upgrade Program,AppleCare, and our corporate HardwareReuse Program. In fiscal year 2021, we sent12.2 million devices and accessories to newowners for reuse. Our Trade In program extendsto 25 countries, providing customers withoptions for product end-of-life — to accessthe value of their current device if they want toupgrade to a newer model, or to recycle theirdevices for free.</P>
<H1>Product safety</H1>
<P>We design our products to make sure they’resafe for anyone who assembles, uses, orrecycles them.</P>
<P>Commitment to safety</P>
<P>The well-being of those who design, make, use,and recycle our products is a priority for Apple,which is why we’re committed to using safermaterials to create safer products. We assessthe health and safety of all our products, duringevery stage of their life cycle — from earlyconcept development, through use, service,and repair, to recycling. During the design andprototyping process, cross-functional Appleteams analyze potential failures and theireffects from a quality and safety perspective.The results drive product design improvementsand manufacturing process controls.</P>
<P>Apple is committed to helping customersunderstand how to safely use Appleproducts. Apple’sproduct user manualsinclude important safety and handlinginformation, and Apple offers additional topicalcontent to provide tips and help customersunderstand features.</P>
<P>For example, Apple published articles to makesure customers withpotential skin sensitivitiesunderstand what materials are used inour wearable products. We also explainedhow toclean and disinfectApple products,and provided guidance on keeping Appleproducts withmagnets a safe distance frommedical devices.</P>
<P>Safety compliance</P>
<P>Apple’s products are designed, tested, andcertified to comply with international andregional safety standards. They also meet ourown specifications, which often go above andbeyond what is required. For example, Apple’sRegulated Substances Specification restrictsthe use of certain chemical substances in Appleproducts, and we apply rigorous additionalcontrols for materials that may have prolongedcontact with the skin. Components that arecritical to safety are subject to enhancedrequirements and additional supplier audits.</P>
<P>Apple tracks customer reports of potentialproduct safety issues, and employeesare trained on how to handle, document,and properly escalate such reports. Appleinvestigates reported incidents and alsoanalyzes products for potential safety issues.In the rare event that Apple determines aproduct poses a potential safety risk, we takeaction to recall the product, which includesnotifying customers and helping customershave their products repaired, replaced,or refunded.</P>
<P>Apple’s Safety Compliance Policy definesprocedures to monitor products in the field andinvestigate potential safety issues. This policyrequires escalation of safety issues to Applemanagement and timely reporting to regulatorswhere necessary. It also requires mechanismsfor employees to confidentially report safetyor compliance concerns, as well as training foremployees on how to address the concerns.Our Product Integrity and Legal teams areresponsible for ensuring that Apple’s SafetyCompliance Policy is followed.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_117.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_118.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple products also help customers inemergenciesand in caring for their well-being, with features likeemergency calling, fall detection, medical ID, andhearing health notifications.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironmentIntroduction</P>
<H1>A forcefor good.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report58</P>
<H2>Communities</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Our approach</P>
<P>Racial Equity and Justice InitiativeEducation</P>
<P>Affordable housing initiativeCorporate donationsEmployee givingJob creation</P>
<P>59</P>
<P>60</P>
<P>62</P>
<P>64</P>
<P>65</P>
<P>67</P>
<P>68</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report59</P>
<H2>People at Apple don’t just serve our communities — we’re a part of them. That’s whyeverywhere Apple is, we feel a deep sense of responsibility to be a force for equity andopportunity, to protect the planet we share, and to help our users get the most out oftheir technology. Whether we’re working with educators, nonprofit leaders, or the globaldeveloper community, we believe in using our technology, our resources, and our voiceto help people make a difference in their communities. We can achieve so much morewhen we work together — with our neighbors — to build a better future for all.</H2>
<H2>Our approach</H2>
<P>At Apple, we’re committed to leaving the worldbetter than we found it. That means supportingcommunities with global and local initiatives,investments, and donations that combatinequity, expand access to opportunity, andhelp respond to urgent needs. Many of theseinitiatives also contribute to the UN SustainableDevelopment Goals (see Appendixpage75).</P>
<P>Some of our largest community initiatives addressracial equity and justice, education, affordablehousing, and other critical issues where we canuse our presence, expertise, and resources tomake a difference. Through these efforts, wefoster open communication with local communitypartners and stakeholders to understanddynamic challenges in order to drive meaningfulimpact. Apple supports these initiatives throughprogram development, donations to nonprofitpartners, and values-based investments, whichgo beyond financial returns to promote positivesocial and environmental impact.</P>
<P>Through our values-based investments, wesee an important opportunity to continue toinvest our capital for good — often throughmultiyear commitments in which Apple playsa substantive role in the project development.Our affordable housing initiative, Racial Equityand Justice Initiative, clean energy investments,and the Restore Fund (seepage 17) are allexamples of initiatives in which values-basedinvestments play a significant role.</P>
<P>Our corporate donations support workundertaken across the company to addresssociety’s toughest problems. We donate tononprofits and other organizations with whichwe partner to support specific initiatives, aswell as directly to organizations supportingour objectives to accelerate social change,strengthen communities, and amplify Apple’svalues. We empower employees to contributeto the causes they care about, and we multiplytheir efforts through matching their donations.</P>
<P>In total, we’ve committed over $3 billiontoward corporate donations and values-based investments since fiscal year 2018.Our corporate donations alone were over$250 million in fiscal year 2021.</P>
<P>Fulfilling our commitments to our communitiesrequires teamwork across the entire</P>
<P>company. Lisa Jackson, our Vice Presidentfor Environment, Policy and Social Initiatives isresponsible for Apple’s environmental initiatives,community education programs, productaccessibility, and community investment, andshe leads Apple’s Racial Equity and JusticeInitiative. Community initiatives are managedthrough cross-functional collaboration withteams across Apple, including Treasury,People, Real Estate and Development, Legal,and Education.</P>
<P>We also know that we can impact communitiesaround the world by creating and sustaininglocal jobs. As our teams continue to grow, we’reproud to foster innovation, opportunity, andeconomic support across the globe.</P>
<H1>$3B+</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_119.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Since FY18, we’ve committed over</P>
<P>$3 billion in strategic, values-basedinvestments and community donations.</P>
<P>Total corporate donations(excluding values-based investments)</P>
<P>FY21:</P>
<H1>$250M+</H1>
<P>FY20:</P>
<H1>$250M+</H1>
<P>FY19:</P>
<H1>$190M+</H1>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report60</P>
<H1>Racial Equity andJustice Initiative</H1>
<P>We have an urgent responsibility to helpdismantle systemic racism and supportopportunities for Black, Hispanic/Latinx, andIndigenous communities. Our Racial Equityand Justice Initiative (REJI) is focused on threekey areas: expanding access to education,supporting criminal justice reform, andremoving economic barriers for communitiesof color.</P>
<P>The initiative began in June 2020 with aninitial commitment of $100 million, followedby an additional $30 million commitment inAugust 2021, to help elevate equity-focusedsolutions across the academic and advocacylandscapes, and a $25 million commitmentin May 2022 to expand access to capital forcommunity financial institutions supportingcommunities of color.</P>
<P>REJI has spurred new partnerships and projectswhile inspiring us to weave a focus on equityand justice into everything we do — includingour existing community programsand business operations.</P>
<H2>Education: Greater accessand greater opportunity</H2>
<P>REJI builds on our long-standing commitmentto education and works hand in hand with ourCommunity Education Initiative (page 62).Historically Black Colleges and Universities(HBCUs), Hispanic-Serving Institutions (HSIs),and Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs)are critical leaders in expanding educationalaccess, as are community colleges and othercenters of learning. To support their continued</P>
<P>leadership, Apple is collaborating with minority-serving institutions on programs designed tobuild a more inclusive workforce.</P>
<P>Propel Center:In January 2021, Apple, incollaboration with Southern Company anda range of community stakeholders, helpedlaunch the Propel Center, a global innovationand learning hub for the HBCU community.The Propel Center supports HBCU studentsand faculty through a robust virtual platform,a physical campus in the historic AtlantaUniversity Center, as well as on-campusactivations at partner institutions. The centeris designed to support the next generation ofdiverse leaders, providing innovative curricula,technology support, career opportunities,and fellowship programs. Experts fromApple support the development of curriculaand provide ongoing mentorship andlearning support.</P>
<P>HSI Innovation Hub:In August 2021, weannounced our partnership with CaliforniaState University (CSU) Northridge’s Global HSIEquity Innovation Hub, which aims to transformHSIs throughout the CSU system and the U.S.in order to increase student success and equipLatinx and other students from historicallyunderserved groups with skills for high-demand careers in STEM. Apple’s commitmentwill support the initiative’s main location on theCalifornia State University, Northridge campusin Los Angeles, and provide Apple technology,design support, and thought partnership as theproject expands.</P>
<P>HBCU C2Initiative:In partnership withTennessee State University, Apple supportsthe HBCU C2initiative, launched in 2019to empower and support HBCUs to bringcoding and creativity experiences to their</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_120.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Apple is partnering with California State University, Northridge’s Global HSI Equity Innovation Hubas part of our Racial Equity and Justice Initiative.</P>
<P>communities, using Apple hardware andits Everyone Can Code and Everyone CanCreate curricula. In 2021, we announced theexpansion of the program to 11 new schools,bringing the total number of community codingcenters and regional hubs on HBCU campusesto 45 across the U.S. In addition to donatingequipment and professional developmentservices, Apple provided funding to supportprogram development.</P>
<P>Taking Action on Racial Equity and Justiceseries:This set of conversation guides andlearning-based challenges on race andinequality issues provides a framework andresources for educators, community leaders,and families to use with young people.</P>
<H2>Criminal justice: An unfairsystem is unfit for everyone</H2>
<P>The criminal justice system disproportionatelyfails communities of color. We supportorganizations working to end mass incarcerationand defend civil rights.</P>
<P>Apple has donated to organizations that supportracial justice, including the Anti-RecidivismCoalition, the Council on Criminal Justice, theInnocence Project, The Last Mile, Recidiviz,The Sentencing Project, and the Vera Instituteof Justice. These commitments will help topromote racial, ethnic, economic, and genderjustice, as well as the safeguarding of youth,and work to end the practice of extremesentences in the criminal justice system.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report61</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_121.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>African American Male Teacher Initiativeat Huston-Tillotson University</H1>
<P>Currently, only 2 percent of all U.S. teachers are Black men, something theprogram at Huston-Tillotson is working to change. When Black students aretaught by a Black teacher, they’re significantly more likely to graduate from highschool and consider attending college. To support Huston-Tillotson University’sAfrican American Male Teacher Initiative, Apple is providing scholarships for theprogram’s students, called Pre-Ed Scholars, as well as hardware, software, andprofessional development courses for students and faculty. Apple’s multiyearpartnership with Huston-Tillotson complements other engagements we’veestablished through our Racial Equity and Justice Initiative, working alongsidethe HBCU community to develop curricula and provide new learning andworkforce opportunities.</P>
<P>Using FaceTime, Rhys Richard chats with his music professor, Dr. Samuel Rowley, as partof his coursework at Huston-Tillotson University.</P>
<P>To further advance our work in this area, Appleis also partnering with a number of communitycolleges to implement programs that arehelping incarcerated and paroled individualslearn new skills and work to prevent recidivism.As one example, at Houston CommunityCollege in Texas, Apple is contributing fundingand technology to a program that supportsindividuals on parole and probation to preparefor career and college readiness.</P>
<H1>Economic empowerment:For today’s entrepreneurs</H1>
<P>Black, Hispanic/Latinx, and Indigenousbusiness owners deserve a fair shot and afair share. Through mentorship and financialinvestments, we back founders who havehistorically been cut out of opportunitiesto access capital in order to achieveeconomic prosperity.</P>
<P>Since 2021, we’ve announced $75 millionin financial commitments to support Black,Hispanic/Latinx, and Indigenous entrepreneurs,businesses, and financial institutions.</P>
<P>These include $25 million in venture capitalinvestments in three Black- and Hispanic/Latinx-founded firms — Harlem Capital,VamosVentures, and Collab Capital. And$25 million of our commitment is to SiebertWilliams Shank’s Clear Vision Impact Fund,which works to increase loan capital forsmall- and medium-size minority-ownedbusinesses and underserved communities.We also committed $25 million to expandaccess to capital for financial institutionssupporting communities of color in historicallyunderserved markets across the U.S. throughCNote’s Impact Cash product.</P>
<P>Through our Impact Accelerator, we’re takingsteps to help better position businesses led bypeople of color to benefit from investments ingreen technology and clean energy, bringingtogether our commitments to equity and theenvironment. Launched in 2020, the ImpactAccelerator is a three-month virtual programthat includes customized training along withaccess to Apple expert mentors and a growingalumni community — to expand participants’opportunities within Apple’s supply chain.Read more about the first class of the ImpactAccelerator onpage18.</P>
<P>We are also supporting economicempowerment for communities of colorthrough two of our existing programs,Entrepreneur Camp (seepage 64) and AppleDeveloper Academy (seepage 63). In early2022, Entrepreneur Camp welcomed its firstcohort of Hispanic/Latinx founders. And inOctober 2021, we partnered with MichiganState University to open an Apple DeveloperAcademy in Detroit, a city with a vibrant Blackentrepreneur and developer community andover 50,000 minority-owned businesses.</P>
<P>Our work to provide access and opportunityto communities of color extends to our ownbusiness activities, including supportinginclusion and diversity among our employees(seepage 23) and increasing Apple’s spendwith diverse suppliers (seepage45).</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report62</P>
<H1>Education</H1>
<P>Access to education is a human right, andwe work hard to ensure that our resourcesare used to uplift communities around theworld, creating opportunities for educatorsand students to gain coding skills and unlockcreativity. Our efforts also support the UNSustainable Development Goals, including goal4 on access to education, goal 8 on decentjobs, and goal 10 on reducing inequality (seeAppendixpage75).</P>
<H2>Community Education Initiative</H2>
<P>Inspired by the impact of ourConnectEDinitiativeand programs like EveryoneCan Create and Everyone Can Code, welaunched our Community Education Initiative(CEI) in 2019 with a focus on expandinglearning opportunities in communities</P>
<P>that are historically underrepresented andunderresourced in technology.</P>
<P>CEI partners with K–12 and higher educationinstitutions, community-based organizations,and nonprofits to bring coding, creativity,and workforce development opportunities toeducators and learners of all ages. CEI aims tobuild knowledge and skills for high-demand,high-growth technical careers alongsidecommunities that have been traditionallyunderresourced to advance education equity.Our support includes hardware grants,monetary grants to support scholarships andprogramming, resources for educator training,curriculum development, and employeeengagement opportunities.</P>
<P>Through educational partnerships acrossthe U.S., we’ve been able to reach tensof thousands of students and educatorswho might not have had access to ourtechnology and education resources. As ofApril 2022, we’ve supported and partneredwith 147 education institutions and nonprofitorganizations — including 47 HBCUs — in over500 different locations across 36 states in theU.S. and four locations across the UK since theinitiative launched in 2019.</P>
<P>Grounded in the positive relationships thatwe’ve established with these organizations,we’re working to deepen our impact inthree areas:</P>
<P>Educator development:We’re providingeducator development and trainingopportunities to build the knowledge andskills that educators need to teach codingin underrepresented communities throughTeacher Coding Academies and the CEILearning Series. These programs allowhundreds of teachers from around the U.S.to meet virtually and in person to sharebest practices for integrating and teachingcoding and creativity concepts. Throughour Academies and CEI Learning Series,we’re connecting CEI educators with AppleDistinguished Educators from all around the</P>
<P>world. Apple Distinguished Educators lead andparticipate in learning workshops, along withour Apple Professional Learning Specialists.</P>
<P>Out-of-school-time learning:We’repartnering with nonprofits, NGOs, andcommunity-based organizations that provideout-of-school-time learning experiencesto increase exposure, awareness, andexperiences through coding and creativity.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_122.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>A new collaboration between Apple and Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of America will bring codingwith Swift to tens of thousands of young learners across the country.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report63</P>
<P>Support for minority-serving institutions:</P>
<P>We’re especially focused on expanding ourengagement with minority-serving institutions,including HBCUs, HSIs, and TCUs, as well ascommunity colleges and public schools inunderserved communities.</P>
<P>In 2021, many of our CEI projects wereundertaken in support of REJI’s educationfocus (page 60). For example, in December2021, Apple and Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of Americalaunched a new collaboration to bring codingwith Swift to tens of thousands of studentsacross the U.S., building on Apple’s existingpartnership with the organization to use</P>
<P>iPad and Apple’s free Everyone Can Codecurriculum. And in Canada, we’ve supportedlearning for Indigenous people through an app-based literacy assessment tool, which drovesignificant literacy outcomes, encouraged acommunity-based approach, and providedlearning activities for children to build oral skills.In addition, we partnered with the Assemblyof First Nations on an interactive collection ofApple Books that explore Canadian historyfrom an Indigenous perspective.</P>
<H1>Apple Developer Academy</H1>
<P>As the iOS app economy continues to grow,we’re investing in educational programs andopportunities that prepare learners of all agesand backgrounds for the jobs of the future.</P>
<P>In 2013, we started the Apple DeveloperAcademy to empower entrepreneurs, creators,and coders by helping them cultivate the skillsnecessary to pursue new career opportunities.The program focuses on communities withhigh youth unemployment and is open toanyone, regardless of academic backgroundor experience. We seek to spark interest</P>
<P>among the next generation of developers andbring diverse representation to the growingapp ecosystem, particularly among womenand individuals from underrepresentedcommunities. A larger and more diversedeveloper community helps create more newideas and businesses, and it gives more peopleaccess to employment and opportunities foreconomic mobility. Some participants are alsoundertaking practical projects in collaborationwith NGOs to help use technology to solvechallenges related to their missions, whichamplifies impact even further.</P>
<P>We offer two distinct training programs as partof the Apple Developer Academy: 1) 30-dayfoundations courses that cover specific topicareas, including an introductory course forthose considering app development as a careerpath, and 2) a more intensive academy programof at least 10 to 12 months that dives deeperinto coding and professional skills. In additionto partnering with institutions, the academyworks closely with employers to provide directpathways to career opportunities. Participantsalso have access to a strong alumni networkas they move forward in their careers.</P>
<P>As of April 2022, we have 23 foundationprograms and 17 academy programs acrossthe globe working in close collaborations withinstitutions that provide content and experienceopportunities. The programs are based in sevencountries with over 2600 participants in totalin calendar year 2021 — and more than15,000 since the inception of the AppleDeveloper Academy in 2013.22</P>
<P>On average, job-seeking graduating studentsreceive three job offers, and 92 percent ofalumni are employed.23We also see highrates of students staying in the industry. Forexample, 62 percent of students are stillworking in iOS coding and design positionsseven years after graduating from the Brazilprogram, and 79 percent of Indonesian alumniare still involved in app development onApple platforms.24</P>
<P>We’re also making progress on our commitmentto support underrepresented groups. In 2021,40 percent of academy students were female,a 63 percent year-on-year increase, and</P>
<P>39 percent came from non-STEM backgrounds,a 56 percent year-on-year increase. In thefoundation programs, 34 percent of studentswere female in 2021.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_123.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_124.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Aristide Lauga (left), from France, is a new student at the Apple Developer Academy who looks forward topursuing his newfound passion for coding. Giada Di Somma (right) graduated from the academy in 2017 and nowworks full-time as a UX design lead in Milan.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report64</P>
<P>In 2021 and early 2022, the Apple DeveloperAcademy has continued to grow with thesenew developments:</P>
<L><LI>•The first U.S. Apple Developer Academy,launching in Detroit in October 2021 as partof our REJI initiative (seepage60)</LI>
<LI>•The first women-dedicated Apple DeveloperAcademy, launching in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia,in November 2021</LI>
<LI>•The first Korean Apple Developer Academy,launching in Pohang in March 2022 andserving 200 students from across Korea</LI>
<LI>•A new foundation program location in France</LI>
<LI>•A significant new investment in Naples, Italy,in September 2021, expanding academyprogramming through 2025 and launching anew alumni resource program</LI>
</L>
<H1>92%</H1>
<P>Apple Development Academy alumniemployment rate*</P>
<H1>40%</H1>
<P>female and 39 percent non-STEM studentsin 2021 academy program</P>
<H1>34%</H1>
<P>female in 2021 foundations program* As of our last alumni survey in December 2021</P>
<H3>Entrepreneur Camp</H3>
<P>Research shows that founders fromunderrepresented communities face uniquechallenges, especially when starting andleading technology companies. We createdApple Entrepreneur Camp with the goal ofsupporting these founders and their app-drivenbusinesses as they build the next generationof cutting-edge apps, and to form a globalalumni network that encourages the pipelineand longevity of underrepresented foundersand developers in technology. The programincludes cohorts for female, Black, andHispanic/Latinx founders and developers fromunderrepresented communities.</P>
<P>During these app-focused technology labs,participants receive one-on-one code-levelguidance on their apps from Apple expertsand engineers, as well as support, inspiration,and insights from top Apple leaders. The coreprogramming is based on Developer Labs atWWDC, where participants work on improving aspecific app in bespoke, one-on-one sessionswith Apple engineers and experts. The programalso includes community sessions, networking,and opportunities for ongoing support. Afterthe lab concludes, participants become partof a growing community of other exceptionalalumni who can help them build their business.Apple Entrepreneur Camp alumni have goneon to secure major funding rounds, garnernumerous awards and accolades, andsignificantly expand both their teams and appusers worldwide. Alumni apps are featured ontheEntrepreneur Campwebsite.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_125.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Located in downtown Detroit, the Apple Developer Academy space is designed to facilitate collaboration andengagement, preparing students for success in the iOS app economy.</P>
<P>There have been 12 Entrepreneur Campcohorts since our first class of female foundersand developers in 2019. Since the launch ofREJI, we expanded to hosting cohorts for Blackfounders in 2021 and Hispanic/Latinx foundersin early 2022. Participants have also receivedadditional guidance from Harlem Capital, CollabCapital, and Vamos Ventures as part of REJI(seepage 61). Entrepreneur Camp alumni hailfrom 26 countries, and we continue to focus onexpanding our outreach to underrepresentedfounders and developers around the world.</P>
<H2>Affordable housinginitiative</H2>
<P>Through our affordable housing initiative,announced in 2019, we’ve made acomprehensive $2.5 billion commitment toaddress the housing availability and affordabilitycrisis in California. Together with governmentand community-based organizations, theinitiative has sought to jump-start long-termdevelopments, help first-time buyers purchasehomes, and support new housing and relatedprograms to alleviate homelessness. As ofJuly 2021, we’ve deployed more than $1 billionsupporting projects and communities in morethan 25 counties across California.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report65</P>
<P>In partnership with the California HousingFinance Agency (CalHFA), Apple has providedmortgage and down payment assistance tothousands of first-time buyers with low andmoderate incomes, with additional benefitsfor teachers, veterans, and firefighters. Applehas also partnered with CalHFA to launch anaffordable housing investment program, thefirst of its kind in California, which has increasedthe availability of funding to develop and buildvery low- to moderate-income housing at alower cost. And we’re supporting several newaffordable housing projects funded throughour partnership with Housing Trust SiliconValley. Many of the new units are reserved forveterans, the homeless or formerly homeless,and residents with developmental disabilities.In 2022, residents moved into the new VeteransSquare development in Pittsburg, California.</P>
<P>The 30-unit building offers 100 percentfree housing to local veterans, along with acommunity garden, courtyard, communityroom, on-site management, and otheramenities and services.</P>
<P>Apple’s affordable housing initiative alsoincludes a partnership with Destination:Home, which has helped fund the constructionof thousands of new units of affordable andsupportive housing for the most vulnerablepopulations across Silicon Valley. With oursupport, Destination: Home has also been ableto expand its Homelessness PreventionSystem to keep thousands of families fromlosing their homes each year.Learnmoreabout this initiative.</P>
<H1>Corporate donations</H1>
<P>Whether it’s racial injustice, food insecurity,a natural disaster, or a health emergency, ourcommunity giving program is agile enoughto allow us to respond in a timely, efficient,and effective way. We support nonprofitorganizations in a variety of ways, includingfinancial resources, Apple technology, andexpertise from our teams.</P>
<H2>Accelerating social change</H2>
<P>We’ve designed our corporate donationsto address immediate needs and to buildcommunity resilience. Several initiativesdescribed on previous pages fall into this areaof focus, including our REJI commitment tofurther racial equity and justice (seepage</P>
<L><LI>60) and addressing housing scarcity and</LI>
</L>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_126.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>homelessness in California (seepage64).</P>
<P>In 2021, Apple marked its 15th anniversary ofpartnering with (RED) to fight HIV/AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa. Since 2006, Apple customershave helped raise nearly $270 million to fundprevention, testing, and counseling servicesfor people impacted by HIV/AIDS, as well asprograms to support this community duringCOVID-19. Apple-supported grants haveenabled care and support services for over11 million people, provided over 192 millionHIV tests, and allowed over 13.8 million peopleaccess to lifesaving antiretroviral treatments.</P>
<P>By redirecting donations to the Global Fund’sCOVID-19 Response at the onset of thepandemic, Apple customers were able to helpfund programs that mitigated the impact ofCOVID-19 on existing HIV/AIDS programs andrural clinics were able to purchase motorbikesthat were used to transport samples tolaboratories in order to expedite test results forimmunocompromised people, such as thoseliving with HIV.</P>
<H2>Strengthening local communities</H2>
<P>We believe we can have an impact oncommunities by supporting grassrootsorganizations that work directly with localstakeholders. We focus our donations onprograms that are building strong communitiesand empowering creatives in the placeswhere we live and work. In fiscal year 2021,we provided 79 small grants across seven</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_127.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Part of the Global Fund’s broader investment in health system strengthening in Zambia includes getting COVIDand HIV tests and blood samples safely delivered to labs. Access to advanced testing equipment is limited soit’s critical to have efficient transport services in place so that samples can get consistently and swiftly deliveredin time for processing. Enos Mumfwa is pictured here with his motorbike about to deliver a cooler of samples.Credit: Adam Sjoberg/(RED)</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report66</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_128.jpg"/>
<ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_129.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<H1>Today at Apple Creative Studios D.C.</H1>
<P>This Apple retail program featured a partnership with Shout Mouse Press,a nonprofit writing and publishing program dedicated to elevating overlookedvoices. In partnership with Shout Mouse Press and Latin American Youth Center,Today at Apple Creative Studios D.C. supported a group of teens who authoreda collection of bilingual children’s books with themes of cultural celebration,grief, family, and friendship. The program equipped the authors with Appletechnology, including iPad Pro, Apple Pencil, and Magic Keyboard, so they couldcontinue to share their stories and explore new media for creative expression inillustration and audio.</P>
<P>For many of the students, who had neither imagined they’d write books norworked in these apps prior to the program, the sessions sparked inspiration forfuture endeavors and opened doors to new modes of storytelling. Through anApple grant, Shout Mouse Press was also able to further support the students’post-program journey with scholarship funding for authors applying for collegeand post-secondary programs. The books these students authored can beenjoyed and downloaded for free on Apple Books.</P>
<P>Joy Ugwu (pictured), a participant of Creative Studios</P>
<P>D.C., co-authored a book with fellow participant Tseganesh Chala.</P>
<P>countries. The grants provide support forarts and digital media education programsfor youth and young adults, education andworkforce development organizations, andBlack-, Hispanic/Latinx-, and Indigenous-ledorganizations that are grounded in advancingenvironmental justice and advocating forcommunities most impacted by climate changeand environmental disparities. Some examplesof grant recipients include:</P>
<P>•Outdoor Afro, which is working to preserveand protect our environment and connectwith Black communities and leaders inOakland, California, and around the country.</P>
<P>•The African American Youth HarvestFoundation (AAYHF) in Austin, Texas, whichprovides community-based resources forAfrican American and low-income youthand families.</P>
<P>•Nasc, which works to support migrants andrefugees in Ireland and offers a number ofdifferent resources, including the Gatewayprogram for women.</P>
<P>In partnership with nonprofits, Today at AppleCreative Studios encourages underrepresentedcreators to pursue their creative ambitionsacross music, design, and the visual arts. Inthe studio, they’ll collaborate with mentors andpeers, and learn from top-tier artists as theybuild their body of work. In fiscal year 2021,Today at Apple partnered with 23 nonprofitsin nine cities around the world, reaching morethan 4000 creators with our programming. Thissummer, Creative Studios will host programs in13 cities with over 28 nonprofit partners.</P>
<H1>Amplifying Apple values</H1>
<P>We’re always looking for ways to support effortsthat align with our Apple values. The followingare just a few examples of this support.</P>
<P>Malala Fund:In 2018, Apple became MalalaFund’s first Laureate partner, supporting theorganization’s work with local advocates andteachers in countries where girls face significanteducation challenges. The fund championsevery girl’s right to 12 years of safe, free, qualityeducation. Apple also assists with technology,curriculum, and research into policy changesrelated to girls’ education. Apple’s 2021 grantinvested in six Education Champion projects inBrazil, India, and Nigeria, impacting nearly eightmillion students.</P>
<P>Thurgood Marshall College Fund:Tocontinue building a diverse talent pipeline,Apple has a long-standing commitment withthe Thurgood Marshall College Fund (TMCF).In 2021, Apple and TMCF expanded thepartnership to include the Engineering andInnovation Scholars Program and the NewSilicon Initiative at HBCUs.</P>
<P>Apple Scholars Program:In partnershipwith a variety of organizations supportingunderrepresented communities, the AppleScholars Program provides scholarshipsupport, professional development andexperiential learning opportunities to studentsfrom underrepresented backgrounds interestedin research and development (R&amp;D). In 2022,Apple welcomed its first cohort of AppleScholars, representing over 30 colleges anduniversities across the country.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report67</P>
<P>Environment programs:We’re supporting effortsto restore areas within the Amazon forest thatare under threat from forest fires. The Alliance’sreforestation work also includes training andoutreach programs to empower local communitiesin protection and governance practices, whiledeveloping and strengthening livelihood modelsthat support economic development. We alsosupport the National Park Foundation in the U.S.,which has provided more than 1,000,000 studentswith meaningful national park experiences since2011, encouraging young people to connect withthe natural world. In addition, we’re backing theFoundation’s work to advance outdoor equity byeliminating barriers and promoting access. Andin the Chyulu Hills region of Kenya, we’resupporting community empowerment programsfor Maasai smallholder farmers, includingeducational scholarships for local students aswell as pastureland management training.</P>
<P>Crises and natural disasters:We alsomobilized funding for a number of unexpectedevents in fiscal year 2021 and early 2022,including flooding in Australia, China, Easternand Western Europe, and the U.S; tornados,hurricanes, and significant storms in the U.S.;support for COVID-19 in several countriesaround the world; the typhoon in the Philippines;wildfires in Canada and the Western U.S.; theearthquake in Haiti; and humanitarian supportin Afghanistan.</P>
<H1>Employee giving</H1>
<P>Our Employee Giving program providesopportunities for employees to contribute to thecauses they care deeply about with the supportof Apple. From volunteering to donations tosmaller individual actions, Apple is committedto giving, hand in hand with our team members.Our program promotes charitable giving toqualified organizations by matching donationsof time, money, eligible stock, or Apple products.</P>
<P>In 2021, Apple’s Employee Giving programcelebrated its 10th anniversary, having raisednearly $725 million for 39,000 organizationsworldwide — with over $120 million distributedto organizations around the globe in 2021alone.25The funds raised through Apple’sEmployee Giving program include the work of68,000 employee volunteers who have loggedalmost 2 million volunteer hours since 2011.</P>
<H2>Responding to the war in Ukraine</H2>
<P>We are deeply concerned about the ongoing war in Ukraine and have provided supportin several ways. We made corporate donations to humanitarian efforts helping people onthe ground, including to relief agencies and non-profits, such as World Central Kitchen,Doctors Without Borders, and the International Rescue Committee. We facilitatedcontributions to UNICEF — which is supporting children and families affected by thewar — through a tile on our website and services like Apple Music and the App Store.We also offered our employees opportunities to donate and volunteer, including holdinga 2-to-1 matching campaign to amplify employee donations to organizations providingshelter, food, and medicine to those affected by the war. Employees also took part in virtualactivities, including providing language support to refugees, recording video messagesand making cards for children, and supporting the Missing Maps Project, which helps mapvulnerable places, like Ukraine, so that NGOs and individuals can use the maps and data tobetter respond to crises. At the same time, we have worked to support our teams in Ukraineand across the region. In Ukraine, we contacted every employee, assisting them and theirfamilies in any way we could. We are also offering support to our Ukrainian team memberslocated outside of the country, as well as any employee who needs support.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_130.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Volunteers from retail participated in a gardening activity that included seeding, weeding, mulching, composting,planting, and harvesting to create micro farms and edible gardens</P>
<P>in Orlando, Florida, in honor of Earth Day 2022.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>AppendixGovernance</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report68</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_131.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>Volunteers from retail in the San Francisco Bay Area participated in a food sort and packaging event at theSan Francisco-Marin Food Bank. During the two hour shift, the team bagged a total of 700 bags of food,equaling 14,760 lbs.</P>
<P>Nearly</P>
<H1>$725M</H1>
<TOC><TOCI>raised for nonprofit organizationsthrough Employee Giving since 2011</TOCI>
</TOC>
<P>Almost</P>
<H1>2M</H1>
<P>employee volunteer hours since 2011.FY21: 256,000+ hours</P>
<H1>45,000+</H1>
<P>employee donors in FY21</P>
<H3>Giving time</H3>
<P>Apple makes a financial contribution for each hourvolunteered with a qualified organization. Someof the ways employees give their time includelending skills in person or online, mentoring youth,and participating in outdoor cleanups or otherlocal events with nonprofit organizations.</P>
<P>Apple employees can also participate in theGlobal Volunteer Program, an in-role leadershipexperience that empowers employees toorganize and lead volunteer activities for theircolleagues in their communities.</P>
<H3>Giving a donation</H3>
<P>When our employees donate money, Applematches their donations, on a dollar-for-dollarbasis up to $10,000 per year per employee.That way, every contribution goes further,every act inspires another, and every effort isamplified. Apple matches donations year-round, but in times of greater need, we haveoften increased the match to 2:1 and the matchcap up to $20,000 per employee.</P>
<H2>Job creation</H2>
<P>Apple supports millions of jobs in countriesaround the world, across North America, Europe,Asia, Central and South America, Australia, andAfrica. In the U.S., Apple is one of the biggestjob creators, and we continue to expandour commitment to fostering innovation andopportunity in the U.S. economy. We support2.8 million jobs across all 50 states through directemployment, spending with U.S. suppliers andmanufacturers, and the iOS app economy. InApril 2021, Apple announced an accelerationof its U.S. investments, with plans to make newcontributions of more than $430 billion and add20,000 new jobs across the country over the nextfive years. This includes a new North Carolinacampus, which will create at least 3000 new jobsin machine learning, artificial intelligence, softwareengineering, and other cutting-edge fields.</P>
<H3>Employees</H3>
<P>Apple has over 165,000 employees worldwidethat span an increasingly wide range of roles,including hardware and software engineering,science, construction, manufacturing, retail,customer support, marketing, and design.</P>
<H3>Suppliers and manufacturers</H3>
<P>Apple has a supply chain that spans the globe,with manufacturing and assembly taking placearound the world, including in the U.S., Europe,Asia, Central and South America, and Australia.From component manufacturers to logisticsproviders, Apple directly or indirectly supportshundreds of thousands of jobs, working withsuppliers and businesses in all 50 states inthe U.S. and every European country. Thesesuppliers provide equipment, parts, andmaterials for all of our core products.</P>
<H3>Jobs in the iOS app economy</H3>
<P>Since the App Store launched in 2008, theiOS app economy has become one of theworld’s fastest-growing sectors. The App Storeecosystem supports millions of jobs acrossthe world, empowering entrepreneurs fromArgentina and Alaska to Zimbabwe and beyond.</P>
<P>In the U.S., it supports more than 2.2 millionjobs, and in Europe, it supports another2.2 million jobs.</P>
<P>In January 2021, we launched the App StoreSmall Business Program, which benefits the vastmajority of developers who sell digital goods andservices on the App Store. The program cuts theApp Store commission in half — to 15 percent —for small businesses that earned up to $1 millionin proceeds during the previous year. Thereduced commission means small entrepreneursand app makers have more resources to createnew jobs, expand their businesses, explorecutting-edge technologies, and pioneer newinnovations that reach users around the world.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>AppendixGovernanceCommunitiesSuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironmentIntroduction</P>
<H1>Standardsthat raisethe bar.</H1>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report69</P>
<H2>Governance</H2>
<P>In this section</P>
<P>Corporate governanceEthics and complianceTax payments</P>
<P>70</P>
<P>71</P>
<P>72</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>Governance</P>
<P>Appendix</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report70</P>
<H1>Apple conducts business ethically, honestly, and in compliance with applicablelaws. We believe that how we conduct ourselves is as critical to Apple’s successas making the best products in the world. Our Business Conduct and GlobalCompliance policies are foundational to how we do business and how we putour values into practice every single day.</H1>
<H1>Corporate governance</H1>
<P>Our corporate governance structure is designedto foster principled actions, informed andeffective decision-making, and appropriatemonitoring of compliance and performance, sothat the long-term interests of shareholders arebeing served.</P>
<P>Environmental, social, and governance (ESG)matters are overseen and managed at multiplelevels within Apple.</P>
<H2>Board oversight of ESG</H2>
<P>Apple’s Board, assisted by its standingcommittees, has ultimate responsibility foroversight of significant risks affecting thecompany’s business, including environmental,social, and governance matters.</P>
<P>Apple’s Board and its committees exerciseoversight of our values and our people throughreview and discussion with management ofprogress relating to our values: accessibility,education, environment, inclusion and diversity,privacy, and supplier responsibility. Matters that</P>
<P>benefit from specialized attention are reservedto certain committees. For example, the Auditand Finance Committee oversees our GreenBond Impact reporting (seepage 14), while theCompensation Committee has incorporatedan ESG Modifier based on our values and otherkey community initiatives to our executivecompensation program (seepage 28). The fullBoard also directly oversees certain issues suchas Apple’s progress toward implementationof our Human Rights Policy (seepage 10)and our environmental goals and initiatives(seepage13).</P>
<H2>Management of ESG</H2>
<P>Work on environmental and social initiatives isembedded across different lines of business,with broad collaboration to drive forwardinitiatives that are important to Apple. Forexample, Apple’s Vice President of Environment,Policy and Social Initiatives is responsible forthe development, review, and execution ofplans designed to minimize Apple’s impact onthe environment, whereas Apple’s Senior VicePresident, Operations leads our efforts andprogress in the critical work of protecting peopleand the planet across our supply chain.</P>
<P>Across our different lines of business, Applehas developed internal systems and proceduresfor managing environmental, social, andgovernance topics, including engaging withexternal stakeholders (seepage 77) to learnabout their priorities and get their feedback, andto coordinate relevant projects and initiatives.</P>
<H2>Board oversight of risk management</H2>
<P>The Board believes that evaluating the executiveteam’s management of the risks confrontingApple is one of its most important areas ofoversight. In carrying out this responsibility, theBoard is assisted by each of its committees thatconsiders risks within its areas of responsibilityand apprises the full Board of significantmatters and management’s response.</P>
<P>Apple has an Enterprise Risk ManagementProgram that is designed to identify, assess,monitor, manage, and mitigate Apple’ssignificant business risks, including financial,operational, compliance, and reputational risks.In 2021, key areas of focus included health andsafety, environment, people, privacy and datasecurity, supply chain and operations, and legaland regulatory risks, including antitrust matters.</P>
<P>The Enterprise Risk Management Program issupported by a Risk Oversight Committee,composed of our Chief Financial Officer,General Counsel, Head of Business Assurance,and other senior business leaders, reportingto the Audit and Finance Committee, with itsgeneral responsibility for overseeing enterpriserisk management.</P>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_132.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>For more information on our corporategovernance framework and Board, see our2022 Proxy Statement.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>Governance</P>
<P>Appendix</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report71</P>
<H2>Ethics and compliance</H2>
<P>Apple is committed to conducting businessethically, honestly, and in full compliance withapplicable laws and regulations.</P>
<H3>BusinessConductandGlobalCompliance</H3>
<P>Apple’s Business Conduct Policy providesa guide to our ethical requirements for ouremployees. This policy includes the principlesthat guide our business practices — honesty,respect, confidentiality, and compliance. It isavailable to employees in over 20 languages.Apple expects its suppliers, contractors,consultants, and other business partners tofollow these principles when providing goodsand services to Apple or acting on our behalf.</P>
<P>Apple’s Business Conduct and GlobalCompliance team focuses on businessconduct, political compliance, export andsanctions compliance, health compliance,antitrust compliance, anti-corruptioncompliance, and third-party compliance.Additional compliance functions are integratedinto our business organizations.</P>
<P>The Business Conduct and Global Complianceteam conducts internal and independent third-party assessments of its programs to ensurethat they are effective and meet or exceed bestpractices. We make changes to our programs,policies, procedures, and training to reflectemerging trends and ensure that the respectivecompliance programs are aligned with Apple’sbusiness and risk profile.</P>
<P>Apple’s Chief Compliance Officer providesregular updates to the Board’s Audit andFinance Committee on the work done by theBusiness Conduct and Global Compliance teamand other compliance functions.</P>
<P>Third-party compliance program</P>
<P>Apple has a robust third-party complianceprogram that has been noted as mature and aleading practice by two external parties. Theprogram utilizes a risk calculator that includesfactors specific to Apple’s risk profile todetermine the level of diligence to conduct ona third party. We also utilize predictive analyticsand data visualization through our custominternal tool. This tool also provides a broadrange of insights about third parties, includingdue diligence findings, ongoing monitoring hits,audits, payment reviews, and remediation.</P>
<H3>Training and resources</H3>
<P>We take our values seriously, and our traininghelps guide our employees in making gooddecisions. All employees are required to takean annual scenario-based online BusinessConduct training that is updated each year.Training topics include workplace behaviors,conflicts of interest, gifts, confidentiality,competition, privacy, and Apple’s HumanRights Policy. Our internal Business Conductwebsite provides additional resources for ouremployees to learn more about the BusinessConduct Policy, including regularly updatedFAQs, featured topics, and toolkits formanagers. Our Business Conduct Helpline isavailable for employees to ask questions andreport concerns.</P>
<P>Additionally, all employees receive mandatoryannual or biannual training on Privacy,Respect at Apple, and Inclusion and Diversity.Employees receive between two and five hoursof training annually, depending on locationand the risks and responsibilities of their role.Additional required and recurring trainingincludes Anti-Corruption, Antitrust, Exportand Sanctions, and manager-specific training.Our Board also regularly receives training andupdates on ethics and compliance at Apple.</P>
<P>Managers get supplementary resources andtraining on topics such as disability awarenessand accommodations, discriminatory behavior,and their responsibilities to receive and reportall allegations of misconduct. Apple also trainseligible contractors on our expectations forethical behavior; topics include workplacebehaviors, secrecy, privacy, and important laws.</P>
<H3>Compliance policies</H3>
<P>Apple’s ethical business practices are set out inour Business Conduct Policy and additional keycompliance policies.</P>
<P>We make key compliance policies, includingthose applicable to our third parties, publiclyavailable on ourEthics and Compliancewebsite.</P>
<P>Anti-corruption</P>
<P>Apple does not tolerate any form of corruptionby Apple employees or by third parties whenworking with or on behalf of Apple. Apple’sAnti-Corruption Policy details how to complywith global anti-corruption laws. If employeesare unsure of the proper course of action, orwhether something constitutes corruption, weencourage them to contact Apple’s BusinessConduct team.</P>
<H1>98%</H1>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_133.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<TOC><TOCI>employees completing businessconduct training in calendar year 2021</TOCI>
</TOC>
<H1>902,000</H1>
<P>Apple training courses completed in 2021</P>
<H1>432,000</H1>
<TOC><TOCI>hours spent on Apple-recommendedand required trainings in 2021</TOCI>
</TOC>
<Figure><ImageData src="images\4_apple_1_72_img_134.jpg"/>
</Figure>
<P>For more information, seeApple’s Ethics andCompliance website.</P>
</Part>
<Part><P>Introduction</P>
<P>SuppliersCustomersOurPeopleEnvironment</P>
<P>Communities</P>
<P>Governance</P>
<P>Appendix</P>
<P>Apple’s 2022 ESG Report72</P>
<P>Export and sanctions</P>
<P>Apple is committed to compliance withapplicable export and sanctions laws, andthe requirements that apply to Apple andits employees are clearly set out in Apple’sExport and Sanctions policies. We also provideinternal resources for employees to help themunderstand applicable laws and how to reportpossible violations.</P>
<P>Antitrust and competition</P>
<P>Apple is committed to conducting business incompliance with competition laws around theworld. Misconduct and violations of Apple’sAntitrust and Competition Law Policy and thelaw must promptly be reported to our AntitrustCompliance Officer or to the Business Conductteam. Apple’s Antitrust Compliance Officer,together with Apple’s General Counsel andApple’s Chief Compliance Officer, regularlyreports to the Audit and Finance Committeeof the Board on matters including the AntitrustCompliance Program’s alignment with potentialantitrust risks, as well as the effectivenessof the program’s design in detecting andpreventing antitrust issues and promotingcompliance with laws and Apple’s policies.</P>
<P>Public policy advocacy</P>
<P>Apple engages in policy discussions wherethey matter to our business and customers.Our Public Policy Advocacy website definesour position on corporate political contributionsand describes how Apple participates in publicdebate in the United States through direct andindirect advocacy.</P>
<P>Apple does not make political contributionsto individual candidates or parties, and wedo not have a political action committee. Anypolitical contributions made by Apple are madein the interests of the company and withoutregard for the private political preferences ofindividual executives or employees. Politicalcontributions are promptly reported publicly onApple’s website.</P>
<H2>Reporting concerns</H2>
<P>Our employees are required to speak upabout any violation of Apple’s BusinessConduct Policy, other Apple policies, or legalor regulatory requirements, and we makeit easy for employees and third parties toreport concerns.</P>
<P>Our employees can contact Apple’s BusinessConduct team by phone, email, or web</P>
<P>form. Apple’s third-party reporting service,EthicsPoint, is also available to employeesand external parties to report concerns tothe Business Conduct team, and providesthe option of anonymous reporting, wherepermissible under local law. The externalreporting service is available 24/7, and providesa multilingual reporting option with local, toll-free numbers.</P>
<P>Business Conduct partners with appropriateteams at Apple to investigate concernsand determine appropriate resolutions,including corrective action up to and includingtermination where necessary. Apple will notretaliate — and will not tolerate retaliation —against any individual for reporting a good-faithconcern or complaint, or for participating in theinvestigation of any complaint.</P>
<H1>Tax payments</H1>
<P>Taxes play a necessary and important rolein our society and Apple believes everycorporation has a responsibility to pay all thetaxes they owe. As one of the largest taxpayersin the world, we comply with the law whereverwe operate and pay taxes on everything weearn around the world. Over the past decade,Apple has paid more than $120 billion incorporate income taxes — and our annualeffective tax rate was 22 percent on average.26</P>
<P>The Audit and Finance Committee of the Boardof Directors regularly reviews and discussesApple’s reports on tax matters from Apple’sChief Financial Officer, General Counsel, theheads of global Tax, Business Assurance,and Internal Audit, and Apple’s independentauditor. These reports include, among othermatters, updates on significant domesticand international tax-related developments,worldwide tax audits, international tax structure,international tax policy, and other tax-relatedlegislative matters.</P>
</Part>
</TaggedPDF-doc>
